<reports>
<report>
<year>1964</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[64/c/21.1
SOIL STRUCTURE 4

The effects of Krilium and peat - Woburn Steckyard Field, plot 6
of Continuous Barley site, red beet 1964,

Design: 3 randomised blocks of 4 plots each.

Area of each plot: 0.0006. Area harvested: 0,0005.

Treatments. All combinations of:-

1. Krilium: None (0), Krilium CRD 189 at 10 cwt active ingredient (Kr).
2. Peat: None (0), 90 cwt peat dry matter (Pt). The Krilium and
peat were applied to the seedbed and worked into the top 2 inches,

Basal dressing: Monoammonium phosphate, potassium nitrate, ammonium
nitrate and magnesium sulphate to supply 200 1b N, 75 1b P,

250 1b K, 50 1b Mg. All fertilisers were dug in except one fifth
N which was applied to the seedbed and worked in.

Cultivations, etc.: Ground chelk applied at 2 tons, plots rotavated,
fertilisers applied, plots dug: Apr 13, 1964, Krilium and peat
applied, all plots worked with drags: Apr 23. Ground chalk applied
at 1 ton and one fifth N applied, seed drilled at 30 1b: May 1.
Sprayed with DDT at 0.6 1b in 20 gals: May 20. Singled: June 15.
Sprayed 3 times with a mixture of menazon, DDT and gemma BHC at
1.5 fluid oz in 40 gals: June 25, July 14 and 21. Lifted: Aug 5.
Variety: Detroit Globe.

NOTE: Crop samples were taken for estimation of dry matter and
chemical analysis,

Standard errors per plot.

Roots: 0.711 or 5.1% (6 d.f.)
Tops: 0.465 or 6.5% (6 d.f.)
Roots and Tops: 1.160 or 5.5% (6 d.f.)
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1965</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[65/c/20.1
SOIL STRUCTURE &
Effects of Krilium and peat, Woburn Stackyard Field, plot § of

Continuous Barley site, red beet 1964, lettuce followed by red

beet 1965.

Design: 3 randomised blocks of 4 plots each.
Area of each plot: 0,0006, Aree Imrvested: 0,0005.
Treatments. All combinations of:-

1. Xrilium: None (0), Krilium CRD 189 at 10 cwt active

ingredient (Kr).

2, Peat: None (0), 90 cwt peat dry matter (Pt).

The treatments were applied to the same plots as in 196k, After
hand digging the 1954 applications were buried and the 1965
treatments were applied toc the seedbed and worked into the top
2 inches.

Basel dressings: Moncemmonium phosphate, potassium nitrate, ammonium
nitrate and megnesium sulphate to supply

1. Iettuce: 100 1b KN, 75 1b P, 200 1b K, 50 1b Mg 3/4 dug in 1/k to
seedbed.

2. Red beet: 200 1b KR, 75 1b P, 200 1b K, 50 1b Mg all to seedbed
except 1f the N applied &s top dressing.

Cultivations, etc.:

Lettuce. Fertilisers for digging in applied: Mar 10, 1965. All plots
mand dug: Apr 1, Peat and Krilium applied and worked into the
seedbed: Apr 22, Pertilisers to seedbed applied and seedbed
Frerared: My 5. Lettuce seed drilled at 3 1b: May 6,

Singled first to 4 inch spacing: May 21, then to 8 inch spacing:
June 14, Sprayed with & mixture of menazon, IDT and game BHC
at 1,5 pints in LO gals and cottoned against birds: May 21,
Harvested: July 8. Variety: Borough Wonder.

Red beet. Seedbed fertilisers applied, prepared seedbed and seed
drilled at 30 1b: July 9, 1965. Top dressing N applied: July 20.
Singled, first to 2 inch spacing: July 28, then to 4 inch
smcing: Aug 13. Sprayed with 2 mixture of menszon, DIT and gamme
BHC at 1.5 pints in 40 gals: Aug 2. Lifted: Oct 19. Variety:
Detroit Globe.

NOE: Crop samples of both lettuce and red beet taken for determination
of dry matter and samples retained for chemical analysis.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
</reports>