<reports>
<report>
<year>1962</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[62/0/8.1
LONG TERM LIMING 2XPERDIMENT - SPRING BEANS 1962

The effect of lime on the yield and composition of crops and on the
status of P and K in soils - Rothamsted (R) Sawyers I and Woburn (j)
Stackyard Series C 1962, the first year.

Design (each field): 2 blocks of 46 plots each, colunms of & plots

' being split for uninoculeted v. inoculated seed,

Area of each sub plot: 0.0145 acres. Area harvested: 0.0093 acres.

Treatments. All combinations of:-

Ground chalk: None; 2; 4; 6 tons CaCO, per acre applied in
March 1962,

PB: None; 0.5 cwt P, 05 per acre as superphosphate.

Ks None; 1.0 cwt x50 per acre as muriate of potash.

Incculation of seed: None; Inoculated with Rhizobium leguminosarum

The maximum pH range between plots was 4.8 - 5.6 on Sawyers I (R)
and 5.6 - 6.3 on Stackyard Series C (W).

Basal dressing: None.
Cultivations, etc.:-

Sawyers I (x): Ploughed: Nov 17, 1961. Ground chalk applied:

Mar 5, 1962, Rotary cultivated: Mar 14. Superphosphate and
muriete of potash applied: Mar 15. Seed drilled at 200 lb per
acre: Mar 16. Sprayed with simazine at 1 1b in 40 gallons per
acre: Apr 11. Sprayed with demeton methyl at 6 fluid oz in
60 gellons per acre: July 6. Combine harvested: Sept 20.
Variety: Tick 30B. Previous crops: Potatoes and fellow 1960,
potatoes and fallow 1961.

Stackyard Series C (W): Ploughed: Nov 24, 1961. Ground chalk
epplied: Mar 9, 1962. Superphosphate and muriate of potash
applied: Mar 15. Seed drilled at 200 1b per acre: Mar 19,
Sprayed with simazine at 1 1b in 40 gallons per acre: Apr 12.
Sprayed with demeton methyl at 6 fluid oz in 60 gellons per
acre: July 12. Combine harvested: Sept 20. Variety: Tick 30B.

' Previous crops: Barley 1960, suger beet 1961.
Note: Samples were taken for counts of pods and beans.
Standard errors per plot. Grain (at AS dry matter):
Sawyers I (R) Whole plot 4.26 cwt per acre or 25.4% (15 def.)
Sub plot! 1.42 cwt per acre or 8.4% (16 a.f.)
Stackyard Series C (W) Whole plot: 2.44 cwt per acre or 13.1% {2 ae}
Sub plots 2.79 cwt per core or 14.9% (16 dof.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1963</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[63/C/3.1
LONG TERM LIMING EXPERIMENT - SPRING BEANS 1963
(LL and WLL)

Effect of lime ~m the yield and composition of crops and on the status
of P and K in soils - Rothamsted (R) Sawyers I and Woburn (W)
Stackyard Series C 1963, the second year.

Design (each field): 2 randomised blocks of 16 plots each.

Area of each plot (acres): 0.0289, Area hmrvested: 0.0121.

Treatments. All combinations of:-

Ground chalk (tons ier acre): Sewyers I (R): None, 2, 4 applied in
> > 8 (6 in March 19@, 2 in winter 19 - 63
in divided dressings) (C). Stackyard Series C (Ww): None, 2 applied
in Spring 1962 (0 and A), 4.75 (4% in spring, 0.75 in October 196) (B),
7.5 (6 in spring, 1.5 in October 19€2) (Cc).
P: None, 0.5 cwt P205 per acre as superphosphate (cumulative).
RK: None, 1.0 ewt X60 per acre e8 muriate of potash (cumulative).
The pH ranges between plots after hervest 19 were as follows:-
Pield Chalk per acre (Spring 19) H range
Sawyers I (R) None Eee - 5.2
2 tons 6.0 - 6.4
4 tons 6.8 - 7.2
6 tons 7.1 - 74
Stackyard Series C (wW) Fone 5.7 - 6.2
2 tons 6.7 = 7.
& toms Tel - 7.4
6 tons 7.2 - 7.4

Cultivetions, etc.

Sawyers I (R): Growd chalk applied at 1 ton per acre to 'C’ plots:
Dec 4, 196.  Ploughed: Mar 27, 1963. Ground chalk applied at
1 ton per acre to 'C’ plots: Aprl. Superphosphate and mriate of
potash applied: Apr 3. Seed drilled at 200 lb per acre: Ae 8,
Sprayed with simzine at 1 1b in © gallons per acre: Apr 18.
Spreyed with demeton-methyl at 6 fluid oz in 40 gions per acre:
June 14. Combine harvested: Oct 18.  Veriety: Tick SB.
Previous crops: Potatoes and fallow 1960, potatoes and fallow 1961.

Stackyard Series C (W): Ploughed: Oct 12, 19%. Ground chalk
applied at 0.75 tons per acre to 'B' plote and et 1.5 tons per
acre to 'C’ plots: Oct 19, Superphosphate and muriate of potash
applied: Mr 13, 1963. Seed drilled at 200 lb per acre: Mar 27.
Sprayed with simzine at 1 1b in © glions per acre: Apr 8.
Sprayed with demeton-methyl at 6 fluid oz in 4 gallons per acre:
June 13. Combine harvested: Sept 21. Variety: Tick 305.
Previous crops: Barley 1960, suger beet 194.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1964</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[64/C/3.1
LONG TERM LIMING EXPERIMENT - SPRING BEANS 1964
(LL and WLL)

For treatments etc., see 'Results' 63/C/3 and for previous years’
results see 62/C/8 and 63/C/3.

Area of each sub plot: 0.0145. Area harvested: Sawyers I (R) -
0.0133, Stackyard Series C (W) - 0.0096.

Plots receiving both P and K were subdivided for a comparison between
broadcasting of powder fertiliser (B) (rates and mterials as
before) and placement drilling of 409 1b 0:14:28(D).

Basal dressing: 0.25 cwt N as 'Nitro-Chalk' broadcast.

Cultivations, etc.

Sawyers I (R): Ploughed: Nov 14, 1963. Fertilisers applied:
Feb 15, 1964. Seed drilled at 200 lb: Mar 6. Sprayed with
simazine at 1 1b in 40 gals: Mar 13. Combine harvested:
Aug 25. Variety: Spring Tick.

Stackyard Series C (W): Ploughed: Nov 1, 1963. Fertilisers
applied and seed drilled* at 200 lb: Nov 8 Sprayed with
simazine at 1 lb in 40 gals: Nov 9. Seed drilled* at 200 lb:
Mar 13, 1964. Sprayed with simazine at 1 lb in 40 gals:
Apr 6, Combine harvested: Aug 25. Variety: Spring Tick.

* The winter beans failed through bird damage and the spring beans
were sown without seedbed cultivation.

NOTE: On Sawyers I (R) samples were taken at harvest for pod and
bean counts.

Standard error per plot. Grain:

Main experiment
Sawyers I (R): 3-56 or 20.2% (15 af.)

Stackyard Series C (W): 1.62 or 10.5% (15 4.f.)

PK plots

Sawyers I (R): Whole plot: 2.46 or 12.4% (3 d.f.)
Sub plot: 0.96 or 4.6% (4 a.f.)
Stackyard Series C (W): Whole plot: 1.30 or 6.6% (3 af.)
Sub plot: 2.23 or 11.4% (4 a.f.)
Ground chalk tons per acre.

CAO = None

CA2 = 2

CAR = &

ca8 = 8
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1965</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[65/C/3.1
LONG TERM LIMING EXPERIMENT - BARLEY 1965
(LL and WLL)

Rothamsted Sawyers I and Woburn Stackyard Series C - the fourth year.

For treatments etc., see 'Results' 63/C/3 and for previous years’
results see 62/C/8, 63/C/3 and 64/C/3.

Area of each plot: 0.0289, Area harvested: 0.0129,

The comparison of broadcasting of powder fertiliser and placement
drilling of compound (0: 14: 28) is discontinued.

Basal applications: 0.5 cwt Nas 'Nitro-Chalk' combine drilled.
Mecoprop/2,4-D (Methoxone Extra at 6 pints in 34 @ls a
Sawyers I (R) and at 6 pints in 40 gals m Stackyard Series C (W)).

Cultivations, etc.:

Sawyers I (R): Ploughed: Sept 18, 1964. Fertilisers applied:
Mar 1, 1965. Seed drilled at 156 lb: Mar 17. Sprayed:
May 19. Combine harvested: Sept 5. Variety: Maris Badger.

Stackyard Series C (W): Rotary cultivated: Oct 14 and 27, 196.
Fertilisers applied, seed drilled at 140 lb: Mar 29, 1965.
Sprayed: My 11. Combined tarvested: Aug 28. Variety:
Maris Badger.

Standard errors per plot. Grein:
Sawyers I (R): 8.68 or 23.0% (15 a.f.)
Stackyard Series C (W): 0.96 or 2.4% (15 a.f.)
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1966</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[66/C/3.1
LONG TERM LIMING EXPERIMENTS - BARLEY 1966
(LL and WLL)
Rothamsted Sawyers I and Woburn Stackyard Series C - the fifth year.
For treatments etc., see 'Results' 63/C/3 and for previous years’
results see 62/C/8, 63/C/3, 64/C/3 and 65/C/3.

Area of each plot: 0.0289, Area harvested: 0.0129,
Basal applications:

Sawyers I (R) = 0.5 cwt N as 'Nitro-Chalk' combine drilled.
Weedkiller: Ioxynil/mecoprop (Actril C at k pints in 40 gals).

Stackyard Series C (W) - 0.5 cwt N as sulphate of ammonia
broadcast by machine, 0.5 cwt N as 'Nitro-Chalk’ broadcast by
machine. Weedkillert Ioxynil/mecoprop (Actril C at 4 pints
in 35 gals).

Cultivations, etc.t-

Sawyers I (R): Ploughed: Jan 10, 1966. P and K applied, seed
drilled at 160 lot Mer 14, Sprayed: May 20, Combine hervested:
Aug 26. Variety: Maris Badger.

Stackyard Series C (W): Ploughed: Sept 16, 1965. P and K applied:
Mar 10, 1965. Sulphate of ammonia applied, seed drilled at
1kO lb: Mar 11, Sprayed: May LL. =‘''Nitro-Chalk' applied by
machine: June 7. Combine harvested: Sept 8. Variety: Maris
Badger.

Standard errors per plot. Grain:

Sawyers I (R): 6.54 or 19.7% (15 4.f.)

Stackyerd C (W): 1.26 or 3.2% (15 a.f.)
NOTE: Ground chalk tons per acre applied 1962 - 63

Sawyers I (R) Stackyard Series C (W)*
CAO = ° 0
CA2 2 2
cay = 4 4.75
cas 2 8 7.5
* These were given incorrectly for Woburn in Results 6:/C/3.1.
The following is a summary of the actual applications.
Sawyers I (R) Stackyard Series C (Ww)

1962 o 2h 6 o 2 4 6
1963 0 0 0 2 0 O 0.75 1.5
ee ——————EE
Total oe2k 8 oO 2 4&7 7.5
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1967</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[67/c/3.1
LONG TERM LIMING EXPERIMENT - BARLEY
(LL and WLL)
Rothamsted Sawyers I and Woburn Stackyard Series C - the sixth year.
For treatments etc., see ‘Results’ 63/C/3 and for previous years’
results see 62/¢/8, 63/¢/3, 63/c/3, 65/C/3 and 66/C/3.
Area of each plot: 0.0289, Area harvested: 0.0128,
Basal applications:

Sawyers I (R): 0.75 cwt Nas 'Nitro-Chalk' combine drilled,
Weedkiller: Mecoprop/2,4-D (Methoxone Extra at 6 pints
in 30 gals).

Stackyard Series C (W): 0,62 cwt N as sulphate of ammonia
broadcast in the seedbed, 0.38 cwt applied by hand as top-
dressing, Weedkillers: Aminotriazole at 4 lb and ammonium
thiocyanate at 3.7 1b in 33 gals. Ioxynil/mecoprop
(Actril C at 5 pints in 35 gals) on 2 occasions, (The
second application was made because the first had little
effect).

Cultivations, etc, t-

Sawyers I (R): Ploughed: Sept 16, 1966. P and K applied:

Feb 22, 1967. Seed drilled at 140 lb: Mar 3. Weedkiller
applied: May 12, Combine harvested: Aug 22, Variety:
Maris Badger,

Stackyard Series C (W): Aminotriazole and ammonium thiocyanate
applied: ont 27, 1966. Ploughed: Oct 28, P and K applied:
Fed 2h, 1967. Sulphate of ammonia applied, seed drilled at
140 lb: Mar 4, Remainder of sulphate of ammonia applied:
Mar 21, TIoxynil/mecoprop applied: May 9 and 31, Combine
harvested: Aug 21, Variety: Maris Badger.

Standard errors per plots. Grain:
Savyers I (R): 7.16 or 26.0% (15 4.f.)
Stackyard Series C (W): 3.04 or 9.2% (15 4.f.)
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1968</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[68/C/3.1
LONG TERM LIMING EXPERIMENT
POTATOES 1968
(LL and WLL)
Rothamsted Sewyers I (R) and Woburn Stackyard Series C (W) - the
seventh year,
For treatments etc, see ‘Results' 63/C/3 and ey? or Seer years'
results see 62/C/8, 63/C/3, 64/C/3, 65/C/3, 66/c/3 and 67/C/3.
Design: 2 randomised blocks of 16 plots.
Area of each plot: 0,0284, Area harvested: Sawyers I (R): 0.0095.
Stackyard C (W): 0.0126,
Treatments: All combinations of:-
1. Ground chalk (tons) applied 196 - 1963,
: Sawyers I (R) Stackyard Series c (w)
CAO 0 0
CA2 2 2
CA4 4 4.75 :
cas 8 75
2. P: None (PO), 1.0 (PL) cwt P205 as superphosphate,
3. Kz None (KO), 1,5 (KL) cwt K20 as muriate of potash,
Basal applications:
Sawyers I (R): 1.5 cwt N a@s 'Nitro-Chalk' broadcast before
planting, Weedkiller: Paraquat at 0.38 lb ion and linuron
at 0.75 lb in 36 gals. Fungicide: Mancozeb at 1.2 1d in é
37 gals on 3 occasions, Insecticide: Demeton-s-methyl at .
3.5 02 applied with the second spraying of mancozeb, :
Stackyard Series C (W): 2.0 cwt Nas 'Nitro-Chalk' broadcast
before planting, Weedkiller: Paraquat at 0,38 1b ion and
linuron at 0.5 1b in. 50 gals. Fungicide: Mancozeb at 1.2 lb
in 38 gals on 3 occasions, Insecticide; Demeton-s-methyl at’.
3.5 0% applied with the first spraying of mancozeb,.
68/C/3.2
Cultivations, etc,:-

Sawyers I (R): Ploughed: 25 Sept, 1967, 'Nitro-Chalk' applied:
28 Mar, 1968, P and K applied, plots rotary cultivated,
potatoes machine planted: 4 Apr, Weedkiller applied: 3 May.
Fungicide applied: 4 July, 19 July, 5 Aug. Insecticide applied:
19 July. Sprayed with undiluted BOV at 15 gals: 30 aug.
Lifted: 3 Oct. Variety: Majestic, :

Stackyard Series C (W): Ploughed: 15 Nov, 1967, 'Nitro-Chalk'
applied: 26 Mar, 1968. P and K epplied, plots rotary
cultivated: 28 Mar, Potatoes machine planted: 29 Mar,
Weedkiller applied: 3 May. Rotary ridged: 13 June. Fungicide
applied: 12 July, 18 July, 30 July. Insecticide applied:

12 July. Sprayed with undiluted BOV at 15 gals: 4 Sept.
Lifted: 2 Oct. Variety: Majestic.
Stendard errors per plot. Tubers:
Sawyers I (R): 1.981 or 19.7% ((15 4.f.)
Stackyard C (W): 1.021 or 10.2% (15 a.f.)
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1969</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[137
LONG TERM LIMING EXPERDENT
FALLOW 1969
(69/R/CS/10 end 69/W/cs/10)

Rothamsted Sawyers I (R) and Woburn Stackyard Series C (W) - the
eighth year.

For treatments etc, see ‘Results’ one and for previous years’
results see 62/C/8, 63/C/3, 64/C/3, 65/c/3, 66/C/3, 67/C/3 end
68/c/3.

Cultivations, etc. t-

Sawyers I (R): Ploughed: 31 Jan, 1969, Rotery cultivated:
16 - 26 Apr, 23 Mey, 3 July. Subsoiled 28 inches apart
20 inches deep: 5 Aug. Deep-tine cultivated: 8 Aug.

Stackyard Series C (W): Deep-tine cultivated: 18 Oct, 1968.
Ploughed: 7 Feb, 1969, 8 Mar. Rotary cultivated:
17 Apr, 1 Mey, 22 May, 17 June, Deep-tine cultivated:
28 Jume. Subsoiled 56 inches apart 20-22 inches deep:
1 July.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1970</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[LONG TERM LIMING
(70/R/CS/10 and 70/w/cS/10)

Rothamsted Sawyers I (R) and Woburn Stackyard Series C (W) -

the ninth year, barley.
For treatments and previous years’ results see ‘Details’ 1967

and 'Results' 67/C/3, 68/C/3 and 69/R&W/CS/10.
Design: 2 rendomised blocks of 16 plots,
Area of each plot: 0.0289, Area harvested: Sawyers I (R): 0,0127,

Stackyard Series C (W): 0,0128,

Treatments: All combinations of?-
1. Ground chalk (tons) applied 19 - 3
Sawyers I (R) Stackyerd Series C (Ww)
CAO 0 0
CA2 2 2
CAu 4 4.75
CAs 8 7.5
2. P: None (PO), 0.5 (Pl) cwt P205 as superphosphate,
3. K: None (KO), 1.0 (K1) cwt K20 as muriate of potash,
Basal epplications:

Sawyers I (R): 0.75 cwt Nas 'Nitro-Chalk' combine drilled.
Weedkiller: 2,4-D at 0.5 lb and dichlorprop at 2 lb in
20 gals.

Stackyarmd Series C (W): 1.0 cwt Nas 'Nitro-Chelk' broadcast
before planting. Weedkiller: Ioxynil at 7.5 oz and mecoprop
at 22,5 oz in 25 gels.

Cultivations, etc.$

Sawyers I (R): Ploughed: 30 Dec, 1969. P and K applied:

26 Mar, 1970, Seed combine drilled at 140 lb: 28 Mar,
Weedkiller applied: 18 May. Combine harvested: 15 Aug.
Variety: Julia,

Stackyard Series C (W): Ploughed: 30 Oct - 8 Nov, 1969. WN
applied: 25 Mar, 1970. Seed drilled at 135 lv, P and K
applied: 26 Mar, Weedkiller applied: 18 May. Combine
harvested: 12 Aug. Variety: Julia.

NOTE: On Sawyers I (R) the yields on the CAO plots were very small
and have been omitted from the analysis.
135
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1971</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[T1/R/CS/10 and Ti/w/cs/10
LONG TERM LIMING

Ooject: To study the effects of different amouts of lime on the yields

of @ range of crops, The effects of P end K are also studied -

Rothamsted (R) Sawyers I and Woburn (W) Steckyard C.

The tenth year, barley.

Design: 2 blocks of 16 plots.

For previous years see 'Details' 1967, 68/C/3(t), 69/R&w/cS/10

and 70/R&¥/CS/10(t).

Whole plot dimensions: 6.40 x 18.3. Area harvested: Sawyers I (R):

0.00516, Stackyard C (W): 0.00520.

Basal applications:-

Sawyers I (R): 94 kg N as ‘Nitro-Chalk' combine drilled, Weedkillers:
Parequat at 0.84 kg ion in 225 1, Ioxynil octanoete, bromoxynil
octanoate and the iso-octyl ester of dichlorprop ("Oxytril P’ et
1.41 in a 1).

Stackyard C (W): 126 kg N as ‘Nitro-Chalk' broadcast before planting.
Weedkillers: Paraquat at 0.56 kg ion in 261 1*, Ioxynil at
0.525 kg and mecoprop at 1,58 kg in 2&1 1.

* Treatment CAO PO Kl received 1.12 kg ion in 281 1.

Cultivations, etc,%-

Sewyers I (R): Paraquat applied: 22 Sept, 1970. Ploughed: 28 Oct.
P and K applied: 3 Mar, 1971. Seed combine drilled at 157 kg:
10 Mar, ‘Oxytril P’ epplied: 4 Mey. Combine harvested: 16 Aug.
Variety: Julia.

Stackyard C (W): Paraquat applied: 16 Sept, 1970. Ploughed: 28 Oct.
N, P and K applied: 4 Mar, 1971. Seed drilled at 157 kg: 17 Mar.
Weedkiller applied: 17 May. Combine hervested: 17 Aug.

Variety: Julia.

NOTE: Om both fields no yields were taken from some of the CAD plots
and those recorded for the remainder were very small, The
yields from the CAD plots were omitted from the analysis.

Standard errors per plot. Grain, tonnes/hectare:

Savyers I (R): 0.773 or 18.7% (12 4.f£.)

Stackyard C (Ww): 0.270 or 6.5% (11 4,f.)

132
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1972</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[Je/R/CS/10 and Te/v/cs/10
LONG TERM LIMING
Qoject: To study the effects of different amounts of lime on the
yields of a range of crops. The effects of P and K are also

studied - Rothamsted (R) Sawyers I and Woburn (W) Stackyard C,

Sponsors: J, Bolton, D.B, Slope.

The eleventh year - barley. - oe ”

For previous years cee 'Deteils’ 1967, 68/¢/3(t) and 69-71/RW/CS/10,

Whole plot dimensions: 6,40 x 18,3. Area harvested: Sawyers I (R)t
0.00512. Stackyard C (W): 0.00516,

Basal applicetions:

Sawyers I (R): 90 kg Nas 'Nitro-Chalk’ combine drilled,
Weedkillers: Paraquat at 0,56 kg ion in 2201. Ioxynil,
bromoxynil, 2,4-DP and MCPA ('Tetroxone’ at 5.6 1 in 220 1).

Stackyard.C (W): 130 kg N as 'Nitro-Chalk’ broadcast before
sowing, Weedkiller: Paraquat at 0.56 kg fon in 280 2,

Seed: Sawyers I (R): Julia (dressed with ethirimol) sown at 160 kg.
Stackyard C (¥): Julia (dressed with ethirimol) sow at 150 kg,
Cultivations, etc. t-

Sewyers I (R): Paraquat applied: 9 Sept, 1971. Ploughed:

ll Nov, P and K applied, seed combine drilled: 20 Mer, 1972.
'Tetroxone’ applied? 17 May. CAD plots cut and carted, because
the crop had failed and plots were very weedy. CAD plots
rotary cultivated twice: 3. July, Ll July. Combine harvested:
2% Aug. : :

Stackyard C (W): Paraquat applied: 9 Sept, 1971. Ploughed:
27 Oct. N, P and K applied: 14 Mar, 1972. Seed drilled:
15 Mar. CAO plots cut and carted, because the crop had
failed and plots were very weedy: 3 July. CAO plots rotary
cultivated three times: 4 July, 18 July, 31 July. Combine
harvested: 15 Aug.

Standard errors per plot. Grain, tonnes/nectere:
Savyers 1 (R): 1.130 or 25.0% (0 af.)
Stackyard C (W): 0,371 or 7.0% (11 4.f.} pu
137
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1973</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[. 73/R/CS/10 and 73/W/Cs/10
LONG TERM LIMING
Object: To study the effects of different amounts of lime on the yields
of a range of crops. The effects of P and K are also studied -
Rothamsted (R) Sawyers I and Woburn (W) Stackyard C.
Sponsors: J, Bolton, D.B. Slope.
The twelfth year, barley.
For previous years see ‘Details’ 1967, 68/c/3(t), 69/Rew/CS/10
70/Rew/c8/10(t) and 7L-72/Ral/CS/10, :
Design: 2 rendomised blocks of 16 plots.
Whole plot dimensions: 6,40 x 18.3. Area harvested: Sawyers I (R): 0.00512.
Stackyard C (W): 0.00518,
Treatments: All combinations of:-
1. Ground chalk (tonnes CaC03) (total applied 1962-63): LIE
: Rothamsted (R) Woburn (W) R WwW
None None 0 oO
5 5 5 5
10 LR 10 Ww
20 1g 20 19
2. Phosphate, applied annually as superphosphate (kg P205): Pe05
None 0
63 63
3. Potassium, applied annually as muriate of potash (kg Kan): Ka
None °
126 126
Basal applications:
Sawyers I (R): Manures: 90 kg N as 'Nitro-Chalk' combine drilled,
aatt MCPA, mecoprop and dicamba ("Banlene Plus’ at 5.6 1
in 2201).
Stackyard C (W): Manures: 130 kg N as ‘Nitro-Chalk' broadcast before
sowing, Weedkiller: Ioxynil at 0.53 kg plus mecoprop at 1.6 kg
in 280 1,
146
73/R/CS/10 and 73/W/cs/10
Seed: Gawyers I (R): Julia, dressed with ethirimol, sow at 160 kg.
Steckyeré C (W): Julia, dressed with ethirimol, sown et 160 ke.
Cultivetions, etc.:-

Sawyers I (R): Ploughed: 29 Nov, 1972, P and K applied: 26 Feb, 1973.
Power harrowed, seed sown: 12 Mar. Weedkiller applied: 15 May.
Plots without lime rotary cultivated: 2 Jwly. Combine harvested:
10 Aug.

Stackyard C (W): Deep-tine cultivated: 28 Sept, 1972. Ploughed:
27 Dec, P and K applied: 28 Feb, 1973. W applied: & Mar.

Seed sown: 12 Mar, Weedkiller applied: 11 May. Certain plots
without lime rotary cultivated: 2 July. Combine harvested:
13 Aug.
NOTE: Plots which had received no lime grew little crop and became
very weedy, At Rothamsted all these plots were cut green in
July, no yields, and rotary cultivated. At Wobum yields were
taken from combinations of no lime with P and K together (both
blocks) and with P alone (one block only), the remaining plots
with no lime were cut green in July and rotary cultivated,
Standard errors per plot. Grain, tonnes/hectare:
Sawyers I (R): 0.910 or 23.0% oe a.f,)
Stackyard C (Ww): 0.476 or 11.4% (11 a.f.)
147
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1974</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[74/R/CS/10 and 7Th/W/cs/10
LONG TERM LIMING
Object: To study the effects of different amounts of lime on the yields
of a range of crops. The effects of P K, and Mg are also studied -
Rothamsted (R) Sawyers I and Woburn (W) Stackyard C.
Sponsor: J. Bolton,
The 13th year, potatoes.
For previous years see 'Details' 1967, 68/c/3(t), 69/RxH/CS/10,
7o/R&W/CS/10(t) and 7L-73/R&W/CS/10.
Design: 2 randomised blocks of 16 plots.
Whole plot dimensions: 6.40 x 18.3. Sub plot area harvested: 0.00117.
Treatments: All combinations oft-
Whole plots: 1. Ground chalk (tonnes CaCO3) (total applied 1962-63): LIME
Rothamsted (R) Woburn (W) R WwW
None None 0 Cc
5 5 > 5
10 12 lo 2
20 19 20 19
2. Phosphate, applied cumlatively to previous
aressings, as superphosphate (kg P205): P205
None 0
125 125
3. Potassium, applied cumlatively to previous
dressings as mriate of potash (kg K20): Ke20 -
None 0
188 188
Subd plots: 4. Magnesium, applied 1974 only, as Epsom salts
(kg Me): MG
None 0
12 n2
146
74/R/CS/10 and 74/w/Cs/10
Basal applications:

Sawyers I (R): Manures: 190 kg Nas 'Nitro-Chalk’. Weedkillers: Linuron
at 1.2 ke plus paraquat at 0.42 kg ion in 450 1. Fumgicide and
insecticide: Mancozeb at 1.3 kg plus demeton-s-methyl at 0.25 kg in
4so 1. Fungicides Mancozeb at 1.3 kg in 450 1.

Stackyard C (Ww): Manures: 250 kg N as 'Nitro-Chalk*, Weedkillers:
Aminotriazole at 4.5 kg plus ammonium thiocyanate at 4,1 kg in
370 1. Linuron at 1.2 ke plus paraquat at 0.28 kg ion in 280 1,
Fungicide and insecticides Mancozeb at 1.3 kg plus Gemeton-s-methyl at
0.25 kg in 450 1. Fumgicide: Mancozeb at 1.3 kg in 450 1.

Seed: Sawyers I (R) and Stackyard C (W): Pentland Crown,
Cultivations, etc, %-

Sawyers I (R): Ploughed: 19 Nov, 1973. Basal N applied: 23 Apr, 1974.
Treatment P, K and Mg applied, spike rotary cultivated, potatoes
planted: 24 Apr. Weedkiller applied: 17 May. Grubbed: 19 June.
Rotary ridged: 21 June. Fumgicide with insecticide applied: ll July.
Fungicide applied: 2 Aug. Haulm mechanically destroyed: 10 Sept.
Sprayed with undiluted BOV at 225 1: 19 Sept. Lifted: 30 Oct.

Stackyard C (W): Aminotriazole plus ammonium thiocyanate applied:

13 sept, 1973. Subsoiled, tines 140 cm apart 50 cm deep: 25 Oct.
Ploughed: 13 Nov. Spring-tine cultivated: 4 Apr, 1974. Basal N,
treatment P, K and Mg applied: 16 Apr. Rotary cultivated, potatoes
planted: 17 Apr. Weedkiller applied: 15 May. Rotary ridged: 12 June.
Fungicide with insecticide applied: 19 July. Fungicide applied:
7 Avg. Haulm mechanically destroyed: 12 Sept. Sprayed with
undiluted BOV at 170 1. Lifted: 30 Sept.

NOTES: (1) Leaf semples were taken in July for N, P, K, Ca and Mg

analysis.

(2) Photographs were taken end grovth scores made in June,

(3) 74/R/CS/10. Estimated values were used in the analysis for
yields from one whole plot, LIME - 20, P205 - 125, K20 - O,
because there was both visual and analytical evidence that K
residues from an unknown source affected growth over most of the
plot area,

(4) 74/Ww/CS/10. An anomalous yield from one sub plot LIME - 12,
P205 - 125, K20 - 188, MG - 112, was treated as missing. An
estimated value was used in the analysis.

Standard errors per plot, Total tubers: pamela ae
Sawyers I (R). Whole plot: 3.85 or 13.0% (14 4.f.)
- Sub plot: 4.05 or 13.7% (15 a.f.)
Stackyard C (W). Whole plot: 3.86 or 15.8% (15 4.f.)
Sub plot: 4,13 or 16.9% (15 4.f.)
147
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1975</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[15/B/C#/10 ane. 75/W/Ccs/10
LONG TERM LIMING
Cbject.s So study the effects of different encvnts of lime on the yielor
of a reree .S crops, The direct effects of P ard K we the residual
effects of Mg are elso studied - Rothamsted (%) Sawyers I and
Woburn (W) Stackyaré C.
Sponsor: J. Bolton.
The 1bt year, cats.
For previous years see 'Details' 1967, 68/C/3(1), €9/RaN/cs/10,
70/ReM/CS/10(t) end T1-74/ReW/CS/10.
Design: 2 randomised blocks of 16 plots, split into 2,
Whole plot dimensions: 6.40 x 18.3.
Treatments: All combinations ofs-
Whole plots: 1. Ground chalk (tonnes CaC03) (t tal applied 1962-63): LIME
Rothamsted (R) Weburn (w) R WwW
None None ° Qo
5 5 D 5
10 12 lio 62
20 19 20 19
2. Phosphate, applied cumlatively to previous
dressings, as superphosphate (kg F2n}): Pen5
None 0
63 63
3. Potassium, applied cumlatively to previous
dressings, eas mrijate of potash (kg K2C): Keo
None °
126 126
Sub picts: 4, Magnesium, applied 1974 only, as Epsom salts
(kg Mg): MG (7%)
None 0
ne2 uz
156
75/R/C8/10 and 75/W/cs/20
Basal applications:
Sawyers I (R): Manures: €0 kg N as *Nitro-Chalk* combine drilled,
Weedki Der: Dicenbs with necoprop and MOPA (*hanlene Plus’ at 5.6 1
in 220 1).
Stackyard C (W): Mamwres: 6 kg N as *Nitro-Chalk’ combine drilled.
Weedkijler: Ioxynil at 0.52 kg with mecoprop at 1.6 kg in 26 1.
Seed: Sawyers I (R) and Stackyard C (Wi):
Oets: Manod, sown at 200 ke.
Cultivations, etc. t-
Sawyers I (R): Chisel ploughed: 7 Feb, 1975. Trentuent P and K applied:
11 Mar. Rotary cultivated, seed sow, N applieds 25 Mar. Weedkiller
applied: 19 May. Combine harvested: 18 Aug.
Stackyard C (W): Ploughed: 11 Dec, 1974,. Treatment P and K applied:
17 Mar. Spring-tine cultivated, seed sown, N applied: 20 Mar,
Weedkiller applied: 22 May. Combine harvested: 18 Aug.
NOTE: Pictographs were taker, and growth scores made in Mey.
137
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1976</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[76/8/CS/10 and 76/W/CS/10
IONG TERM LIMING
Object: To study the effects of different amounts of lime on the yields
of a sequence of crops. The effects of P, K and Mé are also studied -
Rothamsted (R) Sawyers I and wobum (WwW) Stackyard C.
Sponsor: J. Bolton.
The 15th year, spring oilseed rape.
For previous years see “Detai)s’ 1967, 68/C/3(t), 69/Rém/CS/10,
/Réw/CS/10(t) and 71-75/R&W/CS/ 10.
Design: 2 randomised blocks of 16 plots, split into 2.
Whole plot dimensions: 6.40 x 18.3.
Treatments: All combinations of:-
whole plots
1. LIME Ground chalk (tonnes Ca003) (total applied 1962-63):
R WwW Rothamsted (R)  wobum (¥)
0 0 None None
$s § $ 5
10 12 10 12
20 19 20 19
2. P20S Phosphate, applied cumulatively to previous dressings,
as superphosphate (kg P25):
0 None
& 63
3. K20 Potassium, applied cumulatively to previous dressings,
as muriate of potash (kg K20):
0 None
126 15
Subd plots
4. MG Magnesium, applied cuaulatively in 1974 and 1976 only,
as Epsom salts (ke Me):
0 None
112 112
Basal applications: :
Sawyers I (R): Manures: N at 170 kg. Weedkillers: Paraquat at 0.56 ke
fon in 220 l.
Stackyard C (Ww): Manures: N at 170 ke.
Seed: Sawyers I (R): Maris Haplona, sown at 5.6 kee
Stackyard C (W): Maris Haplona, sown at 6.2 kg
120
76/8/CS/10 and 76/4/CS/10
Cultivations, etc.:-

Sawyers I (R): Weedkiller applied: 7 Oct, 1975. Ploughed: 20 Oct.
Sprine-tine cultivated: 11 Mar, 1976. Treatment P, K and Mg and
basal N applied: 24 Mar. Spring-tine cultivated, seed sown:

26 Mar. Harvested green: 14 July.

Stackyard C (W): Heavy spring-tine cultivated, rotary cultivated:
2 Sept, 1975. Ploughed: 21 Oct. Spring-tine cultivated: 9 Mar, 1976.
Treatment P, K and Mg applied: 26 Mar. Basal N applied: 29 Mar.
Spring-tine cultivated with crumbler: 30 Mar. Rolled, seed sown:
31 Mar. Harvested green: 7 July.

NOTES: (1) Photographs were taken and growth scores made in July.
(2) Because of crop failure no yield was harvestable on 5 plots
with the following Treatment Combinations:- :
LIME P205 Ka MG
0 0 0 0
0 0 1B 0 (TWO)
0 0 16 112 (TWO)
These yields were treated as zero, missing values were not
estimated.
76/R/CS/10 SAWYERS 1 (R)
GREENCROP DRY MATTER TONNES/HECTARE
sitet STRATUM STANDARD ERRORS AND COEFFICIENTS OF VARIATION *****
STRATUM DF SE CYS
BLOCK.WP 1S 0.470 30.3
BLOCK.WP SP 16 0.236 15-2
MEAN DM% 34.6
SUB PLOT AREA HARVESTED 0.00084
76/W/CS/10 STACKYARD C(w)
GREENCROP DRY MATTER TONNES/HECTARE
‘@eaH STRATUM STANDARD ERRORS AND COEFFICIENTS OF VARIATION *****
STRATUM DF SE CV%
BLOCK WP 15 0.324 28.7
BLOCK WPeSP 16 0.234 20.7
MEAN DM% 26.6
SUB PLOT AREA HARVESTED 0.00251
121
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1977</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[T1/R/CS/10 and 77/W/CS/10
LONG TERM LIMING
Object: To study the effects of different amounts of lime on the yields of a
sequence of crops. The effects of P, K and Mg are also studied - Rothamsted
(R) Sawyers I and Woburn (W) Stackyard C.
Sponsor: J. Bolton.
The 16th year, spring oats.
For previous years see 'Details' 1967, 1973 and 74-76/R&W/CS/10. ;
Design: 2 randomised blocks of 16 plots, split into 2.
Whole plot dimensions: 6.40 x 18.3. .
Treatments: All combinations of:-
Whole plots
1. LIME Ground chalk (tonnes Ca003) (total applied 1962-63):
R WwW
0 0 :
5 0D
10 12
20 19
2. P205 Phosphate, applied cumulatively to previous dressings,
as superphosphate (kg P205):
0
; 63
3. K20 Potassium, applied cumulatively to previous dressings,
as muriate of potash (kg K20):
0
126
Sub plots
4. MG Magnesium, applied cumulatively in 1974, 1976 and 1977 only,
as Epsan salts (kg Mg):
0
112
Basal applications:
Sawyers I (R): Manures: N at 80 kg, combine drilled. Weedkillers: Dicemba
with mecoprop end MCPA (‘Banlene Plus’ at 4.9 1 in 220 1). /
Stackyard C (W): Manures: N at 95 kg, combine drilled. Weedkillers: Loxynil
. at 0.53 kg plus mecoprop at 1.6 kg in 420 1.
Seed: Sawyers I (R) and Stackyard C (W): Manod, sown at 200 ke.
101
Cultivations, etc.:- .

Sawyers I (R): Deep-tine cultivated twice: 31 Aug, 1976. Ploughed: 11 Dec.
Treatment P and K applied: 29 Mar, 1977. Treatment Mg applied: 30 Mar.
Power harrowed, seed sown: 4 Apr. Weedkillers applied: 30 May. Canbine
harvested: 5 Sept.

Stackyard C (W): Power harrowed: 16 Aug, 1976. Ploughed: 23 Nov. Spring-
tine cultivated with crumbler attached: 9 Mar, 1977. Treatment P, K and
Mg applied: 18 Mar. Spring-tine cultivated with crumbler attached, seed
sown: 31 Mar. Weedkillers applied: 30 May. Combine harvested: 3 Sept.

GRAIN TONNES/HECTARE
##88® TABLES OF MEANS ###08
P205 0 63 MEAN
LIME
0 2.74 3.78 3.26
5 3.33 3.61 3.47
10 3.23 4,30 3.77
20 3.13 4,04 3.58
MEAN 3.11 3.93 3.52
K20 0 126 MEAN
LIME
0 3.50 3.03 3.26
5 3.56 3.38 3.47
10 3.82 3.72 3.77
20 3.68 3.48 3.58
MEAN 3.64 3.40 3.52
K20 0 126 MEAN
P205
0 3.29 2.92 3.11
63 3.98 3.88 3.93
MEAN 3.64 3.40 3.52
MG 0 112 MBEAN
LIME
0 2.38 4.14 3.26
5 3.01 3.93 3.47
10 3.54 4.00 3.77
20 3.64 3552 3.58
MEAN 3.14 3.90 3.52
MG 0 112 MEAN
P205
0 2.71 3.51 3.11
63 3.58 4.29 3.93
MEAN 3.14 3.90 3.52
102
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1978</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[78/R/CS/10 and 78/W/CS/10
LONG TERM LIMING
Odject: To study the effects of different amounts of lime on the yields of a
sequence of crops. The effects of P, K and Mg are also studied - Rothamsted
(R) Sawyers I and Woburn (W) Stackyard C.
Sponsor: J. Bolton.
The 17th year, spring barley.
For previous years see 'Details' 1967, 1973 and 74-77/R&W/CS/10.
Design: 2 randomised blocks of 16 plots, split into 2.
Whole plot dimensions: 6.40 x 18.3.
Treatments: All combinations of:-
Whole plots
1, LIME Ground chalk (tonnes Ca003) (total applied 1962-63):
R W
0 0
5 5
10 12
20 19
2. P205 Phosphate, applied cumulatively to previous dressings,
as superphosphate (kg P205):
Q
63
3. K20 Potassium, applied cumulatively to previous dressings,
as muriate of potash (kg K20):
0
126
Sub plots
4. OMG Magnesium, applied cumulatively in 1974, 1976 and 1977 as Epsom salts
and in 1978 as kieserite (kg Mg):
0
112
Basal applications:
Sawyers I (R): Manures: N at 80 kg, combine drilled. Weedkillers: Dicamba
with mecoprop and MCPA ('Banlene Plus’ at 4.9 1 in 220 1).
Stackyard C (W): Manures: N at 130 kg, combine drilled. Weedkillers: Paraquat
. at 0.56 kg ion in 220 1. Mecoprop, bromoxynil and ioxynil ('Brittox’
at 2.5 kg in 280 1). Fungicide: Tridemorph at 0.53 kg in 280 1.
NOTE: Paraquat was applied on Stackyard C (W) as a spot treatment to control
areas of couch grass (Agropyron repens).
113
78/R/CS/10 and 78/W/CS/10

Seed: Sawyers I (R) and Stackyard C (W): Porthos, dressed with ethirimol,

sown at 160 kg.

Cultivetions, ete.:-

Sawyers I (R): Ploughed: 2° Nov, 1977. Spring-tine cultivated: 7 Apr, 1978.
Treatment P, K and Mg applied, power harrowed, seed sown: 1° Apr.
Weedkiller applied: 8 June. Combine harvested: 8 Sept.

Stackyard C (W): Paraquat applied: 23 Sept, 1977. Ploughed: 30 Sept.
Spring-tine cultivated: 9 Mar. P, K and Mg applied, spring-tine
cultivated with crumbler attached: 13 Mar. Seed sown: 15 Mar. Spring-
tine cultivated with crumbler attached, seed resown because of bird
damage: 3 Apr. Weedkiller end fungicide applied: 15 May. Combine
harvested: 23 Aug.

NOTES: (1) At both Rothamsted and Woburn measurable yields were obtained from
treatment LIME 0 only in combinations with P205 63 and K20 126 (one
replicate at Rothamsted, two replicates at Woburn): Grain yields,
tonnes/hectare from these combinations were:

Rothamsted Woburn

LIME 0 P205 63 K20 126 MG O 1.51 1.05

LIME 0 P205 63 K20 126 MG 112 1.59 2.13
These figures have been excluded from the main analysis.

(2) At Rothamsted only, no measurable yields were obtained from one of
the replicates of certain combinations of LIME 5 with the other
treatments. Combinations affected were all those of P205 0 with
K20 0 and 126 and MG O and 112 and also the single combination
P205 63, K20 0, MG O. Yields from the remainder are presented in
the four-way tables but have been excluded from the analysis.

78/R/CS/10 SAWYERS I(R)

GRAIN TONNES/HECTARE

##88% TABLES OF MEANS #####

P205 . 0 63 MEAN
LIME
10 3.50 4.52 4.01
20 3.55 4.84 4,20
MEAN 3.52 4,68 4,10
K20 0 126 MEAN
LIME -
10 3.60 4.42 4.01
20 3.90 4.49 4,20
MEAN 3.75 445 4.10
K20 0 126 MEAN
P205
0 3.10 3.94 3.52
63 4,40 4.96 4.68
MEAN 3.75 4.u5 4.10
114
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1979</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[79/R/CS/10 and 79/W/CS/10
LONG TERM LIMING
Object: To study the effects of different anounts of lime on the yields of a
sequence of crops. The effects of P, K and Mg are also studied - Rothansted
(R) Sawyers I and Woburn (W) Stackyard C,
Sponsors: G.E.G. Mattingly, A. Penny.
The 18th year, fallow.
For previous years see 'Details’ 1967, 1973 and 74~78/R&W/CS/10.
Design: 2 randanised blocks of 16 plots, split into 2.
Whole plot dimensions: 6.40 x 18.3.
The experiments were fallowed in 1979 but additional treatment ground chalk was
applied: y
Ground chalk (tonnes):
R W
Total 1979 Total 1979
1962-63 1962-63
0 0 0 0
5 2 5 1
10 5 12 2
20 10 19 4
Basal application:
Sawyers I (R): Weedkiller: Glyphosate at 1.5 kg in 2201.
Stackyard C (W): Weedkiller: Glyphosate at 1.5 kg in 280 1.
Qultivations, etc.:-
Sawyers I (R): Weedkiller applied: 24 Oct, 1978. Test chalk applied: 29 Nov.
Ploughed: 21 Dec. Rotary cultivated: 12 June, 1979. Deep-tine cultivated:
3 July.
Stackyard C (W): Weedkiller applied: 14 Sept, 1978. Test chalk applied:
21 Nov. Ploughed: 22 Nov. Spring-tine cultivated with crumbler attached:
17 Apr, 1979. Rotary cultivated: 6 June. Rotary cultivated twice: 4 July,
16 Aug. Deep-tine cultivated: 21 Aug. Heavy spring-tine cultivated:
11 Sept.
93
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1980</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[80/R/CS/10 and 80/wW/CS/10
LONG TERM LIMING
Object: To study the effects of different amounts of lime on the yields of
@ sequence of crops. The effects of P, K and Mg are also studied -
Rothamsted (R) Sawyers I and Woburn (W) Stackyard C.
Sponsors: G.£.G. Mattingly, A. Penny.
The 19th year, fallow.
For previous years see ‘Details’ 1967, 1973 and 74-79/R&W/CS/10.
Design: 2 randomised blocks of 16 plots, split into 2.
Whole plot dimensions: 6.40 x 18.3.
The experiments were fallowed in 1980. .
 Cultivations, etc.:- .
Sawyers 1 (R}: Ploughed: 4 Dec, 1979. Heavy spring-tine cultivated:
21 Apr, 1980. Spring-tine cultivated: 22 May. Rotary cultivated:
19 June. Rotary harrowed: 4 Aug. - .
Stackyard C (W): Heavy spring-tine cultivated: 11 Sept, 1979, 3 Mar, *
1980, 7 Aug. Ploughed: 29 Nov, 1979, Rotary cultivated: 29 July, 1980.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1981</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[81/R/CS/10 and €1/W/CS/10
LONG TERM LIMING .

Object: To study the effects of different amounts of lime on the yields of
a sequence of crops. The effects of P & K are also studied -
Rothamsted (R) Sawyers I and Woburn (W) Stackyard C.

Sponsors: S. McGrath, D.P. Stribley.

The 20th year, s. oats.

For previous years see ‘Details’ 1967, 1973 and 74-80/R&W/CS/10.

Design: 2 randomised blocks of 16 plots.

Whole plot dimensions: 6.40 x 18.3.

Treatments: All combinations of:-

1. CHALK Ground chalk (tonnes CaC03) (total applied 1962-78):

R WwW
0 0
7 6

15 14

30 23

2.PK P&K fertilisers applied (in addition to a basal

dressing of 120 kg K in 1981):

(00)0 None

{OK )P1 K annually until 1978, 25 kg P in 1981

(PO)P1 P annually until 1978, 25 kg P in 1981

(PK )P3 P & K annually until 1978, 75 kg P in 1981

NOTES: (1) Unttl 1978 test P & K were applied cumulatively, rates varied

with crop. None was applied in 1979 & 1980 (fallow).
(2) A sub plot test of Mg applied in earlier years has been ignored.

Basal applications:

Sawyers I {R): Manures: N at 80 kg as ‘Nitro-Chalk' combine drilled, K
at 120 kg as muriate of potash, Mg at 100 kg as kieserite.
Weedkillers: Dicamba, mecoprop and MCPA (as ‘Herrisol' at 5.0 1) in
250 1.

Stackyard C (W): Manures: N at 80 kg as 'Nitro-Chalk', K at 120 kg as
muriate of potash Mg at 100 kg as kieserite. Weedkillers: Dicamba,
mecoprop and MCPA (as ‘Banlene Plus’ at 4.9 1) in 280 1 with the
fungicide. Fungicide: Tridemorph at 0.53 1.

Seed: Peniarth, sown at 190 kg (R), 200 kg (Ww).

102 :
81/R/CS/10 and 81/W/CS/10
Cultivations, etc.:-
Sawyers I (R): Basal K and Mg applied: 1 Dec, 1980. P treatments
applied, ploughed: 8 Dec. Rotary harrowed, seed sown:
13 Apr, 1981.
Weedkillers applied: 1 June. Combine harvested: 10 Sept.
Stackyard C (W): Ploughed: 13 Nov, 1980, 12 Dec. Basal K and Mg
applied: 8 Dec. N applied, heavy spring-tine cultivated: 6 Apr,
1981. Spring-tine cultivated with crumbler attached: 8 Apr. Rotary
Cul tivated, seed sown: 9 Apr. Weedkillers and fungicide applied:
1 June. Combine harvested: 3 Sept.
GRAIN TONNES/HECTARE
weeee TABLES OF MEANS *****
PK (00)0 (OK )P1 (PO)P1 (PK)P3 MEAN
CHALK
0 3.60 2.71 3.70 3.37 3.34
7 3.35 3.67 3.78 3,42 3.55
15 3.32 3.48 3.48 3.86 3.54
30 2.78 3.02 3.26 3.27 3.08
MEAN 3.26 3.22 3.55 3.48 3.38
*#*** STANDARD ERRORS OF DIFFERENCES OF MEANS *****
TABLE CHALK PK CHALK
PK
SED 0.139 0.139 0.278
wee** STRATUM STANDARD ERRORS AND COEFFICIENTS OF VARIATION *****
STRATUM OF Se Cvs
BLOCK.WP 15 0.278 8.2
GRAIN MEAN DM% 82.3
PLOT AREA HARVESTED 0.00520
103
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1982</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[82/R/CS/10 and 82/wW/CS/10
LONS TERM LIMING
Object: To study the effects of different anounts of lime on the yields
of a sequence of crops. The effects of P are also studied - Rothamsted

(R) Sawyers I and Woburn (W) Stackyard C.

Sponsors: S. McGrath, D.P. Stribley.

The 2ist year, s. oats.

For previous years see ‘Details’ 1967, 1973 and 74-81/R8w/CS/10.

Design: 2 randomised blocks of 16 plots.

Whole dimensions: 6.40 x 18.3.

Treataents: All combinations of:-

1. CHALK Ground chalk (tonnes CaC03) (total applied 1962-82):

Rothansted Woburn

R ow Total 1962-78 1982 Total 1962-78 1982
0 0 0 0 0 0
9 «68 7 2 6 2
20 19 15 5 14 5
40 33 30 10 23 10

2. P P fertilizer applied:

Until 1978 1981 1982

0 None None None

Pl «K 25 kg P 50 kg P

P2 P 25 kg P None

P3 P&K 75 kg P 50 kg P

NOTES: (1) Until 1978 test P & K were applied cumulatively, rates varied
with crop. None was applied in 1979 & 1980 (fallow).
(2) A basal dressing of 120 kg K has deen applied since 1981.
{3) A sub plot test of Mg applied in earlier years has been ignored,
but a basal dressing of 100 kg Mg was applied in 1981 and 40 kg
Mg in 1982.
Basal applications:

Sawyers I (R): Manures: N at 30 kg as 'Nitro-Cnalk' combine drilled, K
at 120 kg as muriate of potash, Mg at 40 kg as kieserite.
Weedkillers: Dicamba, mecoprop and MCPA (as 'Banlene Plus’ at 5.0 1)
in 250 1.

Stackyard C (W): Manures: N at 80 kg as ‘Nitro-Chalk', K at 120 kg as
muriate of potash, Mg at 40 kg as kieserite. Weedkillers: Dicamba,
mecoprop and MCPA (as ‘Herrisol’ at 4.9 1) in 280 1.

Seed: Peniarth, sown at 190 kg {R), 200 xg (w).
Cultivations, etc.:-

Sawyers I (2): Ground chalk, applied: 3-7 Dec, 1981. Ploughed: 3 Feb,
1982. Spring-tine cultivated: 5 Apr. P, K and Mg applied, seed
sown: 14 Apr. Weedkillers applied: 26 May. Combine harvested:
26-27 Aug.

Stackyard C (W): Ground chalk applied: 25 Nov, 1981. Ploughed: 26 Feb,
1982. P, and K applied: 24 Mar. Mg and N applied, heavy spring-tine
cultivated: 25 Mar. Spring-tine cultivated with crumbler attached,
seed sown: 29 Mar. Weedkillers applied: 26 May. Combine harvested:
20 Aug.
GRAIN TONNES/HECTARE
ReKKRE TABLES OF MEANS uREKK
P 0 PL P2 P3 MEAN
CHALK
9 1.21 1.20 1.52 1.74 1.42
9 1.15 1.92 1.47 1.38 1.48
20 1.18 1.22 1.37 1.47 1.31
40 1.13 1.43 1.32 1.65 1.38
MEAN 1.17 1.44 1.42 1.56 1.40
***** STANDARD ERRORS OF DIFFERENCES OF MEANS *****
TABLE CHALK P CHALK
P
SED 0.090 0.090 0.180
*eex* STRATUM STANDARD ERRORS AND COEFFICIENTS OF VARIATION *****
STRATUM OF SE CV%
BLOCK. WP 15 0.180 12.9
GRAIN MEAN DMZ 65.8
PLOT AREA HARVESTED 0.00520
92
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1983</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[83/R/CS/10 and 83/W/CS/10
LONG TERM LIMING
Object: To study the effects of different amounts of Time on the yields
of a sequence of crops. The effects of P are also studied - Rothamsted
(R) Sawyers I and Woburn (W) Stackyard C.
Sponsors: $.?. McGrath, D.P. Stribley.
The 22nd year, potatoes.
For previous years see ‘Details’ 1967, 1973 and 74-82/R&W/CS/10.
Design: 2 randomised blocks of 16 plots.
Whole plot dimensions: 6.40 x 18.3.
Treatments: All combinations of:-
1. CHALK Ground chalk (tonnes CaC03) (total applied 1962-83}:
Rothamsted Tota) Woburn Total
R WwW 1962-78 1982 1983 1962-78 1982 1983
0 (0 0 0 0 0 0 0
14 8 7 2 § 6 2 0
5 23 24 15 § 3 14 5 5
50 43 30 10 10 23 10 10
2. P P fertilizer applied:
Until 1978 1981 1982 1983
R&M R&W R&W R v
0 0 0 0 0 0
PL 9 Pl Pi 0 P2
P2 P Pl 0 P2 = P2
P3 P P3 Pl P24
Rates 1981-1983 Pl, P2, P3, P4 = 25, 50, 75, 100 kg P as superphosphate
NOTES: (1) Until 1978 test P was applfed cunulatively, rates varied with
crop. None was applied in 1979 and 1980 (fallow). K was
applied, cumulatively, to Pl and P3 plots. Since 1981 K has
been sop) ind basally.
(2) A sub plot test of Mg applied in earlier years has been ignored.
Since 1981 Mg has been applied basally.
Basal applications:
Sawyers 1 {R): Manures: N at 250 kg as 'Nitro-Chalk', K at 210 kg as
muriate of potash, Mg at 40 kg as kieserite. Weedk{llers: Linuron at
1.0 1 with paraquat at 0.4 kg fon in 500 1. Fungicide: Mancozeb at
1.4 kg in 250 1 on three occasions. fFentin hydroxide at 0.28 kg in
250 1 on five occasions with the insecticide on the first four
occasions. Insecticide: Pirimicard at 0.14 kg. Haulm desiccant:
Undituted BOY at 170 1.
96
83/R/CS/10 and 83/W/CS/10

Stackyard C (W): Manures: N at 260 kg as 'Nitro-Chalk', K at 210 kg as
muriate of potash, Mg at 40 kg as kfeserite. Weedkillers: Glyphosate
at 1.5 kg in 280 1. Linuron at 1.0 1 with paraquat at 0.4 kg fon in
250 1, Fungicide: Mancozeb at 1.4 kg in 250 1 on four occasions with
the insecticide on the first, third and fourth occasions. Fentin
hydroxfde at 0.28 kg {n 250 1 on four occasions with insecticide on
the first three occasions. Insecticide: Pirimicarb at 0.14 kg.
Haulm desiccant: Diquat at 0.50 kg fon in 250 1.

Seed: Pentland crow.
Cultivations, etc. :-

Sawyers I (R): Ground chalk treatments applied: 26 Nov, 1982. Ploughed:
1 Dec, P treatments and N, K and Mg applied: 11 May, 1983. Rotary
harrowed, potatoes planted: 23 May. Rotary ridged: 26 May.
Weedkillers applfed: 7 June. Mancozeb applied: 22 June, 25 Aug,

9 Sept. Fentin hydroxide applied with insecticide: 1 July, 8 July,

18 July, 28 July. Fentin hydroxide applied: 11 Aug. Haulm .
mechanically destroyed: 11 Oct. Haulm desiccant applied: 19 Oct.
Lifted: 28 Oct.

Stackyard C (W): Glyphosate appl fed: 12 Sept, 1982. Ploughed: 8 Oct.
Ground chalk treatments applied: 4 Nov. Ploughed: 23 Dec. Heavy
spring-tine cultivated: 21 Mar, 1983. P treatments and N, K and Mg
applied: 22 Mar. Heavy spring-tine cultivated: 28 Mar, 11 May.
Rotary cultivated, potatoes planted: 11 May. Rotary ridged,
weedkiller applied: 7 June. Mancozeb applied with insecticide:

22 June, 8 July, 18 July. Mancozeb applied: 1 July, Fentin
hydroxide applied with fnsecticide: 29 July, 11 Aug, 26 Aug. Fentin
hydroxide applTfed: 9 Sept. Haulm mechanically destroyed: 5 Oct.
Haulm desiccant applted: 17 Oct. Lifted: 7 Nov.
NOTE: Soil samples were taken from both sites after harvest for chemical
analyses.

]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1984</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[B4/R/CS/10 and 84/W/CS/10
LONG TERM LIMING
Object: To study the effects of different amounts of lime and phosphate
on the yields and compositions of a sequence of crops. Rothamsted (R)
Sawyers I and Woburn (W) Stackyard C.
Sponsors: T.M. Addiscott, S.P. McGrath.
The 23rd year, fallow. “
For previous years see ‘Details’ 1967, 1973 and 74-83/R&W/CS/10.
Design: 2 randomised blocks of 16 plots.
Whole plot dimensions: 6.40 x 18.3.
Cultivations, etc.:-

Sawyers I (R): Heavy spring-tine cultivated: 11 Nov, 1983 twice,

27 Apr, 1984, 9 May. Rotary cultivated: 27 Apr, 15 June, 12 July.
Spring-tine cultivated: 13 July.

Stackyard C (W): Oeep-tine cultivated: 16 Jan, 1984. Heavy spring-tine
cultivated: 15 May. Cultivated with thistle bar: 10 July, 10 Aug.
Rotary cultivated: 25 July.

]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1985</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[85/R/CS/10 and 85/W/CS/10
LONG TERM LIMING
Object: To study the effects of different amounts of lime and phosphate
on the yields and compositions of a sequence of crops. Rothamsted
(R) Sawyers I and Woburn (W) Stackyard C.
Sponsor: S$.P. McGrath,
The 24th year, s. barley.
For previous years see ‘Details’ 1967, 1973 and 74-84¢/R&W/CS/10.
Design: 2 randomised blocks of 16 plots.
Whole plot dimensions: 6.40 x 18.3.
Treatments: All combinations of:-
1. CHALK Residual effects of ground chalk (tonnes CaC03) (tota?
applied 1962-83):
Rothamsted total Woburn total

RW 1962-78 1982-83 1962-78 1982-83

00 0 9 0 0

14 8 7 7 6 2

23 24 15 8 14 10

50 43 30 20 23 20

2. P Residual effects of P fertilizer applied:
Until 1978 1981 1982 1983
R&wW R&W R&W R W

0 0 0 0 0 0

Pl 0 Pl Pl 0 P2

P2 Pp Pl O° P2 pP2

P3 Pp P3 Pi P2 pa

Rates 1981-83 Pl, P2, P3, P4 = 25, 50, 75, 100 kg P as superphosphate

NOTES: Until 1978 test P was applied cumulatively, rates varied with
crop, K was also applied cumulatively, to Pl and P3 plots. Since
1981 K has been applied basally.

Basal applications:-

Sawyers I (R): Manures: (25:0:16) at 450 kg. Weedkillers: Mecoprop
at 1.6 kg with bromoxynil at 0.20 kg and foxynil at 0.20 kg with
fungicide in 200 1. Fungicide: Tridemorph at 9.52 kg.

Stackyard C (W): Manures: (25:0:16) at 490 kg, Weedkillers:
Mecoprop at 1.2 kg with bromoxynt] at 0.26 kg and joxynil at
9.26 kg in 250 1,

Seed; Sawyers I (R): Klaxon, sown at 160 kg.
Stackyard C (W): Klaxon, sown at 150 kg,
96
85/R/CS/10 and 85/W/CS/10
Cultivations, etc.:-

Sawyers I (R): Ploughed: 3 Jan, 1985. NK applied, spring-tine
cultivated, rotary harrowed, seed sown: 18 Mar. Weedkillers with
fungicide applied: 16 May. Combine harvested: 23 Aug.

Stackyard C (Ww): Ploughed: 13 Mar, Spring-tine cultivated, NK
applied, harrowed, seed sown: 18 Mar. Weedkillers applied:
16 May. Combine harvested: 28 Aug.

NOTE: On Sawyers I (R) plots with treatment CHALK 0 gave no measurable
yield.

GRAIN TONNE S/HEC TARE
wiie® TABLES OF MEANS *****
P 0 Pl P2 P3 MEAN
CHALK
0 * * * * *
14 3.87 5.34 7.15 7.93 6.08
23 6.27 7.36 8.16 8.26 7.51
50 7.02 7.67 8.22 8.19 7.78
MEAN 5.72 6.79 7.84 8.13 7.12
x&x*e STANDARD ERRORS OF DIFFERENCES OF MEANS *****
TABLE CHALK Pp CHALK
P
sD 0.416 0.480 0.831
wee STRATUM STANDARD ERRORS AND COEFFICIENTS OF VARIATION *****
STRATUM OF SE CVE
BLOCK . WP ll 0.831 11.7 ;
GRAIN MEAN DM% 76.7
PLOT AREA HARVESTED 0,00373
97
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1986</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[86/R/CS/10 and 86/W/CS/10
LONG TERM LIMING
Object: To study the effects of different amounts of lime and phosphate
on the yields and compositions of a sequence of crops. Rothamsted
(R) Sawyers I and Woburn (W) Stackyard C,
Sponsor: S.P. McGrath.
The 25th year, w. triticale.
For previous years see ‘Details’ 1967, 1973 and 74-85/R&W/CS/10.
Design: 2 randomised blocks of 16 plots.
Whole plot dimensions: 6.40 x 18.3.
Treatments: All combinations of:-
1, CHALK Residual effects of ground chalk (tonnes CaC03) (total
applied 1962-83):
Rothamsted total Woburn total
RW 1962-78 1982-83 1962-78 1982-83
00 0 0 0 0

14 8 7 7 6 2

23 24 15 8 14 10

50 43 30 20 23 20

Zac? Restdual effects of P fertilizer applied:
Until 1978 1981 1982 1983
R&wW R&W R&wW R W
0 0 0 0 0 60

Pl 0 Pi Pl 0 P2

4 Pp Pi 0 P2 P2

P3 P P3 Pl P2 Pa

Rates 1981-83 P1, P2, P3, P4 = 25, 50, 75, 100 kg P as superphosphate

NOTES: Until 1978 test P was applied cumulatively, rates varied with
crop, K was also applied cumulatively, to Pl and P3 plots. Since
1981 K has been applied basally (none in 1986),

Basal applications:-

Sawyers I (R): Manures: N at 170 kg as ‘Nitram’. Weedkiller:
Glyphosate at 1.4 kg in 200 1.

Stackyard C (W): Manures: N at 190 kg as 'Nitram'. Weedkillers:
Clopyralid at 0.05 kg with bromoxynil octanoate at 0.24 kg and
mecoprop at 2.1 kg in 250 |.

Seed: Sawyers I (R): Lasko, sown at 190 kg.
Stackyard C (W): Lasko, sown at 160 kg.
90
86/R/CS/10 and 86/W/CS/10
Cultivations, etc.:-
Sawyers I (R): Weedkiller applied: 23 Sept, 1985. Ploughed: 8 Oct.
Rolled, disced, rotary harrowed, seed sown: 23 Oct. N applied:
30 Apr, 1986. Combine harvested: 10 Sept.
Stackyard C (W): Ploughed: 9 Oct, 1985. Rolled, power harrowed, seed
sown: 22 Oct. N applied: 30 Apr, 1986. Weedkillers applied:
19 May. Combine harvested: 7 Sept.
GRAIN TONNES/HEC TARE
*«an® TABLES OF MEANS *****
P 0 Pl P2 P3 MEAN
CHALK
0 5.49 4.08 7.66 7.75 6.24
14 6.99 8.10 8.40 8.51 8,00
23 7,81 8.12 8.51 8.65 8.27
50 7,52 8.32 8.32 8.62 8.20
MEAN 6.95 7.15 8.22 8.38 7.68
weet STANDARD ERRORS OF DIFFERENCES OF MEANS *****
TABLE CHALK Pp one
SED 0.246 0.246 0.491
weae® STRATUM STANDARD ERRORS AND COEFFICIENTS OF VARIATION *****
STRATUM OF SE CVs
BLOCK . WP 15 0.491 6.4
GRAIN MEAN DMZ 84.6
PLOT AREA HARVESTED 0,00373
91
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1987</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[87/R/CS/10 and 87/W/CS/10
LONG TERM LIMING
Object: To study the effects of different amounts of lime and phosphate
on the yields and compositions of a sequence of crops. Rothamsted
(R) Sawyers I and Woburn (W) Stackyard C,
Sponsors: S.P. McGrath, J. McEwen, D.P. Yeoman.
The 26th year, Lupinus albus.
For previous years see ‘Details’ 1967, 1973 and 74-86/R&W/CS/10.
Design: 2 randomised blocks of 16 plots split into 2.
Whole plot dimensions: 6.40 x 18.3,
Treatments: All combinations of:-
Whole plots
1, CHALK Residual effects of ground chalk (tonnes CaC03)
{total applied 1962-87):
Rothamsted total Woburn total
R W 1962-78 1982-87 1962-78 1982-87
0 0 0 0 0 0
15 9 7 8 6 3
24.5 25.5 15 9.5 14 11.5
52.5 45.5 30 22.5 23 22.5
2. P Residual effects of P fertilizer applied:
Until 1978 1981 1982 1983
R&wW R&W R&wW R WwW
0 0 0 0 0 6(—0
Pl 0 Pl Pl 0 P2
P2 P Pl 0 P2 =p2
P3 Pp P3 Pl P2 P4
Rates 1981-83 P1, P2, P3, P4 = 25, 50, 75, 100 kg P as superphosphate
Sub plots
3. MANGNESE Manganese applied in 1987:
0 None
MN Manganese sprays
NOTES: (1) Until 1978 test P was applied cumulatively, rates varied with
crop, K was also applied cumulatively, to Pl and P3 plots.
Since 1981 K has been applied basally (none in 1986 and 1987).
(2) On Sawyers I (R) manganese was applied as manganese lignin
polycarboxylate (‘Stoller Manganese’ at 3,0 1 in 200 1 on
5 June, 1987 and at 9.0 1 in 200 1 on 11 Aug).
(3) On Stackyard C (W) manganese was applied at 0.19 kg Mn on
4 June, 1987 and 0.57 kg Mn on 4 Aug as manganese sulphate in
200 1.
77
87/R/CS/10 and 87/W/CS/10
Basal applications:-

Sawyers I (R): Weedkillers: Terbutryne at 0,98 kg with terbuthylazine
at 0.42 kg in 200 1. Fungicide: Benomy] at 0.50 kg applied with
the insecticide and a wetting agent ('Agral' at 0,06 1) in 200 1}.
Insecticide: Pirimicard at 0.14 kg.

Stackyard C (W): Weedkillers: Glyphosate at 1.4 kg in 200 1.
Terbutryne at 0.56 kg with terbuthylazine at 0.24 kg in 240 1.
Fungicide: Benomy] at 1.0 kg applied with the pirimicarb and a
wetting agent (‘Enhance' at 0.06 1) in 200 1. Insecticides:
Deltamethrin at 0.038 kg in 200 1. Pirimicarb at 0.15 kg.

Seed: Sawyers I (R): Vladimir, sown at 260 kg.
Stackyard C (W): Vladimir, sown at 250 kg.
Culttvations, etc.:-

Sawyers I (R): Chalk treatments applied: 13 Nov, 1986, Ploughed:
14 Nov. Spring-tine cultivated, rotary harrowed, seed sown,
harrowed: 31 Mar, 1987, Weedkillers applied: 13 Apr. Fungicide
and insecticide applied: 9 July. Combine harvested: 17 Nov.

Stackyard C (W): Glyphosate applied: 16 Sept, 1986. Chalk treatments
applied: 13 Nov. Ploughed: 28 Nov. Spike harrowed with crumbler
attached, seed sown: 6 Apr, 1987. Harrowed, terbutryne and
terbuthylazine applied: 13 Apr. Deltamethrin applied: 8 May.
Benomy] and pirimicarb applied: 13 July. Combine harvested:
18 Nov.

GRAIN TONNES/HEC TARE
*#eee* Tables of means *****
P 0 Pl P2 P3 Mean
CHALK
0 0.71 1.33 2.28 2.97 1.82
15 2.86 2.25 3.47 2.65 2.81
24.5 2.98 2.24 3.69 2.56 2.87
52.5 2.87 2.31 4.04 3.17 3.10
Mean 2.36 2.03 3.37 2.84 2.65
MANGNESE 0 MN Mean
CHALK
0 1.89 1.76 1.82
15 2.69 2.92 2.81
24.5 2.98 2.75 2.87
52.5 3.04 3.15 3.10
Mean 2.65 2.64 2.65
MANGNE SE 0 MN Mean
p
0 2.38 2.33 2.36
Pi 2.12 1.94 2.03
P2 3.32 3.42 3.37
P3 2.78 2.89 2.84
Mean 2.65 2.64 2.65
78
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1988</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[88/R/CS/10 and 88/W/CS/10
LONG TERM LIMING
Object: To study the effects of different amounts of lime and phosphate
on the yields and compositions of a sequence of crops. Rothamsted
(R) Sawyers I and Woburn (W) Stackyard C.
Sponsor: S.P. McGrath.
The 27th year, linseed.
For previous years see ‘Details’ 1967, 1973 and 74-87/R&W/CS/10.
Design: 2 randomised blocks of 16 plots split into 2.
Whole plot dimensions: 6.40 x 18.3.
Treatments: All combinations of:-
Whole plots
1. CRALK Residual effects of ground chalk (tonnes CaC03)
(total applied 1962-87):
Rothamsted total Woburn total
R Ww 1962-78 1982-87 1962-78 1982-87
0 0 0 0 0 0
is 9 7 8 6 3
24.5 25.5 15 9.5 14 11.5
52.5 45.5 30 22.5 23 22.5
Oeil Effects of P fertilizer applied:
Until 1978 1981 1982 1983 1988
Réw R&wW Réw R w R "
0 0 0 0 o 0 o ¢
Pl 0 Pl Pl 0 P2 Pl Pt
P2 P Pl 0 P2 =P2 Pl Pil
P3 Pp e3 Pl P2 P4 P3 PBB
Rates 1981-83 Pl, P2, P3, P4 = 25, 50, 75, 100 kg P as superphosphate
Sub plots
3. MANGNESE Manganese, cumulative to earlier applications:
0 None
MN Manganese sprays
NOTES: (1) Until 1978 test P was applied cumulatively, rates varied with
crop, K was also applied cumulatively, to Pl and P3 plots.
Since 1981 K has been applied basally (none in 1986 and 1987).
(2) On Sawyers I (R) manganese was applied at 0.15 kg Mn, as
manganese chelate, in 260 1 on 20 June, 1988, repeated in
200 1 on 19 July.

: (3) On Stackyard C (W) manganese was applied at 0.16 kg Mn in
220 1 on 15 June and at 0.15 kg Mn with sulphur at 0.12 kg S
in 220 1 on 15 July.

76
88/R/CS/10 and 88/W/CS/10
Basal applications:

Sawyers I (R): Manures: ‘Nitram’ at 250 kg. Muriate of potash at
160 kg. Kieserite at 270 kg. Weedkiller: Trifluralin at 1.1 kg
in 450 1. Desiccant: Diquat 0.60 kg ion applied with a wetting
agent (’Agral’ at 0.50 1) in 240 1.

Stackyard C (W): Manures: ‘Nitram’ at 250 kg. Muriate of potash at
160 kg. Kieserite at 110 kg. Weedkillers: Trifluralin at 0.84 kg
in 200 i. Linuron at 0.26 kg in 220 1. Desiccant: Diquat at
0.60 kg ion in 400 1.

Seed: Antares, dressed iprodione and benomyl, sown at 87 kg (R).
Antares, dressed benomyl, sown at 80 kg (W).
Cultivations, etc.:-

Sawyers I (R): P treatments, K and Mg applied: 14 Dec, 1987.
Ploughed: 15 Dec. Heavy spring-tine cultivated: 5 Apr, 1988. N
applied: 7 Apr. Weedkiller applied, spring-tine cultivated twice:
12 Apr. Rotary harrowed, seed sown, harrowed: 13 Apr. Desiccant
applied: 19 Sept. Combine harvested: 24 Oct.

Stackyard C (W): P treatments, K and Mg applied: 10 Feb, 1988.
Ploughed: 23 Feb. Heavy spring-tine cultivated: 5 Apr. N
applied, spike harrowed with crumbler attached, trifluralin
applied, spike harrowed with crumbler attached, seed sown:
22 Apr. Linuron applied: 5 May. Desiccant applied: 21 Sept.
Combine harvested: 1 Nov.
NOTE: At Rothamsted treatment combinations with CHALK 0 did not give a
measurable yield.

GRAIN (AT 90% DRY MATTER) TONNES/HECTARE
seee* Tables of means *****
Pp 0 Pl P2 P3 Mean
CHALK
1s 2.53 2.57 2.78 2.89 2.69
24.5 2.57 2.90 2.76 2.84 2.77
$2.5 2.62 2.81 2.62 2.59 2.66
Mean 2.57 2.76 2.42 anrt 2.70
MANGNESE ° MN Mean
CHALK
15 2.73 2.65 2.69
24.5 2.78 2.76 2.77
$2.5 2.65 2.66 2.66
Mean 2.72 2.69 2.70
77
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1989</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[89/R/CS/10 and 89/W/CS/10
LONG TERM LIMING
Object: To study the effects of different amounts of lime and phosphate
on the yields and compositions of a sequence of crops. Rothamsted
{R) Sawyers I and Woburn (W) Stackyard C.
Sponsor: $.P. McGrath, J.M. McEwen, D.P. Yeoman.
The 28th year, 8s. beans.
Por previous years see ‘Details’ 1967, 1973 and 74-88/R&éW/CS/10.
Design: 2 randomised blocks of 16 plots split into 2.
Whole plot dimensions: 6.40 x 18.3.
Treatments: All combinations of:-
Whole plots
1. CHALK Residual effects of ground chalk (tonnes CaC03)
(total applied 1962-87):
Rothamsted total Woburn total
R w 1962-78 1982-87 1962-78 1982-87
0 0 9 9 0 9
15 9 7 8 6 3
24.5 25.5 15 9.5 14 11.5
$2.5 45.5 30 22.5 23 22.5
2. 8 Residual effects of P fertilizer applied:
Until 1978 1981 1982 1983- 1988
R&W Ré&W Réw R w R Ww
0 0 0 0 0 9 0 0
Pl 0 Pl Pl Oo P2 Pl Pl
P2 P Pl 0 P2 P2 Pl Pl
P3 Pp P3 Pl P2 P4 P3 P3
Rates 1981-83 Pl, P2, P3, P4 = 25, 50, 75, 100 kg P as superphosphate
Sub plots
3. MANGNESE Manganese in 1989, cumulative to earlier applications:
0 None
MN Manganese sprays
NOTES: (1) Until 1978 test P was applied cumulatively, rates varied with
crop, K was also applied cumulatively, to Pl and P3 plots.
Since 1981 K has been applied basally (none in 1986, 1987
and 1989).
(2) Manganese was applied at 0.19 kg Mn, as ’Vytel’, in 200 1 on
17 May, 1989 (R), in 220 1 on 22 May (W) repeated at 0.10 kg
Mn in 200 1 on 13 June (R), in 220 1 on 15 June (Ww).
66
89/R/CS/10 and 89/W/cS/10
Basal applications: “is

Sawyers I (R): Weedkillers: Simazine at 0.17 kg and trietazine at
1.2 kg in 200 1. Fungicides: Benomy] at 0.55 kg in 200 1.
Fenpropimorph at 0.75 kg in 200 1. Insecticides: Deltamethrin at
7.5 ¢g in 400 1 applied on two occasions. Pirimicarb at 0.14 kg
im 200 1.

Stackyard C (W); Weedkillers: Simazine at 0.14 kg and trietazine at
1.0 kg in 220 1, Alloxydim-sodium at 1.5 kg in 220 1.

Fungicides: Fenpropimorph at 0.75 kg in 220 1. Benomyl at 0.55 kg
applied with a wetting agent in 220 1. Insecticides: Deltamethrin
at 6.2 g in 220 1 and at 7.5 g in 220 1 on a second occasion. :
Pirimicarb at 0.14 kg in 220 1,

Seed: Alfred, sown at 200 kg (R & ¥).

Cultivations, etc. :-

Sawyers I (R): Ploughed: 20 Dec, 1988. Heavy spring-tine cultivated,
rotary harrowed: 29 Mar, 1989. Rotary harrowed, seed sown, i
harrowed, rolled: 30 Mar. Weedkiller applied: 31 Mar.
Deltamethrin applied: 10 May and 31 May. Pirimicarb applied:

14 June. Benomyl and fenpropimorph applied: 14 July. Combine
harvested: 14 Aug.

Stackyard C (W); Ploughed: 14 Dec, 1988. Spring-tine cultivated:

28 Mar, 1989. Rotary harrowed, seed sown: 31 Mar. Simazine and
trietazine applied: 22 Apr. Deltamethrin applied: 22 May and
7 June. Alloxydim-sodium applied: 7 June. Pirimicarb applied:
22 Sune. Benomyl and fenpropimorph applied: 12 July. Combine
harvested: 22 Aug.
NOTES: (1) Establishment counts were made and components of yield were
measured at maturity.

(2) Soils were sampled for pH, P, K and Mg.

(3) Most CHALK 0 plots failed and yields of the rest of these
plots were negligible. They have been omitted from the
analysis.

89/R/CS/10 SAWYERS I (R)
GRAIN TONNES/HECTARE
vaee® Tables of means *****
P 0 Pl P2 P3 Mean

CHALK
15 0.80 0.72 0.94 1.16 0.90

24.5 0.84 1.22 1.06 1.03 1.04

52.5 1.12 1.48 052 1.47 1.40

Mean 0.92 1.14 1.17 1.22 1.11
MANGNESE ° MN Mean

CRALK

1s 0.96 0.84 0.90
24.5 1.06 1.01 1.04
$2. 1.50 1.30 1.40
Mean 1.17 1.05 1.11

67
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1990</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[90/R/CS/10 and 90/w/CS/10
. LONG TERM LIMING
Object: To study the effects of different amounts of lime and phosphate
on the yields and compositions of a sequence of crops - Rothamsted 2
(R) Sawyers I and Woburn (W) Stackyard C.
Sponsors: S.P. McGrath, J. McEwen, D.P. Yeoman.
The 29th year, s. beans.
For previous years see ‘Details’ 1967, 1973 and 74-89/R&W/CS/10.
Design: 2 randomised blocks of 16 plots split into 2.
Whole plot dimensions: 6.40 x 18.3. |
Treatments: All combinations of:-
Whole plots
1. CHALK Residual effects of ground chalk (tonnes CaC03)
{total applied 1962-87):
Rothamsted total Woburn total
R W 1962-78 1982-87 1962-78 1982-87
0 0 0 0 0 0
15s 9 7 8 - 6 3
24.5 25.5 15 9.5 14 12.5
52.5 45.5 30 22.5 23 22.5
2. . Residual effects of P fertilizer applied:
Until 1978 1981 1982 1983 1988
R6&W Raw R&Ww R WwW R WwW
0 0 0 ° o 0 0. (0
Pl 0 Pl Pl Oo P2 Pl Pl
P2 Pe Pl 0 P2 P2 el. (Fi;
P3 Pp P3 Pl P2 pa P3 P3
Rates 1981-83 Pl, P2, P3, P4 = 25, 50, 75, 100 kg P as superphosphate
Sub plots
3. MANGNESE Manganese in 1990, cumulative to earlier applications:
0 None
MN Manganese sprays
NOTES: (1) Until 1978 test P was applied cumulatively, rates varied with
crop, none in 1979 and 1980. K was also applied cumulatively,
to Pl and P3 plots.
Since 1981 K has been applied basally (none in 1986, 1987,
1989 and 1990).
(2) Manganese was applied at 0.19 kg Mn, as ‘vytel’, in 200 1 on
30 Apr, 1990 (R), at 0.096 kg Mn in 220 1 on 30 Apr (W)
repeated at 0.096 kg Mn in 200 1 on 5 June (R).
54
90/R/CS/10 and 90/W/CS/10 ,

Basal applications:

Sawyers I (R): Weedkillers: Simazine at 0.17 kg and trietazine at
1.2 kg in 200 1. Insecticides: Phorate at 2.2 kg. Deltamethrin
at 7.5 g in 200 1 applied on two occasions. Pirimicarb at
0.14 kg in 200 1.

Stackyard C (W): Weedkillers: Glyphosate at 1.4 kg in 220 1.
Simazine at 0.14 kg and trietazine at 0.97 kg in 220 1. Paraquat
at 0.60 kg ion. Insecticide: Phorate at 1.8 kg.

Seed: Alfred, sown at 260 kg (R), 250 kg (W).

Cultivations, etc.:-

Sawyers I (R): Tine cultivated with vibrating tines 60 cm apart,

45 cm deep: 23 Aug, 1989. Ploughed: 24 Nov. Spring-time
cultivated: 5 Mar, 1990. Rotary harrowed, phorate applied, rotary
harrowed, seed sown, harrowed and rolled: 6 Mar. Simazine and
trietazine applied: 12 Mar. Deltamothrin applied: 2 and 17 May.
Pirimicarb applied: 5 June. Combine harvested: 15 Aug.

Stackyard C (W): Glyphosate applied: 1 Sept, 1989. Ploughed: 5 Jan,
1990. Phorate applied, power harrowed with crumbler attached,
seed sown: 5 Mar. Simazine and trietazine applied: 13 Mar.
Paraquat applied: 25 May.

NOTES: (1) At Woburn the crop established poorly as a result of bird
damage. The few remaining plants were destroyed with
weedkiller in May.

{2) At Rothamsted leaf samples were taken just after pod set to
measure nutrient contents, :

(3) At Rothamsted the components of yield were measured at
maturity.

(4) At Rothamsted, most CHALK 0 plots failed and yields of the
rest of these plots were negligible. They have been omitted
from the analysis.

90/R/CS/10 SAWYERS I ({R)

GRAIN TONNES /HECTARE

aeene Tadlea of means ***** :
Pe 0 Pl " p2 P3 Mean ;

CHALK
15 1.64 1.82 1.93 2.27 1.91

24.5 2.10 2.74 2.66 2:73 2.57

$2.5 2.52 3.07 3.21 3.38 3.05

Mean 2.09 2.54 2.60 2.81 2.52
MANGNESE ° MN Mean

CHALK

15 2.02 1.82 1.91
24.5 2.59 2.56 2.87
52.5 3.10 3.00 3.05
Mean 2.56 2.46 2.51

55
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1991</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[91/R/CS/10 and 91/W/CS/10
LONG TERM LIMING
Object: To study the effects of different amounts of lime, phosphate and
sulphur on the yields and compositions of a sequence of crops -
Rothamsted (R) Sawyers I and Woburn (W) Stackyard C.
Sponsors: S.P. McGrath, P.B. Barraclough, G.F.J. Milford.
The 30th year, w. oflseed rape. :
For previous years see ‘Details’ 1967, 1973 and 74-90/R&W/CS/10.
Design: 2 randomised blocks of 16 plots split into 2.
Whole plot dimensions: 6.0 x 18.3.
Treatments: All combinations of:-
Whole plots
1. CHALK Residual effects of ground chalk (tonnes CaCc03)
(total applied 1962-87):
Rothamsted total Woburn total
R Ww 1962-78 1982-87 1962-78 1982-87 .
0 oO 0 0 0 0
15 9 7 8 6 3
24.5 25.5 15 9.5 “14 11.5
$2.5 45.5 30 22.5 23 22.5
2. Residual effects of P fertilizer applied:
Until 1978 1981 1982 1983 1988
R&W Rsw Réw R w R "
0 9 0 0 9 0 9 0
Pl 0 Pl Pl Oo P2 Ba ORL:
P2 P Pl 0 P2 p2 Pl Pl
P3 Pp P3 Pl P2 Pd P3  P3
Rates 1981-83 Pl, P2, P3, P4 = 25, 50, 75, 100 kg P as superphosphate
Sub plots
3. SULPHUR Sulphur (kg $, as calcium sulphate):
0
30
NOTES: (1) Until 1978 test P was applied cumulatively, rates varied with
crop, none in 1979 and 1980. K was also applied cumulatively,
to Pl and P3 plots. Since 1981 K has been applied basally
(none in 1986, 1987, 1999 and 1990).
(2) Sulphur was applied as gypsum (17.5% S) on 13 Mar, 1991 (R),
21 Mar (W).
(3) Test manganese was applied cumulatively, 1987-90.
46
91/R/C8/10 and 91/W/CS/10
Basal applications:

Sawyers I (R): Manures: (25:0:16) at 200 kg. ‘Nitram' at 640 kg.
Magnesium at 0.13 kg as ‘Vytel Liquid Magnesium’ in 200 1.
Manganese at 0.093 kg as 'Vytel Liquid Manganese’ in 200 1.
Weedkillers: Metazachlor at 0.75 kg in 200 1. Clopyralid at
0.10 kg in 200 1. Fungicide: Prochloraz at 0.50 kg in 200 1 and on
a@ second occasion at 0.40 kg in 200 1. Insecticide: Deltamethrin
at 6.2 g in 200 1 and at 12 g in 200 1 on a second occasion.
Desiccant: Diquat at 0.60 kg ion applied with wetting agent,
*Vassgro' at 0.52 1, in 520 1. Irrigation: 25 mm applied on two
occasions.

Stackyard C (W): Manures: (25:0:16) at 200 kg. Magnesium at 0.13 kg
as 'Vytel Liquid Magnesium' in 200 1. ‘'Nitram' at 580 kq.
Manganese at 0.078 kg as 'Vytel Liquid Manganese’ in 300 1.
Weedkillers: Quizalofop-ethyl at 38 g with metazachlor at 0.75 kg
applied with adjuvant 'Cropspray 11 EB’ at 2.0 1 in 220 1.
Fungicide: Prochloraz at 0.28 kg applied with the second
insecticide in 200 1. Insecticide: Deltamethrin at 6.2 g in 220 1
and on a second occasion ‘at 12 g. Desiccant: Diquat at 0.60 kg
ion applied with a wetting agent, ‘Agral* at 0.40 1, in 400 1.

Seed: Libravo, dressed fenpropimorph, gamma-HCH, and thiram, at 6.0 kg
(R & W).
Cultivations, etc. :-

Sawyers I (R): N and K applied: 23 Aug, 1990. Ploughed: 28 Aug.
Rolled: 29 Aug. Rotary harrowed: 30 Aug. Rotary harrowed, seed
sown, harrowed, rolled, metazachlor applied: 31 Aug. Irrigated:
21 and 27 Sept. Deltamethrin applied: 7 Nov. Prochloraz and Mg
applied: 3 Dec. Clopyralid applied: 17 Dec. N applied: 4 Mar,
1991. Second deltamethrin applied: 12 Apr. Second prochloraz and
Mn applied: 23 Apr. Desiccant with wetting agent applied:

30 July. Combine harvested: 7 Aug.

Stackyard C (W): Disced: 15 Aug, 1990. Subsoiled with tines 1.5 m
apart, 0.4 m deep: 21 Aug. Ploughed and rolled: 22 Aug. WN and K
applied: 28 Aug. Rotary harrowed with crumbler attached, seed
sown: 30 Aug. Weedkillers and adjuvant applied: 1 Nov.
Deltamethrin applied: 15 Nov. Mg applied: 3 Dec. N applied:

15 Mar, 1991. Second deltamethrin applied with fungicide: 12 Apr.

Mn applied: 9 May. .Desiccant with wetting agent applied: 1 Aug.

Combine harvested: 13 Aug.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1992</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[92/R/CS/10 and 92/W/CS/10 ——
LONG TERM LIMING ; PO
Object: To study the effects of different amounts of lime, phosphate ‘and .
sulphur on the yields and compositions of a sequence of crops -... .
Rothamsted (R) Sawyers I and Woburn (W) Stackyard C. .
Sponsors: S.P. McGrath, P.B. Barraclough, G.F.J. Milford.
The 3ist year, w. oilseed rape.
For previous years see ‘Details’ 1967, 1973 and 74-91/R&W/CS/10. .
Design: 2 randomised blocks of 16 plots split into 2.
Whole plot dimensions: 5.8 x 16.1 (R), 5.6 x 16.1 (W). al
Treatments: All combinations of:- ,
Whole plots >
1. CHALK Residual effects of ground chalk (tonnes Caco3)
(total applied 1962-87):
Rothamsted total ~ “Woburn total :
R w 1962-78 1982-87 1962-78 1982-87
0 0 0 0 0 0
1s 9 7 8 6 3
24.5 25.5 15 9.5 14 11.5
$2.5 45.5 30 22.5 23 22.5
2. P Residual effects of P fertilizer applied:
Until 1978 1981 1982 1983 1988
R&W R&W R&W R Ww R Ww
0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0
Pl 9 Pl Pl 0 P2 Pl Pl
P2 P Pl ° P2 P2 Pl Pl
P3 P P3 Pl P2 Pd P33
Rates 1981-83 and 1988 Pl, P2, P3, P4 = 25, 50, 75, 100 kg P as
superphosphate .
Sub plots
3. SULPHUR Sulphur (kg S, as calcium sulphate):
0
30
MOTES: (1) Until 1978 test P was applied cumulatively, rates varied with
crop, none in 1979 and 1980. K was also applied cumulatively,
to Pl and P3 plots. Since 1981 K has been applied basally
(none in 1986, 1987, 1989 and 1990).
{2) Test manganese was applied cumulatively, 1987-90.
50
92/R/C8/10 and 92/w/cs/10
Experimental diary:
Sawyers I (R)-
25-Aug-91 : B : Deep-tine cultivated with vibrating tines 60 cm apart,
45 cm deep.
26-Aug-91 : B : Ploughed, rolled.
04-Sep-91 : B : Rotary harrowed.
05-Sep-91 : B : Rotary harrowed, Libravo, dressed Hydraguard and
Rovral WP, drilled at 6.1 kg, rolled.
06-Sep-91 : B : Butisan S at 2.5 1 in 200 1.
24-Oct-91 : B : NK as (25:0:16) at 200 kg.
02-Dec-91 : B : Vytel Liquid Chelated Magnesium at 2.0 1 in 200 1.
05-Mar-92 : T : SULPHUR 30: 30 kg S as gypsun.
05-Mar-92 : B : 34.5% N at 220 kg.
13-Apr-92 : B : Ploughed (crop failed).
Stackyard C (W).
03-Sep-91 : B : Ploughed.
06-Sep-91 : B : Rotary cultivated, Libravo, dressed Hydraguard and
Rovral wp, drilled at 6.0 kg, rolled. :
29-Oct-91 : B : NK as (25:0:16) at 200 kg.
15-Jan-92 : B : Benazalox at 1.25 kg in 200 1.
05-Mar-92 : 2 : SULPHUR 30: 30 kg S as gypsum.
06-Mar-92 : B : 34.5% N at 220 kg.
13-May-92 : B : Ploughed (crop failed).
NOTE: Owing to crop failure no yields were taken. i
$1
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1993</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[93/R/CS/10 and 93/w/CS/10
LONG TERM LIMING
Object: To study the effects of different amounts of lime, phosphate and
sulphur on the yields and compositions of a sequence of crops -
Rothamsted (R) Sawyers I and Woburn (W) Stackyard C.
Sponsors: $.P. McGrath, P.B. Barraclough, G.F.J. Milford, J.M. Day.
The 32nd year, w. lupins.
For previous years see ‘Details’ 1967, 1973 and 74-92/R&W/CS/10.
Design: 2 randomised blocks of 16 plots split into 2 sub plots.
Whole plot dimensions: 5.8 x 16.1 (R}, 5.6 x 16.1 (W).
Treatments: All combinations of:-
Whole plots
1. CHALK Residual effects of ground chalk (tonnes CaC03)
(total applied 1962-87):
Rothamsted total Woburn total
R w 1962-78 1982-87 1962-78 1982-87
° Oo 9 0 0 0
15 9 ? 8 6 3
26.5 25.5 15 9.5 14 11.5
52.5 45.5 30 22.5 23 22.5
2. Residual effects of Pp fertilizer applied: ~
Until 1978 1981 1982 1983 1988
R&W R&W R&W R Ww R WwW
0 0 9 0 o oO o 0
Pl 0 Pl PL 0 p2 Pl Pl
P2 Pp Pl 0 P22 Pl Pl
P3 P P3 Pl P24 P33
Rates 1981-83 and 1988 P1, P2, P3, P4 = 25, 50, 75, 100 kg P as
superphosphate :
Sub plots
3. SULPHUR Sulphur (kg S, as calcium sulphate):
0
30
NOTES: (1) Until 1978 test P was applied cumulatively, rates varied with
crop, none in 1979 and 1980. K was also applied cumulatively,
to Pl and P3 plots. Since 1981 K has been applied basally
(none in 1986, 1987, 1989, 1990 and 1993).
(2) Test manganese was applied cumulatively, 1987-90.
53
93/R/CS/10 and 93/W/CS/10 5

Experimental diary:

Sawyers I (R):

29-Sep-92 : B : Ploughed.

07-Oct-92 : B : Rotary harrowed, CH 304/70, inoculated with rhizobium,
drilled at 100 kg.

13-Oct-92 : B : Opogard 500 FW at 2.8 1 in 200 1.

16-Apr-93 : T : SULPHUR 30: 30 kg S ae gypsum.

22-Jun-93 : B.: Power Dimethoate 40 at 1.7 1 in 200 1.

02-Jul-93 : B : Mistral at 1.0 1 in 200 1.

: B : Sportak 45 at 1.1 1 in 200 1.

06-Sep-93 : B : Stefes Diquat at 3.0 1 with Vassgro Spreader at 0.30 1
in 260 1.

10-Oct-93 : B : Combine harvested.

Stackyard C (W):

02-Oct-92 : B : Rotary harrowed, CH 304/70, inoculated with rhizobium,
drilled at 100 kg.

12-Oct-92 : B : Opogard 500 FW at 1.8 1 and Scythe at 3.0 1 in
200 1.

22-Mar-93 : B : Ploughed (crop failed).

08-Jul-93 ; B : Rotary cultivated.

NOTES: (1) At Rothamsted plant samples were taken in early June from
transects across plots for a detailed study of the relation
between soil pH gradient and plant growth. Harvested grain
samples were taken for sulphur analysis. -

(2) At Woburn the crop failed and no yields were taken.
{3) At Rothamsted, most CHALK 0 plots failed. They have been
omitted from the analysis.

93/R/CS/10 SAWYERS I (R) .

GRAIN TONNES /HECTARE

#ete* Tables of means *****

. P ° PL P2 P3 Mean
CHALK
15 2.34 2.24 1.95 1.75 2.07 :
24.5 1.82 1.13 1.67 1.46 1.52
52.5 1.25 1.49 1.26 1.32 1.33
Mean 1.80 . 1.62 1.63 1.51 1.64
SULPHUR 9 30 Mean
CHALK
is 1.90 2.23 2.07
24.5 1.44 1.60 1.52
52.5 1.19 1.47 1.33
Mean 1.51 1.77 1.64
S4
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1994</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[94/R/CS/10 and 94/W/CS/10
LONG TERM LIMING
Object: To study the effects of different amounts of lime, phosphate and
sulphur on the yields and compositions of a sequence of crops -
Rothamsted (R) Sawyers I and Woburn (W) Stackyard C.
Sponsors: S.P. McGrath, P.B. Barraclough, G.F.J. Milford, J.M. Day.
The 33rd year, w. lupins.
Por previous years see ‘Details’ 1967, 1973 and 74-93/R&W/CS/10.
Design: 2 randomised blocks of 16 plots split into 2 sub-plots.
Whole plot dimensions: 5.8 x 16.1 (R), 5-6 x 16.1 (W).
Treatments: All combinations of:-
Whole plots
1. CHALK Residual effects of ground chalk (tonnes Caco3)
(total applied 1962-87): -
Rothamsted total Woburn total
R Ww 1962-78 1982-87 1962-78 1982-87
0 0 0 ° 0 0
15 9 7 8 6 3
24.5 25.5 15 9.5 14 11.5
$2.5 45.5 30 22.5 23 22.5
22 Residual effects of P fertilizer applied:
Until 1978 1981 1982 1983 1988
REW R&W R&w R Ww R w
0 : 0 0 0 0 0 0 0
Pl -0 Pl Pl Oo P2 Pl Pl
P2 P Pl 0 P2 P2 Pl Pl
3 P P3 Pl P2 Pa P33
Rates 1981-83 and 1988 Pil, P2, P3, P4 = 25, 50, 75, 100 kg P as
superphosphate
Sub-plots
3. SULPHUR Sulphur (kg S, as calcium sulphate), applied
cumulatively since 1991:
§ .
30 Fo
: 52
94/R/C8/10 and 94/W/CS/10

NOTES: (1) Until 1978 test P was applied cumulatively, rates varied with
crop, none in 1979 and 1980. K was also applied cumulatively,
to Pl and P3 plots. Since 1981 K has been applied basally
(none in 1986, 1987, 1989, 1990, 1993 and 1994).

{2) Test manganese was applied cumulatively, 1987-90.
Experimental diary: a
Sawyers I (R):

16-Oct-93 : B : Ploughed.

19-Oct-93 : B : Disced.

20-Oct-93 : B : Spring-tine cultivated, CH304/70 drilled at 40 seeds
per m.

26-Oct-93 : B : Opogard 500 FW at 2.8 1 in 200 1.

16-Feb-94 : B : Atlas Simazine at 1.0 1 in 200 1.

13-Jun-94 : T : SULPHUR 30: 30 kg S as gypsum.

06-Sep-94 : B : Barclay Gallup at 4.0 1 in 200 1.

Stackyard C (W):

16-Sep-93 : B : Ploughed.

24-Sep-93 : B : Rotary harrowed, CH304/70 drilled at 40 seeds per m’.

18-Feb-94 : B : Atlas Simazine at 1.0 1 in 200 1.

10-Mar-94 : T : SULPHUR 30: 30 kg S as gypsum.

09-May-94 : B : Sportak 45 at 1.5 1 in 200 1.

NOTE: Due to poor winter survival at Rothamsted and to excessive grazing
damage at Woburn, both crops were abandoned in summer and no yields
were taken.

53
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1995</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[95/R/CS8/10 and 95/W/CS8/10
LONG TERM LIMING
Object: To study the effects of different amounts of lime, phosphate and
sulphur on the yields and compositions of a sequence of crops -
Rothamsted (R) Sawyers I and Woburn (W) Stackyard C.
Sponsor: S.P. McGrath.
The 34rd year, w. wheat.
For previous years see ‘Details’ 1967, 1973 and 74-94/R&W/CS/10.
Design: 2 randomised blocks of 16 plots split into 2 sub-plots.
Whole plot dimensions: 6.0 x 16.1 ({R), 6.0 x 16.1 (W).
Treatments: All combinations of:-
Whole plots
1. CHALK Residual effects of ground chalk (tonnes CaC03)
(total applied 1962-87):
Rothamsted total Woburn total
R Ww 1962-78 1982-87 1962-78 1982-87
0 0 0 0 0 0
15 9 7 8 6 3
24.5 25.5 15 9.5 14 11.5
52.5 45.5 30 22.5 23 22.5
2.9? Residual effects of P fertilizer applied:
Until 1978 1981 1982 1983 1988
R&wW R&W Réw R Ww R w
QO 0 0 0 o 06 o Oo
Pl 0 Pi Pl Oo P2 Pl Pl
P2 P Pl 0 P2 P2 Pl Pl
P3 P P3 Pl P2 Pé P3) «P3
Rates 1981-83 and 1988 Pl, P2, P3, P4 = 25, 50, 75, 100 kg P as
superphosphate
Sub-plots
3. SULPHUR Sulphur (kg S, as caicium sulphate), applied
cumulatively since 1991:
0
30
51
95/R/CS/10 and 95/w/CS/10
NOTES: (1) Until 1978 test P was applied cumulatively, rates varied with
crop, none in 1979 and 1980. K was also applied cumulatively,
to Pl and P3 plots. Since 1981 K has been applied basally
(none in 1986, 1987, 1989, 1990, 1993, 1994 and 1995).
(2} Test manganese was applied cumulatively, 1987-90.
Experimental diary:
Sawyers I (R):
06-Sep-S4 : B : Barclay Gallup at 4.0 1 in 200 1.
12-Sep-94 : B : Topped.
14-Sep-94 : B : Ploughed.
29-Sep-94 : B : Disced, heavy spring-tine cultivated.
30-Sep-94 : B : Rotary harrowed, Genesis, dressed Rappor, drilled at 380
seeds per m.
24-Nov-94 : B : Alpha Isoproturon 500 at 2.5 1 with Stomp 400 at 2.5 1
in 200 1.
13-Apr-95 : B : 34.5% N at 435 kg.
01-May-95 : T : SULPHUR 30: Gypsum {17.5% S) at 171 kg.
10-May~95 : B : Halo at 2.0 1 in 200 1.
16-Jun-95 : B : Halo at 2.0 1 with Patrol at 0.5 1 in 300 1.
02-Aug-95 : B : Combine harvested.
Stackyard C (W):
23-Sep-94 : B : Ploughed
30-Sep-94 : B : Rotary harrowed, Genesis, dressed Rappor, drilled at 300
seeds per m. Rolled.
28-Nov-94 : B : Panther at 2.0 1 with Decis at 0.20 1 in 200 1.
13-Mar-95 : T : SULPHUR 30: Gypsum (17.5% S) at 171 kg.
15-Mar-95 : B ;: 34.5% N at 116 kg.
21-Apr-95 : B : 34.5% N at 348 kg.
28-Apr-95 : B : Halo at 2.0 1 in 200 1.
01-Jun-95 : B : Cyclone at 1.0 1 with Mallard at 0.3 1 in 200 1.
30-Sun-95 : B : Pirimicarb 50 DG at 280 ¢ in 300 1.
04-Aug-95 : B : Combine harvested.
N.B. At Rothamsted, CHALK 0 plots failed, and have been omitted from the
analyses.
95/R/CS/10 SAWYERS I (R) ‘
GRAIN TONNES/HECTARE
***** Tables of means *****
P - Pi P2 P3 Mean
CHALK
15 $.397 6.84 4327 7.15 6.81
24.5 735 7.27 8.17 8.26 7.76
52.5 6.80 7.88 8.20 8.46 7.83
Mean 6.71 7.33 7.88 7.96 7.47
52
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1996</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[96/R/CS/10 and 96/W/CS/10
LONG TERM LIMING
Object: To study the effects of different amounts of lime, phosphate and
sulphur on the yields and compositions of a sequence of crops -
Rothamsted (R) Sawyers I and Woburn (W) Stackyard C.
Sponsor: S.P. McGrath.
The 35th year, w. wheat.
For previous years see ‘Details’ 1967, 1973 and 74-95/R&W/CS/10.
Design: 2 randomised blocks of 16 plots split into 2 sub-plots.
Whole plot dimensions: 6.0 x 16.1.
Treatments: All combinations of:-
Whole plots
1. CHALK Residual effects of ground chalk (tonnes CaCco3)
(total applied 1962-87):
Rothamsted total Woburn total
R w 1962-78 1982-87 1962-78 1982-87
0 0 0 0 0 0
15 9 7 8 6 3
24.5 25.5 15 9.5 14 11.5
52.5 45.5 30 22.5 23 22.5
2. P Residual effects of P fertilizer applied:
Until 1978 1981 1982 1983 1988
R&W R&W R&W R w R Ww
0 0 0 ° o oO o oO
Pl ° Pi Pl 0 P2 Pl Pl
P2 P Pl Qo P2 P2 Pl Pl
P3 P P3 Pl P2 Pa P3 P3
Rates 1981-83 and 1988 Pl, P2, P3, P4 = 25, 50, 75, 100 kg P as
superphosphate
Sub-plots
3. SULPHUR Sulphur (kg S, as calcium sulphate), applied
cumulatively since 1991:
0
30
52
96/R/CS/10 and 96/W/CS/10 .

NOTES: (1) Until 1978 test P was applied cumulatively, rates varied with
crop, none in 1979 and 1980. K was also applied cumulatively,
to Pl and P3 plots. Since 1981 K has been applied basally
(none in 1986, 1987, 1989, 1990 and 1993 to 1996).

(2) Test manganese was applied cumulatively, 1987-90. .

Experimental diary:

Sawyers I (R):

10-Aug-95 : B : Straw baled.

22-Aug-95 : B : Sub-soiled.

25-Sep-95 : B : Ploughed.

28-Sep-95 : B : Rotary harrowed, Hereward, dressed Panoctine, drilled
at 380 seeds per m*.

11-Mar-96 : B : 34.5% N at 116 kg.

09-Apr-96 : T : SULPHUR 30: Gypsum (17.5% S) at 171 kg.

15-Apr-96 : B : 34.5% N at 463 kg.

26-Apr-96 : B : Ally at 30 g with Cheetah Super at 1.25 1 and Barclay
Holdup at 2.3 1 in 200 1.

13-Jun-96 : B : Alto 100 SL at 0.6 1 with Mallard 750 Ec at 0.4 1 in
300 1. ¥

09-Aug-96 : B : Combine harvested.

Stackyard C (WwW):

25-Aug-95 : B : Sub-soiled.

19-Sep-95 : B : Ploughed.

23~Sep-95 : B : Rolled.

03-Oct-95 : B : Rotary harrowed, Hereward, dressed Sibutol, drilled at
375 seeds per m*.

13-Nov-95 : B : Panther at 2.0 1 in 200 1.

13-Mar-96 : B : 34.5% N at 116 kg.

19-Mar-96 : T : SULPHUR 30: Gypsum (17.5% S) at 171 kg.

16-Apr-96 : B : 34.5% N at 348 kg.

30-Apr-96 : B : Halo at 1.5 1 in 200 1.

06-Jun-96 : B : Silvacur at 1.0 1 in 300 1.

19-Aug-96 : 8 : Combine harvested.

NOTE: At Rothamsted, most CHALK 0 plots failed. They have been omitted

from the analysis.

96/R/CS/10 SAWYERS I (R)

GRAIN TONNES /HECTARE

**e** Tables of means *****
® 0 Pl P2 P3 Mean

CHALK
15 7.47 8.38 8.91 8.44 8.30
24.5 8.38 8.83 8.74 9.20 8.79
52.5 8.03 8.94 8.69 8.86 8.63
Mean 7.96 8.72 8.78 8.83 8.57
53
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
</reports>