<reports>
<report>
<year>1966</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##all plots: 
Ploughed: Oct 13, 1965. Spring-tine cultivated:
March 29, 1966, Ploughed: June 21, Spring-tine cultivated:
July 8, Aug 12,

##Ley: 
Half basal PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O: Oct 26, 1965, Remaining basal PK
applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O: Mar 22, 1966. 'Nitro-Chalk' applied at 0.4 cwtN/acre, seed sown 1 lb English Italian ryegrass, 2 lb Danish
Italian ryegrass, 1.5 lb English Broad Red
clover, 0.5 lb Canadian Alsike Clover,
Mixture sown at 29 lb: Mar 30. Cut twice for hay: July 4, Aug 26,

##Potatoes: 
Half basal PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O: Oct 26, 1965. Remaining basal
PK 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O, and 'Nitro-Chalk' applied at 1.2 cwtN/acre: Mar 23, 1966, Rotary cultivated,
potatoes machine planted Pentland Dell: Mar 29, Earthed up: June 8,
Sprayed with mancozeb 1.2 lb in 33 gals: June 29, July 15,
Aug 4, Haulm mechanically destroyed: Sept 3, Lifted: Sept 13.

##Wheat: 
Half basal PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O: Oct 26, 1965. Remaining basal
PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O: Oct 29. Seed drilled, Capelle 150 lb: Nov 2. 
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied as top-dressing at 0.5 cwtN/acre: Apr 12, 1965
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied as top-dressing at 1.0 cwtN/acre: Apr 12, 1965
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied as top-dressing at 1.5 cwtN/acre: Apr 12, 1965
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied as top-dressing at 2.0 cwtN/acre: Apr 12, 1965, 
Combine harvested: Aug 25.

##Barley: 
Half basal PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O: Oct 26, 1965. Remaining basal
PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O: Mar 7, 1966, Seed drilled - Maris Badger 140 lb, Mar 8
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 0.4 cwtN/acre: Apr 8
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 0.8 cwtN/acre: Apr 8
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 1.2 cwtN/acre: Apr 8
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 1.6 cwtN/acre: Mar 8, 
Combine harvested: Aug 18.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1967</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##Ley: 
Half PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O, ploughed: Sept 14, 1966.
Remaining PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O, seed sown at 29 lb: Sept 16,
'Nitro-Chalk' applied at 0.4 cwtN/acre: Mar 17, 1967. Cut three times for hay:
June 1, July 13, Sept 12,

##Potatoes: 
Half PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O, ploughed: Sept 14, 1966.
Remeining PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O, and 'Nitro-Chalk' applied at 1.2 cwtN/acre: Mar 17, 1967.
Potatoes planted Majestic: Mar 22, Earthed up: June 10.3 Sprayed with
mancozeb at 1.2 lb in 30 gals: July 1, July 26, Avg 8, Sprayed
with fentin acetate at 4,2 oz plus maned at 1.4 oz in 30 gals:
Aug 21, Sprayed with undiluted BOV at 15 gals: Sept 6, Lifted: Sept 12

##Wheat: 
Half PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O, ploughed: Sept 14, 1966.
Remaining PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O: Oct 21. Seed drilled Cappelle at 210 lb: Oct 26, 
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied as top-dressing at 0.5 cwtN/acre: Apr 14, 1967
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied as top-dressing at 1.0 cwtN/acre: Apr 14, 1967
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied as top-dressing at 1.5 cwtN/acre: Apr 14, 1967
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied as top-dressing at 2.0 cwtN/acre: Apr 14, 1967. Sprayed with
Ioxynil/mecoprop (Actril C at 6 pints in 25 gals): Apr 27.
Combine harvested: Aug 22

##Barley: 
Half PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O, ploughed: Sept 14, 1966.
Remeining PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O, seed drilled Maris Badger at 140 lb: Mar 4, 1967.
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 0.4 cwtN/acre: Mar 17
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 0.8 cwtN/acre: Mar 17
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 1.2 cwtN/acre: Mar 17
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 1.6 cwtN/acre: Mar 17. Sprayed with ioxynil/mecoprop
(Actril C at 6 pints in 25 gals): Apr 27. Combine harvested: Aug 18
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1968</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##Ley: 
Half PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O: 14 Sept, 1967. Ploughed: 15 - 16 Sept.
Test Mg as Epsom Salts at 162 lb/acre and remaining PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O, seeds sown at 29 lb: 20 Sept,
'Nitro-Chalk' applied at 0.4 cwtN/acre applied: 27 Mar, 1968, Cut: 5 June, 6 Aug,

##Potatoes: 
Half PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O: 14 Sept, 1967. Ploughed: 15 - 16 Sept.
Sprayed with paraquat at 0.5 lb in 33 gals on the permanent
barley blocks: 2 Mar, Remaining PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O, 'Nitro-Chalk', 
Test Mg as Epsom Salts at 162 lb/acre applied: 26 Mar, Rotary cultivated, potatoes planted: 27 Mar.
Earthed up: 22 May, Grubbed, rotary ridged: 13 June, Sprayed
with mencozeb et 1.2 lb plus demeton-s-methyl at 3.5 oz in 38
gals on the permenent wheat blocks only: 12 July. Sprayed with
mancozeb at 1.2 lb in 38 gals: 18 July, 30 July, Sprayed with
undiluted BOV at 15 gals: 4 Sept. Lifted: 24 Sept.

##Wheat: 
Half PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O: 14 Sept, 1967. Ploughed: 15 - 16 Sept.
Remaining PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O and Test Mg as Epsom Salts at 162 lb/acre applied, seed drilled at 170 lb:
13 Oct, 1967, 
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied as top-dressing at 0.5 cwtN/acre: 9 Apr
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied as top-dressing at 1.0 cwtN/acre: 9 Apr
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied as top-dressing at 1.5 cwtN/acre: 9 Apr
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied as top-dressing at 2.0 cwtN/acre: 9 Apr, 1968, Sprayed with
ioxynil/mecoprop (Actril C at 6 pints in 25 gals): 25 Apr.
Combine harvested: 22 Aug,

##Barley: 
Half PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O: 14 Sept, 1967. Ploughed: 15 - 16 Sept.
Sprayed with paraquat at 0.5 lb in 33 gels: 2 Mar,
Remaining PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O: 4 Mar, Seed drilled at 140 lb: 6 Mar,
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 0.4 cwtN/acre: 15 Mar
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 0.8 cwtN/acre: 15 Mar
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 1.2 cwtN/acre: 15 Mar
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 1.6 cwtN/acre: 15 Mar, Sprayed with ioxynil/mecoprop
(Actril C at 5 pints in 25 gals): 26 Apr, Combine harvested: 20 Aug.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1969</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##Ley: 
Half PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O: 1 Oct, 1968, Ploughed: 4 Oct.
Remaining PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O and Test Mg as Epsom Salts at 162 lb/acre applied: 7 Oct.
Seeds sown at 29 lb: 14 Oct. 'Nitro-Chalk' applied at 0.4 cwtN/acre:
27 Mar, 1969, Cut: 28 June, 3 Sept.

##Potatoes: 
Half PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O: 1 Oct, 1968, Ploughed: 4 Oct.
Remaining PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O and Test Mg as Epsom Salts at 162 lb/acre applied: 7 Oct.
'Nitro-Chalk' applied at 1.2 cwtN/acre: 17 Apr. Rotary cultivated,
potatoes planted: 18 Apr. Paraquat at 0.37
lb ion plus linuron at 0.5 lb in 25 gals: 15 May.
Rotary ridged: 17 June, Mancozeb at 1.2 lb and Demeton-s-methyl at 3.5 oz in 37 gals: 18 July. 
Mancozeb at 1.2 lb in 37 gals: 7 Aug, 27 Aug. Haulm mechenically
destroyed: 16 Sept, Lifted: 23 Sept.

##Wheat: 
Half PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O: 1 Oct, 1968, Ploughed: 4 Oct.
Remaining PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O and Test Mg as Epsom Salts at 162 lb/acre applied: 7 Oct.
Seed drilled at 175 lb: 17 Oct, 1968, 
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied as top-dressing at 0.5 cwtN/acre: 15 Apr, 1969
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied as top-dressing at 1.0 cwtN/acre: 15 Apr, 1969
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied as top-dressing at 1.5 cwtN/acre: 15 Apr, 1969
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied as top-dressing at 2.0 cwtN/acre: 15 Apr, 1969. 
Ioxynil at 9 oz plus mecoprop at 27 oz in 25 gals: 2 May, Combine harvested: 29 Aug.

##Barley: 
Half PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O: 1 Oct, 1968, Ploughed: 4 Oct.
Remaining PK applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O and Test Mg as Epsom Salts at 162 lb/acre applied: 7 Oct.
Seed drilled at 140 lb: 11 Mar resown 16 Apr, 
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 0.4 cwtN/acre: 3 Apr
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 0.8 cwtN/acre: 3 Apr
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 1.2 cwtN/acre: 3 Apr
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 1.6 cwtN/acre: 3 Apr. 
Ioxynil octancate, bromoxynil octencate
and iso-octyl ester of dichlorprop ('Oxytril P' at 1 pt in
25 gals): 22 May. Combine harvested: 29 Aug.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1970</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##All plots: 
All test Mg as Epsom Salts to Barley blocks at 990 lb/acre: 25 Sept, 1969
Half test Mg as Epsom Salts to Wheat blocks at 990 lb/acre: 25 Sept, 1969
half PK(0:14:28) applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O: 25 Sept, 1969. Ploughed:
26 Sept. Remaining PK(0:14:28) applied 0.5 cwt P2O5, 1.0 cwt K2O: 29 Sept,

##Ley: 
Paraquat at 0.5 lb ion in 37 gals: 10 Sept, 1969, Ryegrass Seed sown at 28 lb:
30 Sept, N applied as Nitro-Chalk at 1.0 cwtN/acre: 16 Mar, 1970.3 16 June, 24 July. Cut: 11 June, 
Topped (no yields taken) 23 July, 3 Sept,
N applied as Nitro-Chalk at 0.75 cwtN/acre 11 June, 23 July

##Potatoes: 
Remaining Mg applied on wheat block at 990 lb/acre: 30 Sept, 1969, N
applied as Nitro-Chalk at 1.2 cwtN/acre: 17 Apr, 1970. Rotary cultivated, potatoes planted:
22 Apr. Linuron at 1.0 lb Plus paraquat at 0.37 lb ion in 33 gals: 13 May, Grubbed, rotary ridged: 6 June, 
Mancozeb at 1.2 lb and Demeton-s-methyl at 3.5 fl oz in 37 gals: 31 July. Mancozeb at
1.2 lb in 37 gals: 18 Aug, Sprayed with undiluted BOV at 20 gals:
7 Sept. Lifted: 15 Sept,

##Wheat: 
Paraquat at 0.5 lb ion in 37 gals: 10 Sept, 1960.3 Remaining Mg applied on wheat block at 990 lb/acre:
30 Sept. Rotary cultivated, seed drilled at 170 lb: 23 Oct.
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied as top-dressing at 0.5 cwtN/acre: 24 Apr, 1970
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied as top-dressing at 1.0 cwtN/acre: 24 Apr, 1970
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied as top-dressing at 1.5 cwtN/acre: 24 Apr, 1970
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied as top-dressing at 2.0 cwtN/acre: 24 Apr, 1970.3 
Ioxynil at 9 oz plus mecoprop at 27 oz in 25 gals: 7 May. Combine harvested: 14 Aug,

##Barley: 
Paraquat at 0.5 lb ion in 37 gals: 10 Sept, 1969. Power Harrowed, seed
drilled Julia at 135 lb: 25 Mar, 1970. 
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 0.4 cwtN/acre: 31 Mar
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 0.8 cwtN/acre: 31 Mar
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 1.2 cwtN/acre: 31 Mar
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 1.6 cwtN/acre: 31 Mar, Ioxynil at
6.5 oz plus mecoprop et 22.5 oz in 25 gals: 18 May, 
Combine harvested: 11 Aug
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1971</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##All plots: 
Paraquat applied: 16 Sept, 1970. Half
PK (0:14:28) applied - 63 kgP2O5, 126 kgK2O: 24 Sept
magnesian limestone applied at 3765 kg/ha ploughed in: 6 Oct. 
Ploughed: 10 Oct. 
Remaining PK (0:14:28) applied - 63 kgP2O5, 126 kgK2O
Remaining magnesian limestone at 1255 kg/ha applied to plough furrow
applied: 14 Oct.

##Leys: 
Deep-tine cultivated barley blocks: 21 Oct, 1970.3 N applied at 63 kgN/ha:
1 Apr. Seeds sown Italian Ryegrass S22 at 33 kg: 2 Apr. N applied at 63 kgN/ha: 2 June 
First cut: 16 July.
N applied at 75 kgN/ha: 19 July, Second cut: 8 Sept

##Potatoes: 
Deep-tine cultivated barley blocks: 21 Oct, 1970. 
N  as 'Nitro-chalk 21' applied at 150 kgN/ha: 29 Mar, 1971. 
Rotary cultivated, potatoes planted Majestic:
30 Mar, Linuron at 1.12 kg in 371 l: 5 May. Rotary ridged: 1 June,
Mancozeb at 1.34 kg and Demeton-s-methyl at 246 ml in 416 l: 28 June, Mancozeb at 1.34 kg in 371 l: 12 Aug, 
Haulm mechanically destroyed: 13 Sept. Lifted: 14 Sept

##Wheat: 
Seed drilled Capelle at 191 kg: 14 Oct, 1970.
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 63 kgN/ha: 14 Apr, 1971,
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 126 kgN/ha: 14 Apr, 1971,
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 189 kgN/ha: 14 Apr, 1971,
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 252 kgN/ha: 14 Apr, 1971, 
Ioxynil at 0.53 Kg and mecoprop at 1.58 kg in 281 l: 28 Apr. 
Combine harvested: 28 Aug.

##Barley: 
Deep-tine cultivated: 21 Oct, 1970. 
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 63 kgN/ha: 17 Mar, 1971,
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 126 kgN/ha: 17 Mar, 1971,
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 189 kgN/ha: 17 Mar, 1971,
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 252 kgN/ha: 17 Mar, 1971
seed drilled Julia at 157 kg: 17 Mar, 1971. 
Power harrowed, re-drilled at 157 kg: 9 Apr, 
Ioxynil at 0.53 Kg and mecoprop at 1.58 kg in 281 l: 18 May, Combine harvested: 25 Aug.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1972</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##All plots: 
Half PK (0:14:28) applied - 65 kgP2O5, 130 kgK2O, ploughed: 1 Oct, 1971.
Remaining (0:14:28) applied - 65 kgP2O5, 130 kgK2O applied: 7 Oct.

##Leys: 
Paraquat at 0.56 ion kg in 280 l: 9 Sept, 1971. Deep-tine cultivated, wheat
block only: 4 Nov, N applied at 63 kgN/ha to seedbed as Nitro-Chalk: 18 Apr, 1972. Rotary cultivated:
21 Apr. Seed sown Italian Ryegrass S22 at 28kg: 26 Apr, N applied at 63 kgN/ha as Nitro-Chalk: 6 June, Cut once:
6 Sept,

##Potatoes: 
Deep-tine cultiveted, wheat block only: 4 Nov, 1971.
N applied at 150 kgN/ha as Nitro-Chalk: 4 Apr; 1972, 
Rotery cultivated, potatoes planted Majestic: 18 Apr, 
Linuron at 1.1 kg with paraquat at 0.4 kg ion in 370 l: 6 May, 
Rotary ridged: 19 June, Mancozeb at 1.3 kg in 430 l: 5 July, 
Mancozeb at 1.3 kg with demeton-s-metiyl at 0.25 kg in 430 l: 27 July, Haulm mechanically destroyed: 14 Sept,
Lifted: 20 Sept.

##Wheat: 
Paraquat at 0.56 ion kg in 280 l: 9 Sept, 1971. Seed drilled Cappelle, at 180 kg: 15 Oct, 
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 63 kgN/ha: 11 Apr, 1972,
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 126 kgN/ha: 11 Apr, 1972,
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 189 kgN/ha: 11 Apr, 1972,
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 252 kgN/ha: 11 Apr, 1972. 
2,4-D at 0.7 kg with dichlorprop at 2.8 kg in 280 l: 27 Apr.
Combine harvested: 30 Aug.

##Barley: 
Paraquat at 0.56 ion kg in 280 l: 9 Sept, 1971. Seed drilled Julie (dressed with ethirimol) sown at 180 kg: 15 Mar, 1972.
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 50 kgN/ha: 16 Mar,
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 100 kgN/ha: 16 Mar,
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 150 kgN/ha: 16 Mar,
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 200 kgN/ha: 16 Mar, 
2,4-D at 0.56 kg with dichlorprop at 2.2 kg in 280 l: 8 May,
Combine harvested: 24 Aug,
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1973</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##All plots: 
Half PK (0:14:28) applied - 65 kgP2O5, 130 kgK2O: 4 Oct, 1972.
Ploughed: 10 Oct, Remaining PK (0:14:28) applied - 65 kgP2O5, 130 kgK2O: 17 Oct.

##ley: 
Paraquat at 0.56 kg ion in 280 l: 6 Sept, 1972. Power harrowed, wheat
site only: 18 Oct, 'Nitro-Chalk' at 60 kg N in seedbed: 16 Mar, 1973. Seeds sown Italian ryegrass S22, sown at 40 kg:
20 Mar, N applied at 60 kgN as Nitro-Chalk: 18 May, 3 July, Cut twice: 2 July, 28 Aug.

##Potatoes: 
Power harrowed, wheat site only: 18 Oct, 1972. N
applied at 150 kgN/ha: 23 Mar, 1973. Rotary cultivated: 6 Apr. Potatoes
planted Majestic: 7 Apr. Linuron at 1.2
kg plus paraquat at 0.42 kg ion in 280 l: 14 May,
Grubbed: 1 June, Rotary ridged: 16 June, Mancozeb at 1.3 kg plus demeton-s-methyl at 0.25 kg in 390 l: 5 July. 
Mancozeb at 1.3 kg in 390 l: 26 July, 
Mancozeb at 1.3 kg in 370 l: 13 Aug. Haulm
mechanically destroyed: 19 Sept, Sprayed with undiluted BOV at
220 l: 24 Sept, Lifted: 4 Oct,

##Wheat: 
Paraquat at 0.56 kg ion in 280 l: 6 Sept, 1972. Power harrowed: 18 Oct.
Seed sown Capelle at 200 kg: 20 Oct. 
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 63 kgN/ha: 12 Apr, 1973,
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 126 kgN/ha: 12 Apr, 1973,
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 189 kgN/ha: 12 Apr, 1973,
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 252 kgN/ha: 12 Apr, 1973. 
Ioxynil at 0.63 kg with mecoprop at 1.9 kg in 200 l: 26 Apr. Combine harvested: 22 Aug,

##Barley: 
Paraquat at 0.56 kg ion in 280 l: 6 Sept, 1972. Seed sown Julie, dressed with ethirimol, sown at 160 kg: 12 Mar, 1973.
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 50 kgN/ha: 16 Mar,
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 100 kgN/ha: 16 Mar,
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 150 kgN/ha: 16 Mar,
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied in the seedbed at 200 kgN/ha: 16 Mar, 
Ioxynil at 0.53 kg with mecoprop at 1.6 kg in 280 l: 11 May. Combine
harvested: 13 Aug.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1974</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##All plots: 
Paraquat at 0.56 kg ion in 370 l: 12 Sept, 1973. Magnesian limestone applied at
3.5 tonnes: 5 Oct. Half PK applied P205 at 65 kg, K20 at 130 kg as (0:14:28): 10 Oct. Ploughed: 11 Oct,
Remaining PK applied P205 at 65 kg, K20 at 130 kg as (0:14:28) to the plough furrow: 12 Oct. 
Spring-tine cultivateds 13 Oct.

##Leys: 
Spring-tine cultivated: 30 Mar, 1974. Power harrowed, N applied at 60 kg, as Nitro-Chalk,
seeds sown Italian ryegrass sown at 40 kg: 5 Apr. N applied at 60 kg, as Nitro-Chalk: 31 May, 2 July, 19 Aug. 
Cut: 1 July, 15 Aug, 24 Sept

##Potatoes: 
Spring-tine cultivated: 30 Mar, 1974. N applied  at 150 kg as Nitro-Chalk, rotary
cultivated: 9 Apr. Potatoes planted Pentland Crown: 10 Apr. Linuron at 1.2 kg plus paraquat at 0.28 kg ion in 280 l:
15 May. Rotary ridged: 11 June, Mancozeb at 1.3 kg plus demeton-s-methyl at 0.25 kg in 450 l:
18 July. Mancozeb at 1.3 kg in 450 l: 7 Aug. Haulm mechanically destroyed:
12 Sept. Sprayed with undiluted BOV at 170 l: 18 Sept. Lifted: 30 sept.

##Wheat: 
Seed sown Cappelle, sown at 190 kg: 15 Oct, 1973. Ioxynil at 0.63 kg with mecoprop at 1.9 kg in 280 l: 5 Apr, 197h.
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied at 63 kgN/ha: 9 Apr 1974,
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied at 126 kgN/ha: 9 Apr,
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied at 189 kgN/ha: 9 Apr,
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied at 252 kgN/ha: 9 Apr. 
ioxynil at 0.52 kg with mecoprop at 1.6 kg in 280 l: 14 May.
Combine harvested: 30 Aug.

##Barley: 
Spring-tine cultivated: 27 Mar, 1974. Spring-tine cultivated
with crumbler: 28 Mar. Seed sown Julia, dressed with ethirimol, sown at 160 kg: 29 Mar, 
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied at 50 kgN/ha: 1 Apr,
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied at 100 kgN/ha: 1 Apr,
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied at 150 kgN/ha: 1 Apr,
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied at 200 kgN/ha: 1 Apr.
Ioxynil at 0.52 kg and mecoprop at 1.6 kg in 280 l: 14 May, Combine harvested: 22 Aug.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1975</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##All plots: 
Half PK applied P205 at 65 kg, K20 at 130 kg as (0:14:28), ploughed: 30 Oct, 1974.
Remaining PK applied P205 at 65 kg, K20 at 130 kg as (0:14:28): 8 Nov, Spring-tine cultiveted: 27 Nov.

##Leys: 
Aminotriazole applied at 4.5 kg in 260 l: 11 Sep, 1974. Spring-tine cultivated four
times with crumbler on the second and forth occasions: 26 Feb, 3 Mar,
24 Apr, 28 Apr, 1975. 
N applied at 60 kgN, as 'Nitro-Chalk': 18 Apr, 11 June, 
Seed sown Italian Ryegrass at 40 kg: 2 May.
Topped: 8 July, 21 Aug,

##Potatoes: 
Spring-tine cultivated three times on the second occasion with
crupbler: 26 Feb, 3 Mar, 24 Apr, 1975. N applied at 150 kgN, as 'Nitro-Chalk': 
18 Apr. Deep-tine cultivated: 25 Apr. Rotary cultivated, potetoes planted Pentland Crown: 5 May.
Liruron at 1.2 kg plus paraquat at 0.28 kg ion in 280 l: 22 May, Grubbed: 23 June. Rotary
ridged: 24 June, Demeton-s-methyl at 0.25 kg in 286 l: 25 June, Mancozeb at 1.3 kg in 390 l:
15 July.  Haulm mechanicelly destroyed: 26 Sept. Sprayed with undiluted
B.0.V. at 160 l: 2 Oct. Litted: 6 Oct.

##Wheat: 
Seed sown Cappelle at 200 kg: 27 nov, 1974. 
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied at 63 kgN/ha: 24 Mar, 1975. 
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied at 126 kgN/ha: 24 Mar, 1975. 
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied at 252 kgN/ha: 24 Mar, 1975. 
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied at 189 kgN/ha: 24 Mar, 1975. 
Aminotriazole at 4.5 kg in 280 1, Ioxynil at 0.63 kg with meccprop at 1.9 kg in 280 l: 8 May. Combine barvested: 12 mug.

##Barley: 
Spring-tine dtivated twice, second time with crumbler: 26 Feb,
3 Mar, 1675. Seed sown Julia dressed Ethirimol sown at 160 kg: 4 Mar. 
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied at 50 kgN/ha: 10 Mar
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied at 100 kgN/ha: 10 Mar
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied at 150 kgN/ha: 10 Mar
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied at 200 kgN/ha: 10 Mar. 
Spring-tine cultivated with crunbler three times, seed resown: 1 May, 
Aminotriazole at 4.5 kg in 280 1. Ioxynil at 0.52 kg with mecoprop at 1.6 kg in 280 l: 4 June. Combine harvested: 18 Aug.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1976</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##All plots: 
Half PK applied P205 at 65 kg, K20 at 130 kg as (0:14:28), ploughed: 24 Oct, 1975.
Remaining PK applied P205 at 65 kg, K20 at 130 kg as (0:14:28): 27 Oct.

##Leys: 
Glyphosate at 1.7 kg in 340 l applied to wheat stubble only: 5 Oct, 1975. Spring-tine
cultivated wheat blocks only: 27 Oct. Deep-tine cultivated barley
blocks only: 29 Dec. Spring-tine cultivated barley blocks: 2 Mar,
1976, Spring-tine cultivated  wheat blocks: 9 Mar. N applied at 60 kg as Nitro-Chalk: 20 Apr. Seed sown Italian ryegrass, sown at 40 kg: 27 Apr.
N applied at 60 kg as Nitro-Chalk: 9 June. Cut once: 20 Oct.

##Potatoes: 
Rotary cultivated: 14 Oct, 1975. Spring-tine cultivated barley
blocks: 2 Mar, 1976, wheat blocks: 9 Mar. N applied at 150 kgN as Nitro-Chalk: 30 Mar.
Rotary cultivated, potatoes planted Pentland Crown: 6 Apr. Linuron at 1.2 kg plus paraquat at 0.42 kg ion in 280 l:
7 May. Rotary ridged: 3 June. 
Pirimicarb at 0.14 kg in 450 l: 18 June. 
Mancozeb at 1.3 kg with demeton-s-methyl at 0.25 kg in 450 l: 30 June. 
Mancozeb at 1.3 kg in 450 l: 30 July.
Haulm mechanically destroyed: 15 Sept. Haulm desiccant applied Diquat at 0.59 kg ion in 280 l: 6 Oct. 
Lifted: 19 Oct.

##Wheat: 
Glyphosate at 1.7 kg in 340 l: 5 Oct, 1975. Spring-tine cultivated, seed
sown Cappelle sown at 210 kg: 27 Oct. 
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied at 63 kgN/ha: 1 Apr, 1976. 
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied at 126 kgN/ha: 1 Apr, 1976. 
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied at 252 kgN/ha: 1 Apr, 1976. 
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied at 189 kgN/ha: 1 Apr, 1976. 
Ioxynil at 0.63 kg plus mecoprop at 1.9 kg in 280 l: 20 Apr.
Combine harvested: 2 Aug.

##Barley: 
Deep-tine cultivated: 29 Dec, 1975. Spring-tine cultivated:
2 Mar, 1976. Seed sown Julia, dressed with ethirimol, sown at 160 kg: 8 Mar. 
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied at 50 kgN/ha: 9 Mar
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied at 100 kgN/ha: 9 Mar
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied at 150 kgN/ha: 9 Mar
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied at 200 kgN/ha: 9 Mar. 
loxynil at 0.52 kg and mecoprop at 1.6 kg in 280 l: 28 Apr. Combine harvested: 26 July.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1977</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##All plots: 
Glyphosate at 1.7 kg in 280 l: 24 Sept, 1976. Rotary cultivated
grass leys: 1 Nov. Ploughed: 8 Nov.

##Wheat: 
test Aldicarb applied at 10 kg/ha, rotary cultivated, seed sown Cappelle, sown at 210 kg PK (0:20:20) at 290 kg, combine drilled: 24 Nov, 1976. 
methabenzthiazuron at 1.6 kg in 280 l: 25 Nov. 
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied at 63 kgN/ha: 12 Apr, 1977
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied at 126 kgN/ha: 12 Apr, 1977 
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied at 252 kgN/ha: 12 Apr, 1977 
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied at 189 kgN/ha: 12 Apr, 1977. 
Ioxynil at 0.53 kg plus mecoprop at 1.6 kg in 220 l: 15 May. Pirimicarb at 0.14 kg in 270 l: 11 July. Combine harvested: 7 Sept.

##Barley: 
Spring-tine cultivated: 7 Mar, 1977. test Aldicarb applied at 10 kg/ha, rotary cultivated,
seed sown Julia, dressed with ethirimol, sown at 160 kg. PK (0:20:20) at 300 kg, combine drilled: 8 Apr. 
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied at 50 kgN/ha: 13 Apr
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied at 100 kgN/ha: 13 Apr
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied at 150 kgN/ha: 13 Apr
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied at 200 kgN/ha: 13 Apr. 
Ioxynil at 0.53 kg plus mecoprop at 1.6 kg in 220 l: 19 May.
combine harvested on 16 Aug:
Remaining treatments combine harvested: 30 Aug.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1978</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##wheat: 
ploughed: 27 Sept, 1977.
test Aldicarb applied at 10 kg/ha, rotary cultivated: 24 Oct, 1977. Spring-tine
cultivated, seed sown Cappelle, sown at 210 kg. PK (0:20:20) at 310 kg, combine drilled: 25 Oct. 
Methabenzthiazuron at 1.5 kg in 280 l: 29 Oct.
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied at 63 kgN/ha: 7 Apr, 1978
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied at 126 kgN/ha: 7 Apr, 1978 
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied at 252 kgN/ha: 7 Apr, 1978 
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied at 189 kgN/ha: 7 Apr, 1978. 
Mecoprop, bromoxynil and Ioxynil ('Brittox' at 3.5 l in 280 l) 10 May. Combine harvested: 25 Aug.

##Barley: 
ploughed: 27 Sept, 1977.
Spring-tine cultivated: 9 Mar, 1978. test Aldicarb applied at 10 kg/ha, rotary
cultivated, spring-tine cultivated with crumbler attached, seed sown Porthos, dressed with ethirimol, sown at 160 kg. PK (0:20:20) at 300 kg, combine drilled: 3 Apr. 
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied at 50 kgN/ha: 15 May
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied at 100 kgN/ha: 15 May
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied at 150 kgN/ha: 15 May
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied at 200 kgN/ha: 15 May
Mecoprop, bromoxynil and ioxynil as 'Brittox' at 2.5 1 and Tridemorph at 0.52 kg in 280 l: 15 May. Combine
harvested: 23 Aug.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1979</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##All plots: 
Ploughed: 30 Aug, 1978. Spring-tine cultivated, with crumbler
attached: 31 Aug. test Dazomet applied 336 kg/ha and all plots rotary cultivated: 7 Sept.

##Wheat: 
Rotary cultivated: 11 Oct, 1978. Seed sown Flanders, sown at 180 kg, PK (0:20:20) at 310 kg, combine drilled: 13 Oct. 
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied at 63 kgN/ha: 18 Oct
Methabenzthiazuron at 1.5 kg in 220 l: 18 Oct. 
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied at 63 kgN/ha: 10 Apr, 1979
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied at 126 kgN/ha: 10 Apr, 1979
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied at 189 kgN/ha: 10 Apr, 1979 
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied at 189 kgN/ha: 10 Apr, 1979.
Combine harvested: 30 Aug.

##Barley: 
Heavy spring-tine cultivated: 16 Oct, 1978. Spring-tine cultivated,
with crumbler attached, twice: 16 Apr, 1979, 20 Apr. Seed sown Porthos, dressed with ethirimol, sown at 160 kg PK (0:20:20) at 300 kg, combine drilled: 23 Apr. 
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied at 50 kgN/ha: 30 Apr
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied at 100 kgN/ha: 30 Apr
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied at 150 kgN/ha: 30 Apr
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied at 200 kgN/ha: 30 Apr. 
Bromoxynil with ioxynil ('Oxytril CM' at 2.1 kg in 250 l): 5 June. Combine harvested: 28 Aug.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1980</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##All plots: 
Ploughed: 24 Sept, 1979. test Dazomet applied 336 kg/ha and all plots rotary
cultivated: 25 Sept.

##W. wheat: 
Glyphosate at 1.7 kg in 250 l: 13 Sept, 1979. Spring-tine cultivated with crumbler attached: 24 Oct. 
Seed sown, Flanders, sown at 190 kg, (0:20:20) at 310 kg, combine drilled: 13 Nov. 
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied at 63 kgN/ha: 19 Nov. 
Isoproturon at 2.1 l in 280 l: 12 Apr, 1980. 
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied at 63 kgN/ha: 15 Apr
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied at 126 kgN/ha: 15 Apr
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied at 189 kgN/ha: 15 Apr 
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied at 189 kgN/ha: 15 Apr
Mecoprop, bromoxynil and Ioxynil ('Brittox' at 3.5 l in 280 l): 15 Apr. 
Demeton-s-methyl at 0.21 kg in 300 l: 5 July. 
Combine harvested: 26 Aug.

##S. barley: 
Heavy spring-tine cultivated: 3 Mar, 1980.3 24 Mar, 9 Apr.
Rotary cultivated, seed sown Georgie, dressed with ethirimol, sown at 160 kg, (0:20:20) at 300 kg, combine drilled: 10 Apr. 
N1 Nitro-Chalk applied at 50 kgN/ha: 15 Apr
N2 Nitro-Chalk applied at 100 kgN/ha: 15 Apr
N3 Nitro-Chalk applied at 150 kgN/ha: 15 Apr
N4 Nitro-Chalk applied at 200 kgN/ha: 15 Apr. 
'Brittox' at 3.5l in 280 1 and Tridemorph at 0.53 kg in 280 l: 16 May. 
Ethirimol ('Milgo E' at 1.3 l in 280 l): 5 June. Combine harvested: 22 Aug.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1981</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##W. wheat: 
Glyphosate at 1.5 l in 280 l: 9 Sept, 1980. Chalk at 7.5 t applied: 11 Sept.
Ploughed: 16 Sept. Spring-tine cultivated: 25 Sept. Spring-tine
cultivated with crumbler attached, rotary cultivated after barley
only: 30 Sept. Seed sown Flanders, sown at 190 kg, NPK (10:23:23) at 280 kg: 1 Oct. 
Chlortoluron at 4.5 l in 300 l: 3 Oct. N applied at 150 kg as 'Nitro-Chalk': 10 Apr, 1981. 
Mecoprop with bromoxynil and ioxynil (as 'Brittox' at 2.4 l) in 280 l: 22 Apr. 
Triadimefon with captafol (as ‘'Bayleton CF' at 2.0 kg) in 280 l: 20 June. 
Combine harvested: 19 Aug.

##1st year ley: 
Glyphosate at 1.5 l in 280 l: 9 Sept, 1980. Chalk at 7.5 t applied: 11 Sept.
Ploughed: 16 Sept. Spring-tine cultivated, NPK applied (10:23:23) at 300 kg: 25 Sept.
Seeds sown S23 perennial ryegrass at 31 kg, Blanca white clover at 8 kg, mixture sown at 39 kg.: 26 Sept. 
N applied at 65 kg as 'Nitro-Chalk': 7 May, 1981. Cut: 11 June, 8 Sept.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1982</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##W. wheat: 
Glyphosate at 1.5 kg in 280 l: 16 Sept, 1981. Ploughed: 25 Sept. 
NPK  applied (10:23:23) at 280 kg: 29 Sept. Spring-tine cultivated with crumbler attached:
7 Oct. Seed sown Avalon, sown at 190 kg: 3 Oct. 
chlortoluron at 3.5 kg in 280 l: 15 Oct. N applied at 150 kg as 'Nitro-Chalk':
14 Apr, 1982. Combine harvested: 3 Aug.

##1st year ley: 
Glyphosate at 1.5 kg in 280 l: 16 Sept, 1981. Ploughed: 25 Sept.
NPK applied (10:23:23) at 280 kg: 29 Sept. Spring-tine cultivated with crumbler
attached: 7 Oct, 15 Apr, 1982, 19 Apr. 
Seeds sown S23 perennial ryegrass at 31 kg, Blanca white clover at 8 kg, mixture sown at 39 kg: 29 Apr. 
Topped: 16 June, N applied at 40 kg as 'Nitro-Chalk': 23 June. Cut: 13 July.

##2nd year ley: 
PK applied (0:14:28) at 490 kg: 8 Feb, 1982. Cut: 13 July.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1983</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##W. wheat: 
Ploughed: 20 Sept, 1982, Spring-tine cultivated: 28 Sept.
NPK applied (5:14:30) at 340 kg: 30 Sept. Rotary cultivated, seed sown Avalon, sown at 190 kg: 1 Oct.
Prochloraz at 0.4 kg and Mecoprop with bromoxynil and foxynil (as 'Brittox' at 3.5 l): 15 Apr, 1983. 
N applied at 150 kg as 'Nitro-Chalk': 28 Apr.
Combine harvested: 5 Aug.

##Ley, 1st year: 
Ploughed: 20 Sept, 1982. Spring-tine cultivated: 28 Sept. 
NPK applied (5:14:30) at 340 kg: 30 Sept. Spring-tine cultivated: 8 Mar, 1983.
N applied at 50 kg as 'Nitro-Chalk', rotary cultivated: 17 Mar. Paraquat at 0.84 kg ion in 280 l: 16 May.
Rotary cultivated: 7 June. 
Seed sown S23 perennial ryegrass at 27 kg, Blanca white clover at 7 kg, mixture sown at 34 kg: 9 June. Cut: 15 Aug.

##Ley, 2nd and 3rd years: 
PK applied (0:18:36) at 380 kg: 11 Jan, 1983. Cut: 21 June, 15 Aug.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1984</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##w wheat:
ploughed: 13 Sept 1983
NPK applied (5:14:30) at 340 kg: 28 Sept
rotary cultivated, seed sown Avalon, sown at 200 kg: 28 Sept
Chlortoluron at 3.5 kg in 250 l: 29 Sept
N applied at 140 kg as 'Nitro-Chalk': 4 Apr 1984
combine harvested 21 Aug

##ley 1st year
ploughed: 13 Sept 1983
NPK applied (5:14:30) at 340 kg, rotary cultivated: 28 Sept
seeds sown S23 perennial ryegrass at 27 kg, Blanca white clover at 7 kg, mixture sown at 34 kg: 29 Sept
N applied at 50 kg as ‘Nitro-Chalk': 27 Mar 1984
cut: 17 June, 11 Sept

##Ley, 2nd, 3rd and 4th years: 
PK applied (0:18:36) at 380 kg: 31 Jan 1984
cut: 17 June, 11 Sept
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1985</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##W. wheat: 
Ploughed: 3 Oct, 1984, 
NPK applied (5:14:30) at 340 kg (N at 80 kg as ‘Nitro-Chalk' (27.5% N)): 9 Oct 
spring-tine cultivated, seed sown Avalon, sown at 160 kg: 9 Oct, 
N applied at 70 kg as ‘Nitro-Chalk' (27.5% N): 15 Apr, 1985, 24 Apr. 
Mecoprop at 1.2 kg with bromoxynil at 0.3 kg and ioxynil at 0.3 kg in 250 l: 16 May. 
Propiconazole at 0.25 kg in 250 l: 17 June
Propiconazole at 0.12 kg in 250 l: 2 July. 
carbendazim and maneb (as 'Septal' at 2.5 kg): 2 July.
Combine harvested: 2 Sept.

##Ley, 1st year: 
Ploughed: 3 Oct, 1984, Spring-tine cultivated: 22 Apr, 1985, 
N applied at 50 kg as 'Nitro-Chalk' (27.5% N): 24 Apr. 
NPK applied (5:14:30) at 340 kg: 25 Apr.
Spring-tine cultivated with crumbler attached, seeds sown S23 perennial ryegrass at 27 kg, Blanca white clover at 7 kg, mixture sown at 34 kg: 1 May. 
Cut: 20 Nov.

##Ley, 2nd, 3rd, 4th and 5th years: 
PK applied (0:18:36) at 380 kg: 25 Jan, 1985. 
Chain harrowed: 12 Apr. Cut: 1 July, 20 Nov.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1986</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##Ley, 1st year: 
ploughed: 4 dec 1985
heavy spring-tine cultivated, spike harrowed with crumbler attached, seeds sown S23 perennial ryegrass at 27 kg, Blanca white clover at 7 kg, mixture sown at 34 kg. 7 May 1986
N applied at 50 kg as 'Nitro-Chalk', rolled: 8 may
NPK applied (5:14:30) at 340 kg: 5 June
topped: 12 June.

##Ley, 2nd, 3rd, 4th, 5th and 6th years: 
PK applied (0:18:36) at 400 kg: 29 Nov 1985
cut: 12 June
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1987</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##winter wheat
Ploughed and rolled: 17 July, 1986. 
Subsoiled with 25 cm wings on tines 30 cm deep and 70 cm apart, in two directions at right angles: 28 Aug. 
Glyphosate at 1.4 kg in 200 l: 16 Sept. 
Methiocarb at 0.22 kg: 18 Sept. 
PK applied (0:18:36) at 560 kg: 25 Sept. 
Carbofuran at 7.5 kg: 25 Sept.
rotary harrowed with crumbler attached, : 25 Sept.
seed sown Mercia, sown at 190 kg: 25 Sept. 
Chlortoluron at 5.6 kg in 200 l: 9 Oct. 
Mn at 0.16 kg as manganese sulphate in 240 l: 14 Apr 1987
Prochloraz at 0.34 kg with carbendazim at 0.13 kg and Chlormequat at 1.1 kg  in 240 l: 14 Apr, 1987. 
Clopyralid at 0.07 kg, bromoxynil at 0.334 kg with mecoprop at 2.5 kg in 240 l: 14 Apr. 
N1 at 50 kgN/ha as Nitro-Chalk: 23 Apr
N2 at 100 kgN/ha as Nitro-Chalk: 23 Apr
N3 at 150 kgN/ha as Nitro-Chalk: 23 Apr
N4 at 200 kgN/ha as Nitro-Chalk: 23 Apr
N5 at 250 kgN/ha as Nitro-Chalk: 23 Apr. 
Fenpropimorph at 0.75 kg with chlorothalonil at 0.75 kg in 200 l: 5 June. 
Propiconazole at 0.12 kg with carbendazim and maneb (as 'Septal' at 2.5 kg) in 200 l: 29 June, 
Combine harvested: 1 Sept.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1988</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##potatoes
Glyphosate at 1.4 kg in 200 l: 22 Sept, 1987. 
Ploughed: 22 Feb, 1988. Heavy spring-tine cultivated: 5 Apr. 
PK applied (0:18:36) at 1400 kg: 8 Apr. 
N1 at 70 kgN/ha as Nitro-Chalk: 20 Apr
N2 at 140 kgN/ha as Nitro-Chalk: 20 Apr
N3 at 210 kgN/ha as Nitro-Chalk: 20 Apr
N4 at 280 kgN/ha as Nitro-Chalk: 20 Apr
N5 at 350 kgN/ha as Nitro-Chalk: 20 Apr
Oxamyl at 5.0 kg, spring-tine cultivated: 20 Apr. 
Mg at 100 kg as kieserite, rotary harrowed, potatoes planted Pentland Crown: 21 Apr
Rotary ridged, Linuron at 1.5 kg in 220 l: 13 May. 
Mancozeb at 1.4 kg in 220 l: 15 July and 1 Aug. 
Mancozeb at 1.4 kg in 220 1 with pirimicarb Pirimicarb at 0.14 kg: 14 June, 5 July and 15 Aug. 
Fentin hydroxide at 0.28 kg in 220 l: 30 Aug. 
Desiccant Diquat at 0.80 kg ion in 400 l: 15 Sept. 
Haulm mechanically destroyed: 29 Sept. Potatoes lifted: 26 Oct.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1989</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##wheat 
Ploughed: 28 Oct, 1988. Dolomite at 5 t, Methiocarb at 0.20 kg: 29 Oct. 
PK applied (0:18:36) at 556 kg: 31 Oct. Carbofuran at 7.5 kg
and cultivated in: 1 Nov. Spike harrowed with crumbler attached,
seed sown Mercia, with methiocarb pellets, sown at 165 kg: 2 Nov, 
Seed sown Mercia without methiocarb, Mercia, sown at 180 kg : 13 Dec. 
Omitted plots spring-tine cultivated: 6 Feb, 1989. 
Omitted plots re-sown: 7 Feb. 
Omitted plots harrowed and sown to s. wheat Alexandria, sown at 180 kg: 31 Mar. 
Mecoprop at 2.5 kg with bromoxynil at 0.34 kg and clopyralid at 0.07 kg in 220 l: 28 Apr. 
Manganese at 0.096 kg Mn as a foliar spray in 220 l: 29 Apr and 22 May. 
N1 at 50 kgN/ha as Nitro-Chalk: 3 May
N2 at 100 kgN/ha as Nitro-Chalk: 3 May
N3 at 150 kgN/ha as Nitro-Chalk: 3 May
N4 at 200 kgN/ha as Nitro-Chalk: 3 May
N5 at 250 kgN/ha as Nitro-Chalk: 3 May. 
Prochloraz at 0.40 kg with carbendazim at 0.15 kg applied with Chlormequat chloride at 1.6 kg in 220 l: 17 May.
pPropiconazole at 0.12 kg in 220 l: 5 June. 
Metsulfuron-methyl at 6.0 g in 220 1 to s. wheat only: 13 June. 
Fenpropimorph at 0.75 kg with maneb at 1.6 kg and carbendazim at 0.25 kg in 220 l: 3 July. 
Combine barvested: 7 Aug.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1990</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##winter beans
Subsoiled with tines 50 cm apart and 40 cm deep: 15 Sept, 1989. 
PK applied (0:24:24) at 420 kg and K applied as Muriate of potash at 170 kg: 19 Sept. 
Paraquat at 0.80 kg ion in 220 l: 10 Oct.
Disced: 11 Oct. Seed Banner sown at 18 seeds per square metre broadcast by drill, ploughed in and rolled: 12 Oct. 
Propyzamide at 0.85 kg with simazine at 0.85 kg in 220 l: 15 Oct. 
Manganese at 0.19 kg in 220 l: 5 Apr, 1990. 
Deltamethrin at 7.5 g in 220 l: 23 Apr and 18 May. 
Fenpropimorph at 0.75 kg in 220 l: 11 July. Combine harvested: 11 Aug.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
</reports>