<reports>
<report>
<year>1966</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[66/3/9.1
INTENSIVE CEREALS
(wc)
Woburn Stackvard Classical Site 1966 - the first year

To investigate the growing of continuous winter wheat in comparison witn
a five course rotation, both with heavy dressings of fertilisers,
There is a similar experiment involving spring barley.

These experiments are respectively, wheat on part of the site of the
Continuous Wheat Experiment 1877 - 195k and the barley on part of
the site of the continuous barley, As well as crop yields, soll
carbon and nitrogen will be studied, and the incidence of soil-
borne diseases,

Design: For each cereal: 2 randomised blocks of 6 plots, split for N,
Area of each sub-plot: 0,0103. Area harvested: Wheat and barley -
0.0067, potatoes - 0.0069, Area of each whole plot: 0,0k31.

Area harvested: Ley - 0,0k11,
Treatments: Wheat blocs: All combinations ofi-
1. Whole plots: cropping:
Continuous wheat: Five course rotation, in all phases:
1 year ley, potatoes, wheat, wheat, wheat,
2. Sub-plots: Nitro to wheat:
0.5 (11), 1.0 2), L.5 (¥3), 2,0 (Kb4) cwt N as "Nitro
Chalk' as spring top-dressing,
Treatments: Barley blocks: All combinations ofi-
1, Whole plots: cropping:
Continuous barley: Five course rotation, in all phases:
1 year ley, potatoes, barley, barley, barley.
2. Sub-plots: Kitro to barley:
0.4 (1m), 0.8 (2), 1.2 (N3), 1.6 (N4) cwt K as 'Nitro-
Chalk' applied in the seedbed,
Varieties: Potatoes: Pentland Dell
Wheat: Cappelle
Barley: Maris Badger
Ley: 1 1b English Italian ryegrass, 2 1b Danish
Italian ryegrass, 1.5 1b English Broad Red
clover, 0.5 1b Canadian Alsike Clover,
Mixture sown at 29 1b,

Other applications:

All crops: 1.0 cwt P205, 2.0 cwt K20, half ploughed in, half worked
into the seedbed,

Ley: O. cwt ¥ as 'Nitro-Chalx'.

Potatoes: 1.2 cwt N as 'Nitro-Chalk',
66/8/9.2
NOTE: The whole area carried spring beans without menure in 1964,
and was bare fallowed in 1965. To lessen the risk of damage
due to Wheat-Buldb Fly mustard was broadcast with 0,42 cwt | as
'Nitro-Chalk' on June 28, 1965. The mustard was destroyed
mechanically on Oct 7, and ploughed in on Oct 13.
Cultivations, etc.:

Ley: Half basal PK applied: Oct 26, 1965, Remaining basal PK
applied: Mar 22, 1966. 'Nitro-Chalk' applied, seed sown at
25 1b: Mar 30. Cut twice for hay: July b, Aug 26,

Potatoes: Half basal PK applied: Oct 26, 1965. Remaining basal
PK, and 'Nitro-Chelk' applied: Mar 23, 1966, Rotary cultivated,
potatoes machine planted: Mar 29, Earthed up: June 8,
Sprayed with mancozeb 1.2 1b in 33 gals: June 29, July 15,
Aug 4, Haulm mechanically destroyed: Sept 3, Lifted:
Sept 13.

Wheat: Half basal PK epplied: Oct 26, 1965. Remaining basal
PK applied: Oct 29. Seed drilled 150 1b: Nov 2. 'Nitro-
Chalk' applied: Apr 12, 1965, Combine harvested: Aug 25.

Barley: Half basal PK applied: Oct 26, 1965. Remaining basal
PX applied: Mar 7, 1966, Seed drilled 140 1b, and 'Nitro-
Chalk' applied: Mar 8, Combine harvested: Aug 18.

Standard errors per sub plot, Grain:

Wheat: 2.23 or 5.7% (21 d.f.)

Barley: 2.15 or 4.6% (21 4.1.)
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1967</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[67/B/9.1
INTENSIVE CEREALS
(WIC)
Woburn Stackyard Classical Site 1967 - the second year
For treatments and previous years' results, see 'Results' 66/B/9.,
Crop sequence symbols
Year
& 67 68 69 70 n T (F] ™ LF
C1 L P w Ww Ww L P Ww w W
ce P Ww w Ww L P Ww w w L
c3 Ww Ww Ww L P Ww Ww w L P
ch Ww Ww L P W w Ww L P Ww
cs Ww L P w w Ww L P w W
cé Ww Ww Ww w Ww Ww Ww Ww Ww Ww
Area of each sub plot: 0,0103, Area harvested: Ley - 0,0022, wheat and
barley - 0,0066, potatoes = 0,0069.
Basal applications:

All crops: 1.0 cwt P205, 2,0 cwt K20, half ploughed in, half worked into
the seedbed.

Potatoes: 1.2 cwt N as 'Nitro-Chelk',
Ley: O.L cwt K as 'Nitro-Chalk'.
Cultivations, etc,:

All plots: Half basal PK applied, ploughed: Sept 14, 1966.

Ley: Remaining basal PK applied, seed sown at 29 1b: Sept 16,
'Nitro-Chalk' applied: Mar 17, 1967. Cut three times for hay:
June 1, July 13, Sept 12,

Potatoes: Remeining basal PX, and 'Nitro-Chalk' applied: Mar 17, 1967.
Potatoes planted: Mar 22, BEerthed up: June 10, Sprayed with
mancozeb at 1.2 1b in 30 gals: July 1, July 26, Avg 8, Sprayed
with fentin acetate at 4,2 oz plus maned at 1.4 oz in 30 gals:
Aug 21, Sprayed with undiluted BOV at 15 gals: Sept 6, Lifted:
Sept 12, Variety: Majestic.

Wheat: Remaining PK applied: Oct 21. Seed drilled at 210 1b:

Oct 26, 'Nitro-Chalk' applied: Apr 14, 1967. Sprayed with
foxynil/mecoprop (Actril C at 6 pints in 25 gals): Apr 27.
Combine harvested: Aug 22, Variety: Cappelle,

Barley: Remeining PK epplied, end seed drilled st 140 1b: Mar 4, 1967.
'Nitro-Chelk' applied: Mar 17. Sprayed with ioxynil/mecoprop
(Actril C at 6 pints in 25 gals): Apr 27. Combine harvested:
Aug 18, Variety: Maris Badger.
67/3/9.2
KOTES: (1) Estimates of eyespot (Cercosporells herpotrichoides) end
take-all (Ophiobolus graminis) were made in May and June
on barley and in April and July on wheat,

(2) Lea” samples of potato and wheat were teken in June for
mineral analysis, N P and K levels were normal while Mn
levels were high and Ca and Mg were low.

Standard errors per plot, Grain:
Wheat sub plot: 6,76 or 18,67 (12 4.1.)
Zarley sub plot: 2,57 or 6.5% (12 4.1.)
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1968</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[68/B/7.1
INTENSIVE CEREALS
(wie)
Woburn Stackyard Classical Site 1968 - the third year
For treatments, and previous years' results, see 'Results' 66/B/9

and 67/B/9.

Area of each sub-plot: 0,0103. Area harvested: Ley - 0,0022,

wneat - 0,0033, barley - 0.0066, potatoes - 0,003k.,

Wheat blocks only: A test of magnesium was introduced on eighth
plots: None (0), 162 1b MgO es Epsom salts (MG),
Basal epplications:

All crops: 1,0 cwt P205, 2.0 cwt K20, half ploughed in, half

worked into the seedbed.

Potatoes: 1.2 cwt N as 'Nitro-Chalk’',

Ley: 0.4% cwt N as 'Nitro-Chalk',

Cultivations, ete,

All plots: Helf PK epplied: 14 Sept, 1967. Ploughed: 15 - 16 Sept.
Ley: Mg and remaining PK applied, seeds sown at 29 lb: 20 Sept,
Jute ohar! applied: 27 Mar, 1968, Cut twice: 5 June,

Aug,

Potatoes: Sprayed with perequat at 0,5 1b in 33 gals on the permanent
barley blocks: 2 Mar, Remaining PX, 'Nitro-Chalk', and Mg
applied: 26 Mar, Rotary cultivated, potatoes planted: 27 Mar.
Barthed up: 22 May, Grubbed, rotary ridged: 13 June, Sprayed
with mencozeb et 1.2 1b plus demeton-s-methyl at 3,5 oz in 38
gals on the permenent wheat blocks only: 12 July. Sprayed with
mancozeb at 1.2 1b in 38 gals: 18 July, 30 July, Sprayed with
undiluted BOV at 15 gals: 4 Sept. Lifted: 24 Sept.

Wneat: Remaining PK and Mg applied, seed drilled at 170 lb:

13 Oct, 1967, 'Nitro-Chalk' applied: 9 Apr, 1968, Sprayed with
ioxynil/mecoprop (Actril C at 6 pints in 25 gals): 25 Apr.
Combine harvested: 22 Aug,

Barley: Sprayed with paraquat at 0.5 1b in 33 gels: 2 Mar,
Remaining PK applied: 4 Mar, Seed drilled at 140 1b: 6 Mar,
'Nitro-chalk' applied 15 Mar, Sprayed with ioxynil/mecoprop
(Actril C at 5 pints in 25 gals): 26 Apr, Combine harvested:
20 Aug.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1969</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[106
INTENSIVE CEREALS
(69/v/ri/13)

Woburn Stackyard I 1969 - the fourth year,

For treatments etc., and previous years' results, see 'Results’

66/8/9, 67/8/9 and 68/B/7.

Area of each sub plot: 0,0103. Area harvested: Ley - 0.0022,

wheat - 0,0033, potatoes - 0,0034,

NOTE: The magnesium test on eighth plots of wheat blocks continued
and was cumiletive with 1968 and a similar test was introduced
on eighth plots on the barley blocks: None (0), 162 1b MgO
es Epsom salts (Mg).

Basal and standard applications:

All crops: 1.0 cwt P205, 2,0 owt K20 es (0:14:28), helf ploughed in,
half applied to the plough furrow,

Ley: Ob cwt N as 'Ritro-Chalk',

Potatoes: 1.2 cwt N as 'Ritro-Chalk', Weedkiller: Paraquat at 0,37
1b ion plus linuron at 0,5 1b in 25 gals, FRungicide: Mancozed
at 1,2 1b in 37 gzls applied on 2 occasions, Insecticide:
Demeton-s-methyl at 3,5 oz applied once with fungicide,

Wneat: Weedkiller: Ioxynil at © oz plus mecoprop at 27 oz in
25 grls,

Barley: Weedkiller: Ioxynil octancate, bromoxynil octencate
and iso-octyl ester of dichlorprop ('Oxytril P' at 1 pt in
25 gals).

Cultivations, etc,.:

All plots: Helf PK applied: 1 Oct, 1968, Ploughed: 4 Oct.
Remaining PK and Mg applied: 7 Oct.

Ley: Seeds sown at 29 1b: 1k Oct. 'Nitro-Chalk' applied:

27 Mar, 1969, Cut twice: 28 June, 3 Sept.

Potatoes: 'Nitro-Chalk' applied: 17 Apr. Rotary cultivated,

potatoes planted: 18 Apr. Weedkiller applied: 15 May.

Rotary ridged: 17 June, Rungicide plus insecticide applied:

18 July. PFungicide applied: 7 Aug, 27 Aug. FHaulm mechenically
destroyed: 16 Sept, Lifted: 23 Sept.

Wheat: Seed drilled at 175 1b: 17 Oct, 1968, 'Kitro-Chalk' applied:
15 Apr, 1969. Weedkiller applied: 2 May, Combine harvested:
29 Aug.
107
Barley: Seed drilled at 140 1b: 11 Mer resown 16 Apr, 'Nitro-
Chelk' applied: 3 Apr. Weedkiller applied: 22 May. Combine
harvested: 29 Aug.
NOTE: Estimates of eyespot (Cercosporellas herpotrichoides) and
take-2ll (Ophiocbolus graminis) were made in May and June
on barley and in April and July on wheat.
Standard errors per plot.
ley, dry matter, cwt:
Wheat blocks 1/L plot: 1st cut: 5.89 or 19.2% (4 4.1.)
2nd cut: 0.21 or 4, 7% (4 d.f.)
Total of 2 cuts: 5.81 or 16.5% (Lk 4.f.)
Barley blocks 1/4 plot: 1st cut: 7.31 or 18, 7% (& a.f,)
2nd cut: 0.52 or 9.3% (4 a.f.)
Total of 2 cuts: T.66 or 17.1% (4 4.7.)
Wheat, grain, cwt: 1/b plot: 2.1k or 7.4% (12 a.f.)
1/8 plot: 1.99 or 6.9% (16 a.f.)
Berley, grein, cwt: 1/k plot: 1.45 or L.o% (12 4.1.)
1/8 plot: 1.52 or 5.1% (16 4.1.)
Potatoes, total tubers, tons:
Wheat blocks 1/k plot: 0.882 or 6.3% (b a.f.)
Berley blocks 1/4 plot: 0.766 or L.6p (bk 4.1.)
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1970</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[INTENSIVE CEREALS
(70/w/RN/13)
Woburn Stackyard I 1970 = the fifth year.
For treatments and previous years' results, see 'Results’ 66/B/9,
67/8/9, 68/B/7 and 69/W/Ri/13.
Area of each sub-plot: 0,0103, Area harvested: Ley - 0,002,
potatoes ~ 0,0034, wheat and barley - 0,0033.
NOTE: The magnesium test wes amended to compare residual (MR) with
equivalent fresh dressing (MM) to sub-plots previously untreated.
The fresh dressings were 1980 1b Epsom salts (half before ploughing,
nalf after) on the wheat blocks and 990 1b Epsom salts (all before
ploughing) on the barley blocks,
The ley is now ryegrass only, The barley variety is now Julia,
Basel and standard applications:
All crops: 1.0 cwt P205, 2,0 cwt K20 as (0:14:28), half ploughed in,
half applied to plough furrow,
Ley: 1.0 cwt N in spring, 0,75 cwt RN after the first two cuts, as
'Nitro-Chalk', Weedkiller: Paraquat at 0,5 1b ion in 37 gals.
Potatoes: 1.2 cwt N as 'Nitro-Chalk', wWeedkiller: Linuron at 1,0 1b
Plus paraquat at 0,37 1b ion in 33 gals. Fungicide: Mancozeb at
1.2 1b in 37 gals applied on 2 occasions, Insecticide:
Demeton-s-methyl at 3.5 fl oz applied on one occasion with
fungicide,
Wheat: Weedkillers: Paraquat at 0.5 1b ion in 37 gals, Ioxynil at
9 oz plus mecoprop at 27 oz in 25 gals.
Barley: Weedkillers: Parequet at 0,5 1b ion in 37 gals, Ioxynil at
6.5 oz plus mecoprop et 22,5 oz in 25 gals,
Cultivations, etc,:
All plots: Mg and half PK applied: 25 Sept, 1969. Ploughed:
26 Sept. Remaining PK applied: 29 Sept,
Ley: Paraquat applied: 10 Sept, 1969, Seed sown at 28 1b:
30 Sept, N applied: 16 Mar, 1970, 16 June, 24 July. Cut three
times: 11 June, 23 July*, 3 Sept*,
Potatoes: Remaining Mg applied on wheat block: 30 Sept, 1969, N
applied: 17 Apr, 1970. Rotary cultivated, potatoes planted:
22 Apr. Weedkiller applied: 13 May, Orubbed, rotary ridged:
6 June, Fungicide plus insecticide epplied: 31 July. Fungicide |
. epplied: 18 Aug, Sprayed with undiluted BOV at 20 gals:
T Sept. Lifted: 15 Sept,
* Topping cuts, No yields recorded,
109
70/W/RN/43

Waeet: Paraquat applied: 10 Sept, 1960, Remaining Mg applied:
3C Sept. Fotery cultivated, seed drilled at 170 1b: 23 Cet.
I epplied: 2k Aor, 1970, IToxynil plus mecoprop applied:

7 May. Combine harvested: 1b Zug,

Barley: Paraquat applied: 10 Sept, 1569. Power narrowed, seed
drilled at 135 lb: 25 Mar, 1970. N applied: 31 Mar, Ioxynil
plus mecoprop applied: 18 May, Combine harvested: 11 Aue,

HOTE: Estimetes of eyespot (Cercosporella herpotirichoides) and
take-all (Ophiobelus graminis) were made on boi: cereal crops,
Standard errors per plot,

Ley: dry matter, cwt:

Waeat blocks 1/4 plots 1st cut: 2.02 or 10.37 (4 4.7.)
Barley blocks 1/4 plot: 1st cut: 1.27 or 4.7% (4 G.f,)

Potatoes, total tubers, tons:

Wheat blocks 1/4 plot: 0.910 or 7.2% (4 a.f.)
Barley blocks 1/k plot: 1.957 or 14.5% (4 a.f,)

Waeet, grain, cwt:

1/4 plot: 2,70 or 12,% (12 4.1)
1/8 plot: 1.54 or 7.4% (16 a.r.)

Barley, grein, cwt:

1/4 plot: 2,47 or 8,6 (12 a.z.)
1/8 plots 2.18 or 7.6% (16 4.1.)
110
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1971</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[T/¥/Ri/13
INTENSIVE CEREALS

Object: To study the effects of intensive cereal cropping on yield,
incidence of soil-borme diseases and organic matter in the soil-
Woburn Steckyard I.

The sixth year, ley, potatoes, winter wheat, barley,

For previous years see 66/B/9(t), 67/B/9, 68/B/7(t) and 63-TO/M/RN/13(t).

Design: For each cereal: 2 randomised blocks of 6 plots, split into 4,

Whole plot dimensions: 8,53 x 20.4, Sub plot area harvested:
Potatoes - 0,00343, wheat - 0,00271, barley - 0.00277.

NOTE: The magnesium test on all crops is now ended,

Basal applications: All crops: 5020 kg magnesian limestone three-quarters
ploughed in, a quarter applied to plough furrow, 126 kg P205, 252 kg
X20 as (0:14:28), half ploughed in, half applied to plough furrow,
Weedkiller: Paraquat at 1.12 kg ion in 281 1,

Ley: 63 kg N in seedbed, 63 kg N 8 weeks after sowing, 75 kg N after
each cut except the last as 'Nitro-Chalk' 21,

Potatoes: 150 kg N as 'Nitro-Chalk' 21, Weedkiller: Linuron at
1.12 kg in 371 1, Fungicide: Mancozeb at 1,34 kg in 416 1 on
the first occasion, and 371 1 on the second, Insecticide:
Demeton-s-methyl at 246 ml applied with first mancozeb spray.

Wheat and barley: Weedkiller: Ioxynil at 0.53 Kg and mecoprop at
1.58 kg in 281 1.

Cultivations, etc.: All plots: Paraquat applied: 16 Sept, 1970. Half
PK applied: 24 Sept, Tharee-quarters magnesian limestone applied:

6 Oct. Ploughed: 10 Oct. Remaining PK and magnesian limestone

applied: 1k Oct.

Leys: Deep-tine cultivated barley blocks: 21 Oct, 1970, N applied:
1 Apr. Seeds sown at 33 kg: 2 Apr. First cut: 16 July.

N applied: 19 July, Second cut: 8 Sept, Variety: Italian
Ryegrass S22,

Potatoes: Deep-tine cultivated barley blocks: 21 Oct, 1970. N
applied: 29 Mar, 1971. Rotary cultivated, potatoes planted:

30 Mar, Weedkiller applied: 5 May. Rotary ridged: 1 June,
Pumgicide plus insecticide applied: 28 June, Fungicide
applied: 12 Aug, BHaulm mechanically destroyed: 13 Sept.
Lifted: 14 Sept, Variety: Majestic,

Wheat: Seed drilled at 191 kg: 14 Oct, 1970. NK applied:

14 Apr, 1971, Weedkiller applied: 28 Apr. Combine harvested:
28 Aug. Variety: Cappelle.
1m
T/W/R¥/13
Barley: Deep-tine cultivated: 21 Oct, 1970. K applied, seed drilled
et 157 kg: 17 Mer, 1971. Power harrowed, re-drilled at 157 kg:
G Apr, Weedkiller applied: 18 May, Combine harvested: 25 Aug.
Variety: Julia,
NOTE: Estimates of eyespot (Cercosporella herpotrichoides) end take-all
(Ophiobolus graminis) were made on both cereal crops.
Standard errors per sub plot,
Wheat, grain, tonnes/hectare: Sub plot: 0,391 or 10,6% (12 4.f,)
Barley, grain, tonnes/hectare: Sub plot: 0.19% or 4.5% (11 4.f.)
112
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1972</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[T/4/RY/13
: INTENSIVE CEREALS
Object: To study the effects of intensive cereal cropping on yield,
incidence of soil-borne diseases and orgenic matter in the soil -
Woburn Stackyard I.
Sponsors: G.YW. Cooke, D.B. Sicpe.
The seventh year, ley, poletoes, winter wheat, barley,
For previous years see 65/B/9(t), 67/B/9, 68/8/7(¢), 65/M/RN/13(t),
TO//RN/13(¢) and TA/W/0/13(%).
Whole plot dimensions: 8,53 x 20,4, Sub plot erce harvested:
Potatoes - 0,00139, wheat - 0,00273, barley - 0.00273.
Basel applications: ALL crops: 130 kg P205, 260 kg K20 és (G:1k:28),
hall ploughed in, half applisd to the plough furrow, Weedkiller
} to ell crops except potatoes: Paraquat at 0.56 kg icon in-280 1,
Leys: 83 kg If in secedved, 63 :g N after sowing 23 'Ritro-Chell',
Only one cut was taken, $
Potatoes: 150 kg I as 'Nitro-Chalk', Weedkiller: Linuron at 1.1 kg
with paraquat at O,k kg fon In 370 1, Fungicide: Mancozeb at
1.3 kg in 430 1, Fungiclde with insecticide: Mancozed at 1.3 kg
with demeton-s-metiyl at 0.25 kg in 430 1,
Wheav: Weedkiller: 2,4-D at 0,7 kg with dichlorprop at 2.8 kg in
280 1,
Barley: Weedliller: 2,4-D at 0,56 kg with dichlorprop at 2,2 kg in
280 1,
Seed: Leys: Italian ryegrass S22, sown at 28 ka,
Potatoee: Majestic,
Wheat: Cappelle, covn at 180 kg,
Barley: Julie (dresced with etnirimol) sown at 180 ka.
Cultivations, etc.: All plots: Half PK applied, ploughed: 1 Oct, 1971.
Remaining PK applied: 7 Oct.
Leys: Paraquat applied: 9 Sept, 1971. Deep-tine cultivated, wheat
block only: 4 Rov, N applied: 18 Apr, 1972. Rotary cultivated:
21 Apr. Seed sown: 26 Apr, WN applied: 6 June, Cut once:
6 Sept,
114
Te/M/RE/13
Potatoes: Deep-tine cultiveted, wheat block only: 4 Nov, 1971.
H applied: 4 Apr; 1972, FRotery cultivated, potatoes planted:
18 &pr, Linuron with peraquat applied: 6 May, Rotary ridged:
2 19 June, Rungicide applied: 5 July, Fungicide with insecticide
applied: 27 July, Hauln mechenicaolly destroyed: 1h Sept,
Lifted: 20 Sept.
Wheat: Paraquat applied: ¢ Sept, 1971. Seed drilled: 15 Oct, NW
appliéd: 11 Apr, 1972. 2,4-D with dichlorprop epplied: 27 Apr.
© Combine harvested: 30 Aug.
Barley: Paraquat applied: © Sept, 1971. Seed drilled: 15 Mar, 1072.
F applied: 16 Mer, 2,4-D with dichlorprop applied: 8 May,
Combine harvested: 24 Aug,
NOTE: Bstimates of eyespot (Cercosporella herpotrichoides) and take-all
(Geeurannomyces greminic formerly Ophiotolus graminis) were
. rade cn both cereal crops,
Standard errors per sto plot.
Wheat, grain, tonnes/hectaret 0.389 or 5% (12 a.7,)
Berley, grein, tonnes/hectare: 0,197 or 4,0% (11 4.f%.)

- NOTES: (1) One barley plot (CS6, NSO) was severely demaged by birds, The
yield of this plot was not recorded - an estimated value
wes used in the analysis,

(2) In 1872 and in 1ST the yields of leys were not recorded,
115
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1973</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[T3/%/R8/13
Basal applications: All crops: Manures: (0:14:28) at 130 kg P205,
260 kg K20, half ploughed in, half applied to the plough furrow.
Hoaiailer to all crops except potatoes: Paraquat at 0.56 kg ion
in 280 1,
Ley: 'Nitro-Chalk' at 60 kg N in seedbed, 60 kg N after sowing,
and 60 kg N after the first cut, Two cuts were taken,
Potatoes: 'Ritro-Chalk' at 150 kg N, Weedkiller: Linuron at 1.2
kg plus paraquat at 0,42 kg ion in 280 1, Fungicide with insecticide:
Mancozed at 1.3 kg plus demeton-s-methyl at 0.25 kg in 390 1.
Fungicide: Mancozeb at 1.3 kg in 390 1 on the first occasion and
in 370 1 on the second occasion,
Waeatd Weedkiller: Ioxynil at 0.63 kg with mecoprop at 1,9 kg in
200 1.
Barley: Weedkiller: Ioxynil at 0,53 kg with mecoprop at 1.6 kg
in 280 1.
Seed: Ley: Italian ryegrass S22, sown at 40 kg,
Potatoes: Majestic,
Wheat: Cappelle, sown at 200 kg.
Barley: Julie, dressed with ethirimol, sown at 160 kg.
Cultivations, etc.:- All plots: Half PK applied: 4 Oct, 1972.
Ploughed: 10 Oct, Remaining PK applied: 17 Oct.
ley: Paraquat applied: 6 Sept, 1972. Power harrowed, wheat
site only: 18 Oct, N applied: 16 Mar, 1973. Seeds sown:
20 Mar, N applied: 18 May, 3 July, Cut twice: 2 July, 28 Aug.
Potatoes: Power harrowed, wheat site only: 18 Oct, 1972. Hu
applied: 23 Mar, 1973. Rotary cultivated: 6 Apr. Potatoes
planted: 7 Apr. Linuron with Jaragiat applied: 1h May,
Grubbed: 1 June, Rotary ridged: 16 June, Pingicide with insecticide
applied: 5 July. Frngicide applied: 26 July, 13 Avg. Haulm
mechanically destroyed: 19 Sept, Sprayed with undiluted BOV at
220 1: 2h Sept, Lifted: li Oct,
Wheat: Paraquat applied: 6 Sept, 1972. Power harrowed: 18 Oct.
Seed sown: 20 Oct. NW applied: 12 Apr, 1973. Ioxynil with mecoprop
applied: 26 Apr. Combine harvested: 22 Aug,
Barley: Paraquat applied: 6 Sept, 1972. Seed mown: 12 Mar, 1973.
N applied: 16 Mar, Ioxyni) with mecoprop applied: 11 Mey. Combine
harvested: 13 Aug.
NOTE: Estimates of eyespot (Cercosporella herpotrichoides) and take-oll
(Geevmenn-myces graminis) were: mde on both cereal exops in July,
Standard errurs per sub plot,
Wheat, grain, tonneafhectare: 0,141 or 3.97% (12 a.7.)
Barley, grain, Lonnesfiectares 9,256 or 5.67 (12 0.7.)
129
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1974</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[h/¥/R/13 :

Basal applications: All crops: Manures: Magnesian limestone applied at
3.5 tonnes. P205 at 130 kg, K20 at 260 kg as (0:14:28), half ploughed
in, helf applied to the plough.farrow. Weedkillers: Paraquat at 0.56 kg
ion in 370 1.

Standard applications:

Leys: N at 60 kg, as 'Nitro-Chalk?, in seedbed and repeated after sowing
and after each cut except the last,

Potatoes: N at 150 kg as 'Nitro-Chalk!, Weedkiller: Linuron at 1.2 kg
plus paraquat at 0.28 kg ion in 280 1. Fungicide with insecticide:
Mancozeb at 1.3 kg plus demeton-s-methyl at 0.25 kg in 450 1.
Fungicides Mancozeb at 1,3 kg in 450 1.

Wheat: Weedkiller: Ioxynil at 0.63 kg with mecoprop at 1.9 kg in 280 1
on the first occasion and ioxynil at 0.52 kg with mecoprop at 1.6 kg
in 280 1 on the second occasion,

Barley: Weedkiller: Ioxynil at 0.52 kg and mecoprop at 1.6 kg in 280 1.

Seed: Leys: Italian ryegrass sown at 40 kg.

Potatoes: Pentland Crown.
Wheat: Cappelle, sown at 190 kg.
Barley: Julia, dressed with ethirimol, sown at 160 kg.

Cultivations, etc.:- All plots: Paraquat applied: 12 Sept, 1973. Magnesian
limestone applied: 5 Oct. Half PK applied: 10 Oct. Ploughed: 11 Oct,
Remaining PK applied: 12 Oct. Spring-tine cultivateds 13 Oct.

Leys: Spring=tine cultivated: 30 Mar, 197k. Power harrowed, N applied,
seeds sown: 5 Apr. N applied: 31 May, 2 July, 19 Aug. Cut three
times: 1 July, 15 Aug, 24 Sept. -

Potatoes: Spring-tine cultivated: 30 Mar, 1974. N applied, rotary
cultivated: 9 Apr. Potatoes planted: 10 Apr. Weedkiller applied:
15 May. Rotary ridged: 11 June, Fungicide with insecticide applied:
18 July. Fungicide applied: 7 Aug. Haulm mechanically destroyed:
12 Sept. Sprayed with undiluted BOV at 170 1: 18 Sept. Lifted:

30 sept.

Wheat: Seed sown: 15 Oct, 1973. Weedkiller applied: 5 Apr, 197h.

N epplied: 9 Apr. Weedkiller applied on second occasion: 14 May.
Combine harvested: 30 Aug.

Barley: Spring-tine cultivated: 27 Mar, 197h. Spring-tine cultivated
with crumbler: 28 Mar. Seed sown: 29 Mar, N applied: 1 Apr.
Weedkiller applied: 14 May, Combine harvested: 22 Aug.

NOTE: Estimates of eyespot (Cercosporella herpotrichoides) end take-all

(Geeumannomyces graminis) were made on both cereal crops in early
July.

Standard errors per sub plot.

Wheat, grain: tonnes/hectare: 0.346 or 9.7% es a.f.)

Barley, grain: tonnes hectare: 0.559 or 10.8 (12 d.f.)

122
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1975</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[: T5/w /R/13
Fasal applications: Al) crope: P05 al 130 kg, ¥Z0 at 260 kg =& (0:14:28),
half plcvgled in, half arplied to the plough furrow,
Stendsxd spplicaticns:
Leys: N at 60 kg, as 'Nitro-Chalk', in seedbed erd repested ufter sowing.
Weedkiller: /nfrotrievole at 4.5 kg ir 260 1.
Potatoes: k at 15C kg es 'Nitro-Chalk', Weedkiller: Liruron at 1.2 kg plus
pareqrat at 0.28 kg ion in 280 1. Insecticide: Pemeton-g-methyl at
0.25 kg iv 286 1. Fungicide: Mancozeb at 1.3 kg in 390 1.
Wheat: Weedkillers: Aminotriazole at 4.5 kg in 280 1, IToxyn!l at 0.63 kg
with meccprop at 1.9 kg in 280 1,
Barley: Weedkillers: Aminotriazole at 4.5 kg in 280 1. Toxynil at 0.52 kg
with mecroprvp at 1.6 kg in 280 1.
Seed: leys: Iteljan ryegress sown at LO kg.
Potetoes: Pentland Crown.
Wheat: Caprelle sown at 200 Xg.
Terley: vilia, dressed with ethirimcl, sown at 160 ke.
Cultivations, etc.s3- All plots: k2lf PK ayrlied, ploughed: 3C Cet, 1974.
Reraining PK erplied: 8 Nov, Spring-tine cultiveted: 27 kov.
Leys: Arinctriszole epplied: 11 Sep, 19Th. Spring-tine cultivated four
timer with crumbler on the second end forth occasions: 26 Feb, 3 Mar,
2h Apr, 28 Apr, 1975. N applied: 1€ Apr, 11 June, Seed sown: 2 May.
Topped: § July, 21 Aug,
Potatoes: Spring-tine cultivated three times on the second occasion with
crupbler: 26 Fev, 3 Mar, 24 Apr, 1975. N applied: 18 Apr. Deep-
tire cultivated: 25 Apr. Rotary cultivated, potetoes planted: 5 Mey.
Linuron will paruquat upplieds £2 Mey, Crubled: 23 June. Rotary
ridged: 24 Jire, Insecticide aprlied: 25 June, Fungicide epplied:
15 July.  Haulm mechanicelly destroyed: 26 Sept. Sprayed with undiluted
B.0.V. et 16C 1: 2 Oct. Litted: 6 Oct.
Wheat: Seed sown: 27 hov, 1974. KN applied: 2k Bev, 1975. Weedkiller applied:
8 May. Combine barvested: 12 mug.
Barley: Spring-tine dtivated twice, second time with crumbler: 26 Feb,
3 Mar, 1675. Seed sown: 4 Mar. N applied: 10 Mar. Spring-tine
cultivated with cnuntlexr tlree times, seed resown: 1 May, Wecdkiller
applied: L June. Combine harvested: 18 Avg.
NOTES: (1) No cuts were teken from the leys because of poor growth in a dry yeer.
(2) The berley wes resown because of peor germisatiop exé tird dsrage on
the first sowirg.
(3) Estimates of eyespot (Cercosporella herpotrichoides) and take-all
(Gacumarromyces graminis) were made on both ceresl crops.
114
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1976</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[6/M/R/ 13
Basal applications: All crops: P205 at 130 kg, K20 at 260 kg as (0:14:28),
half ploughed in, half applied to the plough furrow.
Standard applications:

Leys: N at 60 kg as ‘Nitro-Chalk’ in the seedbed, repeated after sowing.
Weedkiller: Glyphosate at 1.7 kg in 340 1 to vheat stubble onlys
Potatoes: N at 150 kg as ‘Nitro-Chalk’. Weedkiller: Linuron at 1.2 kg
plus paraquat at 0.42 kg ton in 280 1. Insecticide: Pirimicard at 0.14 kg

in 450 1. Fungicide with insecticide: Mancozeb at 1.3 kg with demeton-
s-methyl at 0.25 kg in 450 1. Fungicide: Mancozed at 1.3 kg in 450 1.
Haulm desiccant: Diquat at 0.59 kg ion in 280 1.

Wheat: Weedkillers: Glyphosate at 1.7 kg in 340 1. Ioxynil at 0.63 kg
plus mecoprop at 1.9 kg in 280 1.

Barley: Weedkiller: loxynil at 0.52 kg and mecoprop at 1.6 kg in 280 1.

Seed: Ley: Italian ryegrass, sown at 40 kg

Potatoes: Pentland Crown

Wheat: Cappelle sown at 210 kg

Barley: Julia, dressed with ethirimol, sown at 160 kg
Cultivations, etc.:- All plots: Half PK applied, ploughed: 24 Oct, 1975.

Remaining PK applied: 27 Oct.

Leys: Weedkiller applied to wheat stubble only: S Oct, 1975. Spring-tine
cultivated wheat blocks only: 27 Oct. Deep-tine cultivated barley
blocks only: 29 Dec. Spring-tine cultivated barley blocks: 2 Mar,
19076, wheat blocks: O Mar. N applied: 20 Apr. Seed sown: 27 Apr.

N applied: 9 June. Cut once: 20 Oct.

Potatoes: Rotary cultivated: 14 Oct, 1975. Spring-tine cultivated barley

blocks: 2 Mar, 1976, wheat blocks: 9 Mar. N applied: 30 Mar.

Rotary cultivated, potatoes planted: 6 Apr. Weedkiller applied:

? May. Rotary ridged: 3 June. Pirimicarb applied: 18 June. Fungicide
vith insecticide applied: 30 June. Fungicide applied: 30 July.

Haulm mechanically destroyed: 15 Sept. Haulm desiccant applied:

6 Oct. Lifted: 19 Oct.

Wheat: Glyphosate applied: 5 Oct, 1975. Spring-tine cultivated, seed
sown: 27 Oct. N applied: 1 Apr, 1976. Weedkiller applied: 20 Apr.
Combine harvested: 2 Aug.

Bar ley: Deep-tine cultivated: 29 Dec, 1975. Spring-tine cultivated:

2 Mar, 1976. Seed sown: 8 Mar. N applied: 9 Mar. Weedkiller
applied: 28 Apr. Combine harvested: 26 July.
NOTES: (1) Five plots of wheat N 63 were damaged by birds shortly before
harvest. No yields are presented for N 63 on wheat.
(2) Four other plots of wheat were also affected by bird damage:
Tr
C/L/P 189
c/1/p/C 126
c/L/p/C 189
L/e/c/c 126
Estimated values were used in the analysis.
100
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1977</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[T7/W/RN/13
Standard applications:

wheat: Manures: (0:20:20) at 290 kg, combine drilled. Weedkillers: Glyphosate
at 1.7 kg in 280 1, methabenzthiazuron at 1.6 kg in 280 1, Ioxynil at 0.53 kg
plus mecoprop at 1.6 kg in°220 1. Insecticide: Pirimicarb at 0.14 kg in
270 1.

Barley: Menures: (0:20:20) at 300 kg, combine drilled. Weedkillers: Glyphosate
at 1.7 kg in 280 1, Ioxynil at 0.53 kg plus mecoprop at 1.6 kg in 220 1.

Seed:

Wheat: Cappelle, sown at 210 kg.

Barley: Julia, dressed with ethirimol, sown at 160 kg.

Cultivations, etc.:~- All plots: Glyphosate applied: 2U4 Sept, 1976. Rotary cultivated
grass leys: 1 Nov. Ploughed: 8 Nov.

Wheat: Aldicarb applied, rotary cultivated, seed sown: 24 Nov, 1976. Methabenzthia-
zuron applied: 25 Nov. N applied: 12 Apr, 1977. Ioxynil plus mecoprop
applied: 15 May. Pirimicarb applied: 11 July. Combine harvested: 7 Sept.

Barley: Spring-tine cultivated: 7 Mar, 1977. Aldicarb applied, rotary cultivated,
seed sown: 8 Apr. N applied: 13 Apr. Ioxynil plus mecoprop applied: 19 May.
The following treatments were cowbine harvested on 16 Aug:

ALDICARB 0 ALDICARB 10 ALDICARE 0 ALDICARB 10
PREVCROP C/C/C/L PREVCROP P/C/C/C PREVCROP C/C/L/P PREVCROP C/L/R/C
N 50, 150, 200 N 50, 150 N 100, 200 N 100, 150
Remaining treatments combine harvested: 30 Aug.

86
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1978</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[T8/W/RN/13
Standard applications:

Wheat: Manures: (0:20:20) at 310 kg, combine drilled. Weedkillers:
Methabenzthiazuron at 1.5 kg in 280 1. Mecoprop, bromoxynil and
foxynil ('Brittox' at 3.51 in 280 1).

Barley: Manures: (0:20:20) at 300 kg, combine drilled. Weedkillers:
Mecoprop, bromoxynil and foxynil ('Brittox' at 2.51 in 280 1).
Fungicide: Tridemorph at 0.52 kg applied with the weedkillers.

Seed: Wheat: Cappelle, sown at 210 kg.
Barley: Porthos, dressed with ethirimol, sown at 160 kg.
Cultivations, etc.:- All plots ploughed: 27 Sept, 1977.

wheat: Aldicarb applied, rotary cultivated: 24 Oct, 1977. Spring-tine
cultivated, seed sown: 25 Oct. Methabenzthiazuron applied: 29 Oct.
N applied: 7 Apr, 1978. Mecoprop, bromoxynil and joxynil applied:
10 May. Combine harvested: 25 Aug.

Barley: Spring-tine cultivated: 9 Mar, 1978. Aldicarb epplied, rotary
cultivated, spring-tine cultivated with crumbler attached, seed sown:
3 Apr. N applied, weedkillers and fungicide applied: 15 May. Combine
harvested: 23 Aug.

. 104
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1979</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[79/W/RN/13
Standard applications: .

Wheat: Manures: (0:20:20) at 310 kg, combine drilled. Weedkillers:
Methabenzthiazuron at 1.5 kg in 220 1.

Barley: Manures: (0:20:20) at 300 kg, combine drilled. Weedkillers:
Bramoxynil with ioxynil ('Oxytril CM' at 2.1 kg in 250 1).

Seed: Wheat: Flanders, sown at 180 kg.
Barley: Porthos, dressed with ethirimol, sown at 160 kg.
Cultivations, etc, :-

All plots: Ploughed: 30 Aug, 1978. Spring-tine cultivated, with crumbler
attached: 31 Aug. Dazomet applied and all plots rotary cultivated:
T Sept.

Wheat: Rotary cultivated: 11 Oct, 1978. Seed sown: 13 Oct. Autumn N
and weedkiller applied: 18 Oct. Spring N applied: 10 Apr, 1979.
Combine harvested: 30 Aug.

Barley: Heavy spring-tine cultivated: 16 Oct, 1978. Spring-tine cultivated,
with crumbler attached, twice: 16 Apr, 1979, 20 Apr. Seed sown:

23 Apr. N applied: 30 Apr. Weedkiller applied: 5 June. Combine
harvested: 28 Aug.
85
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1980</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[80/W/RN/13

Sub plots .

3. Nitrogen fertiliser {kg N}, cumulative:

W. Wheat S. Barley W. Wheat S. Barley
Autumn Spring Spring

0+ 63 50 0 + 63 50

0 + 126 100 0 + 126 100

0 + 189 150 0 + 189 150

63 + 189 . 200 63 + 189 200

Standard applications:

W. wheat: Manures: (0:20:20) at 310 kg, combine drilled. Weedkillers:
Glyphosate at 1.7 kg in 250 1, Isoproturon at 2.1 1 in 280 1.
Mecoprop, bromoxynil and foxynil ('Brittox' at 3.5 1 in 280 1).
Insecticide: Demeton-s-methyl at 0.21 kg in 300 1.

S. barley: Manures: (0:20:20) at 300 kg, combine drilled. Weedkillers:
('Brittox' at 3.51 in 280 1). Fungicide: Tridemorph at 0.53 kg in
280 1. Ethirimol ('Milgo E' at 1.3 1 in 280 1).

Seed: W. wheat: Flanders, sown at 190 kg. ’
S. barley: Georgie, dressed with ethirimol, sown at 160 kg.
Cultivations, etc.:- v

All plots: Ploughed: 24 Sept, 1979. Dazomet applied and all plots rotary
cultivated: 25 Sept.

MW. wheat: Glyphosate applied: 13 Sept, 1979. Spring-tine cultivated with
crumbler attached: 24 Oct. Seed sown: 13 Nov. Autumn N applied: 19
Nov. Isoproturon applied: 12 Apr, 1980. Spring N and 'Brittox'
applied: 15 Apr. Insecticide applied: 5 July. Combine harvested: 26
Aug.

S. barley: Heavy spring-tine cultivated: 3 Mar, 1980, 24 Mar, 9 Apr.
Rotary cultivated, seed sown: 10 Apr. N applied: 15 Apr. ‘SBrittox'
and tridemorph applied: 16 May. Ethirimol applied: 5 June. Combine
harvested: 22 Aug.

89
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1981</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[81/W/RN/13
INTENSIVE CEREALS

Object: To study the effects of intensive cereal cropping on yield,

incidence of soil-borne pathogens and organic matter in the soil .

- Woburn Stackyard I.
Sponsors: A.E. Johnston, J. McEwen.
The 16th year, w. wheat, ley.
For previous years see 'Details' 1973 and 74-80/W/RN/13.
Treatments:-

Until 1977 the experiment tested all phases of the five-course rotation
ley, potatoes, cereal, cereal, cereal and continuous cereal. From 1977 to
1980 all phases were cropped with cereal. The experiment was in two
halves, one in which the cereal was w. wheat, sown on part of the site of
the classical wheat experiment 1877-1954 and one in which the cereal was s.
barley, sown on part of the site of the classical barley experiment
1877-1954, From 1981 the experiment is being used to establish leys of
different durations for test on w. wheat in 1987. Plots not in ley are
sown to w. wheat on both halves of the experiment.

The following crop sequences are planned:-

1981 82 83 84 85 86 87
w(5) N W W W L WN
W(5) W W W L L WN
W(6) W W L L L w
w(7) w L L L L N
W(8) L L L L L WV
L L L L L L N
L = clover/grass ley w = w. wheat (5)etc = number of years continuous
cereal

NOTE: Yields are not taken in the period 1981-86.

Standard applications:

W. wheat: Manures: Chalk at 7.5 t. (10:23:23) at 280 kg. N at 150 kg
as 'Nitro-Chalk'. MWeedkillers: Glyphosate at 1.5 1 in 280 1.
Chlortoluron at 4.5 1 in 300 1. Mecoprop with bromoxynil and ioxynil
(as 'Brittox' at 2.4 1) in 280 1. Fungicide: Triadimefon with
captafol (as ‘'Bayleton CF' at 2.0 kg) in 280 1.

1st year ley: Manures: Chalk at 7.5 t. (10:23:23) at 300 kg. N at 65 kg
as 'Nitro-Chalk'. Weedkiller: Glyphosate at 1.5 1 in 280 1.

Seed: W. wheat: Flanders, sown at 190 kg.
Ley: S23 perennial ryegrass at 31 kg, Blanca white clover at 8 kg,
mixture sown at 39 kg.
88
81/W/RN/13
Cultivations, etc.:~
W. wheat: Glyphosate applied: 9 Sept, 1980. Chalk applied: 11 Sept.
Ploughed: 16 Sept. Spring-tine cultivated: 25 Sept. Spring-tine
cultivated with crumbler attached, rotary cultivated after barley
only: 30 Sept. Seed sown: 1 Oct. Chlortoluron applied: 3 Oct. N
applied: 10 Apr, 1981. 'Brittox' applied: 22 Apr. Fungicide
applied: 20 June. Combine harvested: 19 Aug.
1st year ley: Glyphosate applied: 9 Sept, 1980. Chalk applied: 11 Sept.
Ploughed: 16 Sept. Spring-tine cultivated, NPK applied: 25 Sept.
Seeds sown: 26 Sept. N applied: 7 May, 1981. Cut: 11 June, 8 Sept.
89
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1982</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[82/W/RN/13
INTENSIVE CEREALS
Object: To study the effects of intensive cereal cropping on yield,
incidence of soil-borne pathogens.and organic matter in the soil

- Woburn Stackyard I.

Sponsors: A.E. Johnston, J. McEwen.

The 17th year, w. wheat, ley.

For previous years see ‘Details’ 1973 and 74-81/W/RN/13.
Treatments: -

Until 1977 the experiment tested all phases of the five-course rotation
ley, potatoes, cereal, cereal, cereal and continuous cereal. From 1977 to
1980 al) phases were cropped with cereal. The experiment was in two
halves, one in which the cereal was w. wheat, sown on part of the site of
the classical wheat experiment 1877-1954 and one fn which the cereal was
s. barley, sown on part of the site of the classical barley experiment
1877-1954. From 1981 the experiment is being used to establish leys of
different durations for test on w. wheat in 1987. Plots not in Tey are
sown to w. wheat on both halves of the experiment.

The following crop sequences are being followed:

1981 82 83 84 85 86 87
W(5) W W w N L w
W(s) W W Ww L L W
W(6) W w L L L w
W(7) W L L L L W
W(8) L L L L L N
L L L L L L ®
L = clover/grass ley W = w. wheat (5)etc = number of years continuous
cereal
NOTE: Yields are not taken in the period 1981-86.
Standard applications:
W. wheat: Manures: (10:23:23) at 280 kg, N at 150 kg as 'Nitro-Chalk'.
Weedkillers: Glyphosate at 1.5 kg in 280 1, chlortoluron at 3.5 kg in
280 1.

1st year, clover/grass ley: Manures: (10:23:23) at 280 kg. WN at 40 kg

as 'Nitro-Chalk'.

Weedkiller: Glyphosate at 1.5 kg in 280 1.

2nd year, clover/grass ley: Manures: (0:14:28) at 490 kg.

Seed: W. wheat: Avalon, sown at 190 kg.
Ley: S23 perennial ryegrass at 31 kg, Blanca white clover at 8 kg,
mixture sown at 39 kg.
Cultivations, etc.:-
W. wheat: Glyphosate applied: 16 Sept, 1981. Ploughed: 25 Sept. NPK
applied: 29 Sept. Spring-tine cultivated with crumbler attached:
7 Oct. Seed sown: 3 Oct. Chlortoluron applied: 15 Oct. N applied:
14 Apr, 1982. Combine harvested: 3 Aug.
77
82/W/RN/13
1st year ley: Glyphosate applied: 16 Sept, 1981. Ploughed: 25 Sept.
NPK applied: 29 Sept. Spriag=tine cultivated with crumbler
attached: 7 Oct, 15 Apr, 1982, 19 Apr. Seeds sown: 29 Apr. Topped:
16 June, N applied: 23 June. Cut: 13 July.
2nd year ley: PK applied: 8 Feb, 1982. Cut: 13 July.
78
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1983</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[83/N/RN/13
INTENSIVE CEREALS
Object: To study the effects of intensive cereal cropping on yield,
incidence of soil-borne pathogens and organic matter in the soil

- Woburn Stackyard I.

Sponsors: A.E. Johnston, J. McEwen. .

The 18th year, w. wheat, ley.

For previous years see 'Details' 1973 and 74-82/W/RN/13.
Treatments: -

Until 1977 the experiment tested all phases of the five-course rotation
ley, potatoes, cereal, cereal, cereal and continuous cereal. From 1977 to
1980 all phases were cropped with cereal. The experiment was in two
halves, one in which the cereal was w. wheat, sown on part of the site of
the classical wheat experiment 1877-1954 and one in which the cereal was
s. barley, sown on part of the site of the classical barley experiment
1877-1954, From 1981 the experiment is being used to establish leys of
different durations for test on w. wheat in 1987. Plots not in ley are
sown to w. wheat on both halves of the experiment.

The following crop sequences are being followed:

1981 82 83 84 85 86 87
W(5) N N W Ww L W
W(5) N WN N L L Ww
W(6) W W L L L Ww
N(7) N L L L L ¥
W(8) L L L L L W
L L L L L L W
L = clover/grass ley WN = w. wheat (5)etc = number of years continuous
cereal
NOTE: Yields are not taken in the period 1981-86.
Standard applications:
W. wheat: Manures: (5:14:30) at 340 kg, N at 150 kg as 'Nitro-Chalk'.
Weedkillers: Mecoprop with bromoxynil and foxynil (as 'Brittox' at
3.5 1) with the fungicide in 280 1. Fungicide: Prochloraz at 0.4 kg.
Ley, 1st year: Manures: (5:14:30) at 340 kg, N at 50 kg as 'Nitro-
Chalk'. Weedkiller: Paraquat at 0.84 kg fon in 280 1.
Ley, 2nd and 3rd years: Manures: (0:18:36) at 380 kg.
Seed: W. wheat: Avalon, sown at 190 kg.
Ley: S 23 perennial ryegrass at 27 kg, Blanca white clover at 7 kg,
mixture sown at 34 kg.
85
B83/W/RN/13
Cultivations, etc.:-

NW. wheat: Ploughed: 20 Sept, 1982, Spring-tine cul tivated: 28 Sept.
NPK applied: 30 Sept. Rotary cultivated, seed sown: 1 Oct.
Weedkillers and fungicide applied: 15 Apr, 1983. N applied: 28 Apr.
Combine harvested: 5 Aug.

Ley, 1st year: Ploughed: 20 Sept, 1982. Spring-tine cultivated:

28 Sept. NPK applied: 30 Sept. Spring-tine cultivated: 8 Mar, 1983.
N applied, rotary cultivated: 17 Mar. Weedkiller applied: 16 May.
Rotary cultivated: 7 June. Seed sown: 9 June. Cut: 15 Aug.
Ley, 2nd and 3rd years: PK applied: 11 Jan, 1983. Cut: 21 June, 15 Aug.
86
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1984</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[84/W/RN/13
INTENSIVE CEREALS
Object: To study the effects of intensive cereal cropping on yield,
incidence of soil-borne pathogens and organic matter in the soil
- Woburn Stackyard I.
Sponsors: A.E. Johnston, J. McEwen.
The 19th year, w. wheat, ley.
For previous years see ‘Details’ 1973 and 74-83/W/RN/13.
Treatments: = ’
Until 1977 the experiment tested all phases of the five-course rotation
ley, potatoes, cereal, cereal, cereal and continuous cereal. From 1977 to
1980 all phases were cropped with cereal. The experiment was in two
halves, one in which the cereal was w. wheat, sown on part of the site of
the classical wheat experiment 1877-1954 and one in which the cereal was
s. barley, sown on part of the site of the classical barley experiment
1877-1954. From 1981 the experiment is being used to establish leys of
different durations for test on w. wheat in 1987, Plots not in ley are
sown to w. wheat on both halves of the experiment.
The following crop sequences are being followed:
1981 82 83 84 85 86 87
(5) w w W N L W
W(5) W N W L L W
W(6) W W L L L W
w(7) w L L L L W
” w(8) L L L L L W
L L L L L L W
L = clover/grass ley W = w. wheat (5)etc = number of years continuous
cereal
NOTE: Yields are not taken in the period 1981-86.
Standard applications:
W. wheat: Manures: (5:14:30) at 340 kg, N at 140 kg as 'Nitro-Chalk',
Weedkiller: Chlortoluron at 3.5 kg in 250 1.
Ley, lst year: Manures: (5:14:30) at 340 kg, N at 50 kg as ‘Nitro-
Chalk'.
Ley, 2nd, 3rd and 4th years: Manures: (0:18:36) at 380 kg.
Seed: W. wheat: Avalon, sown at 200 kg.
Ley: S 23 perennial ryegrass at 27 kg, Blanca white clover at 7 kg,
mixture sown at 34 kg.
90
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1985</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[85/N/RN/13
INTENSIVE CEREALS
Object: To study the effects of intensive cereal cropping on
yield, incidence of soil-borne pathogens and organic matter in
the sofl - Woburn Stackyard I.
Sponsors: ALE, Johnston, J. McEwen.
The 20th year, w, wheat, ley.
For previous years see ‘Details’ 1973 and 74-84/N/RN/13.
Treatments:-
Until 1977 the experiment tested all phases of the five-
course rotation ley, potatoes, cereal, cereal, cereal and
continous cereal, From 1977 to 1980 all phases were cropped with
cereal. The experiment was in two halves, one in which the
cereal was w. wheat, sown on part of the site of the classical
wheat experiment 1877-1954 and one in which the cereal was
s. barley, sown on part of the site of the classical barley
experiment 1877-1954, From 1981 the experiment is being used to
establish leys of different durations for tests on w. wheat in
1987. Plots not in ley are sown to w. wheat on both halves of
the experiment,
The following crop sequences are being followed:
1981 82 83 84 85 86 87
W(5) N W W MW L W
W(5) W W W L L W
W(6) N W L L L W
W(7) w L L i L W
N(8) L L L L L W
L L L L k L w
L = clover/grass ley W = w, wheat (5)etc = number of years
continous cereal
NOTE: Yields are not taken in the period 1981-86.
Standard applications:
W. wheat: Manures: (5:14:30) at 340 kg. N at 80 kg followed
by N at 70 kg, as ‘Nitro-Chalk' (27.5% N). Weedkillers: Mecoprop
at 1.2 kg with bromoxynil at 0.3 kg and ioxynil at 0.3 kg in
250 1, Fungicides: Propiconazole on two occasions at 0.25 kg in
250 1 on the first occasion and at 0,12 kg in 250 1 on the second
occasion with carbendazim and maneb (as 'Septal' at 2.5 kg).
Ley, 1st year: Manures: (5:14:30) at 340 kg. N at 50 kg as
'Nitro-Chalk' (27.5% N).
Ley, 2nd, 3rd, 4th and 5th years: Manures: (0:18:36) at 380 kg.
Seed: W, wheat: Avalon, sown at 160 kg.
Ley: 523 perennial ryegrass at 27 kg, Blanca white clover
at 7 kg, mixture sown at 34 kg.
81
85/W/RN/13
Cultivations, etc.:-

W. wheat: Ploughed: 3 Oct, 1984, NPK applied, spring-tine
cultivated, seed sown: 9 Oct, N applied: 15 Apr, 1985,

24 Apr. Meedkillers applied: 16 May. Propiconazole
applied: 17 June, 2 July. ‘'Septal' applied: 2 July.
Combine harvested: 2 Sept.

Ley, 1st year: Ploughed: 3 Oct, 1984, Spring-tine cultivated:
22 Apr, 1985, N applied: 24 Apr. NPK applied: 25 Apr.
Spring-tine cultivated with crumbler attached, seeds sown:
1 May. Cut: 20 Nov.

Ley, 2nd, 3rd, 4th and 5th years: PK applied: 25 Jan, 1985. Chain
harrowed: 12 Apr. Cut: 1 July, 20 Nov.

82
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1986</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[86/W/RN/13
INTENSIVE CEREALS

Object: To study the effects of intensive cereal cropping on
yield, incidence of soil-borne pathogens and organic matter in
the soil - Woburn Stackyard I.

Sponsors: A.E. Johnston, J. McEwen.

The 21st year, ley.

For previous years see ‘Details' 1973 and 74-85/W/RN/13.

Treatments: Until 1977 the experiment tested all phases of the five-
course rotation ley, potatoes, cereal, cereal, cereal and continous
cereal, From 1977 to 1980 all phases were cropped with cereal. The
experiment was in two halves, one in which the cereal was w. wheat,
sown on part of the site of the classical wheat experiment 1877-1954
and one in which the cereal was s. barley, sown on part of the site
of the classical barley experiment 1877-1954. From 1981 the
experiment is being used to establish leys of different durations for
tests on w, wheat in 1987. Plots not in ley were sown to w. wheat
on both halves of the experiment.

The following crop sequences are being followed:

1981 82 83 84 85 86 87

ue N N W W L W

N(5 W W W L L W

w(6) W W L L L W

(7) W L L L L W

N(8) L L L L L W

L L L L L L W

L = clover/grass ley W = w, wheat (5)etc = number of years
continous cereal

NOTE: Yields are not taken in the period 1981-86.

Standard applications:

Ley, 1st year: Manures: N at 50 kg as 'Nitro-Chalk'., (5:14:30) at
340 kg.
Ley, 2nd, 3rd, 4th, 5th and 6th years: Manures: (0:18:36) at 400 kg.

Seeds: $23 perennial ryegrass at 27 kg, Blanca white clover at 7 kg,

mixture sown at 34 kg.
78
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1987</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[87/W/RN/13

Standard applications: Manures: (0:18:36) at 560 kg. Mn at 0,16 kg as
manganese sulphate in 240 ) applied with the prochloraz, carbendazim
and growth regulator. Weedkillers: Glyphosate at 1.4 kg in 200 1,
Chlortoluron at 5.6 kg in 200 1. Clopyralid at 0.07 kg, bromoxynil
at 0,34 kg with mecoprop at 2.5 kg in 240 1. Fungicides: Prochloraz
at 0.34 kg with carbendazim at 0.13 kg. Fenpropimorph at 0.75 kg
with chlorothalonil at 0.75 kg in 200 1, Propiconazole at 0.12 kg
with carbendazim and maneb (as 'Septal' at 2.5 kg) in 200 1, Growth
regulator: Chlormequat at 1.1 kg. Insecticide: Carbofuran at 7.5 kg.
Molluscicide: Methiocarb at 0.22 kg.

Seed: Mercia, sown at 190 kg.

Cultivations, etc,:- Ploughed and rolled: 17 July, 1986. Subsoiled with
25 cm wings on tines 30 cm deep and 70 ¢m apart, in two directions at
right angles: 28 Aug. Glyphosate applied: 16 Sept. Methiocarb
applied: 18 Sept. PK applied, carbofuran applied, rotary harrowed
with crumbler attached, seed sown: 25 Sept. Chlortoluron applied:

9 Oct. Mn, prochloraz, carbendazim, chlormequat applied: 14 Apr,
1987. Clopyralid, bromoxynil and mecoprop applied subsequently:
14 Apr. N applied: 23 Apr. Fenpropimorph and chlorothalonil
applied: 5 June. Propiconazole, carbendazim and maned applied:
29 June, Combine harvested: 1 Sept.

GRAIN TONNES/HECTARE

*xkxx Tables Of means *****

N 0 50 100 150 200 250 Mean
LEY AGE
1 YEAR 4.86 6.33 7.94 7.96 7.99 8.51 7.27
2 YEARS 5.82 8.22 8.73 8.87 9,01 9,08 8.29
3 YEARS 7.72 8.60 8.85 9.36 9.18 9.36 8.84
4 YEARS 8.37 8.94 8.85 9.28 9.43 8.96 8.97
5 YEARS 8.37 8.94 8.85 9.28 9.06 9.22 8.95
6 YEARS 8.24 8.63 8.62 8.77 8.16 8.99 8.57
Mean 7.23 8.28 8.64 8.92 8.81 9.02 8.48
*** Standard errors of differences of means ***
Table LEY AGE N LEY AGE ;
N
s.e.d. 0.271 0.158 0.445
Except when comparing means with the same level(s) of
LEY AGE 0.387

*xw*x Stratum standard errors and coefficients of variation *****

Stratum d.f. s.e. cv .

BLOCK WP 15 0.383 4.5

BLOCK WP. SP 90 0.547 6.5

GRAIN MEAN DMX 82.6

SUB PLOT AREA HARVESTED 0.00165

69
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1988</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[88/W/RN/13
INTENSIVE CEREALS

Object: To study the effects of leys of different duration, following
prolonged intensive cereal cropping, on a sequence of arable crops
= Woburn Stackyard I.

Sponsors: A.E. Johnston, J. McEwen.

The 23rd year, potatoes.

For previous years see ‘Details’ 1973 and 74-87/W/RN/13.

Design: 4 randomised blocks of 6 plots split into 6.

Treatments: Until 1977 the experiment tested all phases of the five-
course rotation: ley, potatoes, cereal, cereal, cereal and continous
cereal. From 1977 to 1980 all phases were cropped with cereal. The
experiment was in two halves, one in which the cereal was w. wheat,
sown on part of the site of the classical continuous wheat experiment
1877-1954 and one in which the cereal was s. barley, sown on part of
the site of the classical continuous barley experiment 1877-1954.
From 1981 the experiment was used to establish grass/clover leys of
different durations for tests on w. wheat in 1987. Plots not in ley
were sown to w. wheat on both halves of the experiment. All leys
were ploughed for 1987 and the site sown to w. wheat. This was
followed in 1988 by potatoes testing all combinations of the
following treatments:

Whole plots

1. LEY AGE Length of ley (until ploughing in summer 1986):

1 YEAR

2 YEARS

3 YEARS

4 YEARS

5 YEARS

6 YEARS

Sub plots

2. N Nitrogen fertilizer in 1988 (kg N) as ‘Nitro-Chalk’:

0
70
140
210
280
350

Basal applications: Manures: (0:18:36) at 1400 kg. Mg at 100 kg as
kieserite. Weedkillers: Glyphosate at 1.4 kg in 200 1. Linuron at
1.5 kg in 220 1. Fungicides: Mancozeb at 1.4 kg in 220 1 on five
occasions, applied with the pirimicarb on the first, second and
fifth. Fentin hydroxide at 0.28 kg in 220 1. Nematicide: Oxamyl at
5.0 kg. Insecticide: Pirimicarb at 0.14 Xg on three occasions.
Desiccant: Diquat at 0.80 kg ion in 400 1.

65 s
88/W/RN/13
Seed: Pentland Crown.
Cultivations, etc.:- Glyphosate applied: 22 Sept, 1987. Ploughed:
22 Feb, 1988. Heavy spring-tine cultivated: 5 Apr. PK applied:
8 Apr. N treatments applied, oxamyl applied, spring-tine cultivated:
20 Apr. Mg applied, rotary harrowed, potatoes planted: Zl Apr.
Rotary ridged, linuron applied: 13 May. Mancozeb applied: 15 July
and 1 Aug. Mancozeb applied with pirimicarb: 14 June, 5 July and
15 Aug. Fentin hydroxide applied: 30 Aug. Desiccant applied:
15 Sept. Haulm mechanically destroyed: 29 Sept. Potatoes lifted:
26 Oct.
TOTAL TUBERS TONNES/HECTARE
ks%4+ Tables of means *****
N 0 70 140 210 280 350 Mean
LEY AGE
1 YEAR 37.5 52.6 64.6 60.4 59.4 62.9 56.2
2 YEARS 41.9 57.8 66.2 59.9 64.5 63.3 58.9
3 YEARS 44.9 59.9 64.7 67.6 65.8 63.4 61.0
4 YEARS 46.8 58.1 66.0 67.6 67.9 62.9 61.5
5 YEARS 43.6 61.1 68.6 75.8 69.1 64.9 63.9
6 YEARS 47.5 66.5 64.2 71.1 65.8 67.9 63.8
Mean 43.7 59.3 65.7 67.1 65.4 64.2 60.9
s#+ Standard errors of differences of means ***
LEY AGE N LEY AGE
N
2.08 1.73 4.40
Except when comparing means with the same level(s) of
LEY AGE 4.25
»xaxxx Stratum standard errors and coefficients of variation #a#»»
Stratum d.f. s.e. cvi
BLOCK. WP 15 2.94 4.8
BLOCK.WP. SP 90 6.01 9.9
66
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1989</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[89/W/RN/13

NOTE: Because of an error twelve sub plots from four whole plots were
not sown with the rest of the experiment, These had the
combinations LEY AGE 1 YEAR with N 50, 100 and 250,
LEY AGE 4 YEARS with N 50, 100 and 150 and LEY AGE 5 YEARS with
N 0, 50, 100 (from two separate whole plots), 150 and 250. They
were sown to w. wheat later on two occasions but failed and were
re-sown to s. wheat. Yields from these plots were not recorded.
Estimated values were used in the analysis.

Basal applications: Manures: Dolomite at 5S t. (0:18:36) at 556 kg.
Manganese at 0,096 kg Mn as a foliar spray in 220 1 applied twice.
Weedkillers: Mecoprop at 2.5 kg with bromoxynil at 0.34 kg and
clopyralid at 0.07 kg in 220 1. Metsulfuron-methyl at 6.0 g in
220 1 to s. wheat only. Fungicides: Prochloraz at 0.40 kg with
carbendazim at 0.15 kg applied with the growth regulator in 220 1.
pPropiconazole at 0.12 kg in 220 1, Fenpropimorph at 0.75 kg with
maneb at 1.6 kg and carbendazim at 0.25 kg in 220 1. Molluscicide:
Methiocarb at 0.20 Xg. Nematicide: Carbofuran at 7.5 kg. Growth
regulator: Chlormequat chloride at 1.6 kg.

Seed: W. wheat: Mercia, with methiocarb pellets, sown at 165 kg —- omitted

plots sown at 180 kg.
S. wheat: Alexandria, sown at 180 kg.

Cultivations, ete.:- Ploughed: 28 Oct, 1988. Dolomite applied,
methiocarb applied: 29 Oct. PK applied: 31 Oct. Carbofuran applied
and cultivated in: 1 Nov. Spike harrowed with crumbler attached,
seed sown: 2 Nov, Omitted plots sown: 13 Dec. Omitted plots spring-
tine cultivated: 6 Feb, 1989. Omitted plots re-sown: 7 Feb. Omitted
plots harrowed and sown to s. wheat: 31 Mar. Mecoprop, bromoxynil
and clopyralid applied: 28 Apr. Mn applied: 29 Apr and 22 May. WN
applied: 3 May. Prochloraz and growth regulator applied: 17 May.
Propiconazole applied: 5 June. Metsulfuron-methyl applied to
s. wheat: 13 June. Fenpropimorph, maneb and carbendazim applied:

3 July. Combine barvested: 7 hug.
54
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1990</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[90/W/RN/13
INTENSIVE CEREALS

Object: To study the effects of leys of different duration, following
prolonged intensive cereal cropping, on a sequence of arable crops
= Woburn Stackyard I.

Sponsor: J. McEwen.

The 25th year, w. beans.

For previous years see ‘Details’ 1973 and 74-89/W/RN/13.

Design: 4 randomised blocks of 6 plots split into 6.

Treatments: Until 1977 the experiment tested all phases of the five-
course rotation: ley, potatoes, cereal, cereal, cereal and continous
cereal. From 1977 to 1980 all phases were cropped with cereal. The
experiment was in two halves, one in which the cereal was w. wheat,
sown on part of the site of the classical continuous wheat experiment
1877-1954 and one in which the cereal was s. barley, sown on part of
the site of the classical continuous barley experiment 1877-1954.
From 1981 the experiment was used to establish grass/clover leys of
different durations for tests on w. wheat in 1987. Plots not in ley
were sown to w. wheat on both halves of the experiment. All leys
were ploughed for 1987 and the site sown to w. wheat. This was
followed by potatoes in 1988, w. wheat in 1989, and by w. beans in
1990, testing all combinations of the following treatments:

whole plots

1. LEY AGE Length of ley (until ploughing in summer 1986):

1 YEAR
2 YEARS
3 YEARS
4 YEARS
5 YEARS
6 YEARS
Sub plots
2. N RES Residues of nitrogen fertilizer to w. wheat in 1989
(kg N):
0)
(50)
(100)
(150)
(200)
(250)

Basal applications: Manures: (0:24:24) at 420 kg. Muriate of potash at
170 kg. Manganese at 0.19 kg in 220 1. wWeedkillers: Paraquat at
0.80 kg ion in 220 1. Propyzamide at 0.85 kg with simazine at
0.85 kg in 220 1. Fungicide: Fenpropimorph at 0.75 kg in 220 1.
Insecticide: Deltamethrin at 7.5 g in 220 1 applied on two occasions.

LY
90/W/RN/13

Seed: Banner sown at 18 seeds per square metre.

Cultivations, etc.:- Subsoiled with tines 50 cm apart and 40 cm deep:
15 Sept, 1989. PK and K applied: 19 Sept. Paraquat applied: 10 Oct.
Disced: 11 Oct. Seed broadcast by drill, ploughed in and rolled:

12 Oct. Propyzamide and simazine applied: 15 Oct. Mn applied:
S Apr, 1990. Deltamethrin applied: 23 Apr and 18 May. Fenpropimorph
applied: 11 July. Combine harvested: 11 Aug.

GRAIN TONNES/HECTARE

axsA* Tables of means **#*#*

N RES 0) (50) (100) (150) (200) (250) Mean
LEY AGE
1 YEAR 4.41 4.12 4.26 3.80 3.42 4.35 4.06
2 YEARS 4.96 4.17 4.48 4.03 4.87 5.06 4.60
3 YEARS 5.11 4.41 4.46 4.81 4.51 4.35 4.61
4 YEARS 5.02 4.11 4.62 4.51 4.31 4.51 4.51
5 YEARS 5.33 5.09 41.81 5.18 4.50 4.68 4.93
6 YEARS 4.83 4.58 4.55 4.47 4.23 4.41 4.51
Mean 4,94 4.41 4.53 4.47 4.31 4.56 4.54
*+# Standard errors of differences of means **~
LEY AGE N RES LEY AGE
N RES
0.270 0.148 0.428
Except when comparing means with the same level(s) of
LEY AGE 0.364

ass#% Stratum standard errors and coefficients of variation ****=

Stratum d.£. s.e. cvi

BLOCK.WP 15 0.382 8.4

BLOCK. WP, SP 90 0.514 11.3

GRAIN MEAN DM% 89.9

SUB PLOT AREA HARVESTED 0.00132

53
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
</reports>