<reports>
<report>
<year>1959</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[59/4/91
WHEAT AND BARLEY - WOBURN STACKYARD 1959

For history, treatments, etc., see "Details of the Classical and Long
Term Experiments" 1956,

Strip cropping 1959: To investigate the residual effects of early
manures, winter wheat and spring barley were sown in strips across
these two experiments, Yields were estimated from sample combine
cuts,

Cultivations, etc,: The site of the Continuous Wheat was ploughed on
May 28 and Sept 26, 1958 and that of the Continuous Barley on May 27
and Oct 28,

Wheat: Seed drilled at 3 bushels per acre: Dec 5, 'Nitra-Shell'(20.5%N)
applied at 45 cwt per acre: Mar 25, 1959. Sprayed with
TCB/MCPA at 4 pints in 40 gallons per acre: hpr 29, Combine
harvested: Aug 20. Variety: Squarehcad's Master 13/4.

Barley: Seed drilled at 3 bushels per acre: Mar 16, 1959.
'Nitre-Shell' (20.57 N) applied at LF owt per acre: Mer 25. Sprayed
with TCB/MCPA at 4 pints in 40 gallons per acre: May 11.
Combine harvested: Aug 19. Variety: Flumage Archer.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1960</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[60/h/841
WHEAT AND BARLEY, AND BARLEY AND POTATOES MICROFLOTS -
WOBURN STACKYLRD 1960
For history, treatments, etc,, see "Details of the Classical and Long
Tem Experiments" 1956.
Strip cropping end microplots 1960: Wheat and berley were sown in
5 strips as in 25 except that on the south cesterm of the 3
~¢, A= blocks of each of the old experiments, the barley strip was
C\¢ replaced by 2 strips, one of potatoes, one of barley, for micro-
plot tests of P end K fertilisers.
Aree of cech mpin plot (acres): Area harvested (acres):
10a - 11b 0.0274 0.0206
Remeinder 0.0411 0.0234
Aree of each microplot (acres): Area harvested (acres):
11a and 11b 0.0034 Barley - 0.0019
Potatoes = 0.0014
Remainder 0.0026 Berley = 0.0013
Potatoes - 0.0010
Trectments (to microplots only). Certein combinations of:- 2?
Superchosphete:~ None, 0.25 (8), 1.0 (F) owt P0 per acre
(barley and potatoes).
Sulphate of potashi- None, 0.15 (X,), 0.6 (x,) owt K,0 per ecre
Pan 1
Sight of potash:- None, 0.30 (K;), 1.2 (Kg) owt K,0 per acre
tn
Flots 11a and 11b being narrower than the rest were divided into 4
microplots each instead of 16 and carried tests of K only
(continuous wheat site) or P only (continuous barley site).
Basal dressings per acre:
To wheat and berley:- 0.9 cwt N as 'Nitro-Chalk'.
To microplots:-
Pototoes: 1.2 cwt N as 'Nitro-Chalk'.
Barley: 0.6 cwt N as 'Nitro-Chalk'.
Cultivations, etcs: Ground chalk applied to whole area at 11 cwt
per aero: Scpt 10, 1559.
Wheat: Peruancnt wheat site ploughed: Sept 11.
Permanent barley site ploughed: Sept 15. Seed drilled at
3 bushels per acre: Oct 22, 1959. ‘Nitro-Chalk' applied:
Mer 21, 1960. Sprayed with DNOC at 2 gallons in 8 gallons
per acre: May 3. Combine harvested: Aug 31. Variety:
Squarehead's Master 13/4.
Barley: Floughed 2nd time: Nov 12 = 23, 1959. Seed drilled
at 2% bushels per acre; 'Nitro-Chalk' applied: Mar 21, 1960.
Sprayed with TCB/MCPA at 4 pints in 40 gellons per acre:
Mey 23. Combine harvested: Aug 30. Variety: Flumage Archer.
60//842
Microplots.,

Potatoes: Ploughed 2nd time: Nov 12 - 23, 1955. Basel N, besal
and treetment P and K applied on the flat: Apr 21, 1960.
Potatoes planted by machine: Apr 22, Blanks in rows plented
with chitted seed: Moy 27. Earthed up: June 13. Lifted:
Sept 19. Variety: Majestic.

Barley: Basal and treatment P and K applied: Mar 22, 1960.

Basal N spplied, seed drilled at 23 bushels per acre: Mar 23.
Sprayed with TCB/MCPA at 4 pints in 40 gellons per acre: Mey 23.
Harvested: aug 10. Veriety: Plumage Archer.
Swmery of Results
Y Main plots
Crop in 1960 | Wheat Barley
Crop in old Continuous Continuous | Continuous Continuous
scheme ; wheat barley wheat barley
Grain (at 857 dry matter): cwt ver acre
Plot 1 i 12.2 24.9 21,3 17.9
2 947 2.2 1544 16.9
3 20.0 274 20.4 16.0
4 15.1 21.9 21.9 19.2
5 15.0 24.0 23.0 19.0
6 20.2 25.9 2.7 23.5
7 20.9 27.3
8 20.3 27.2
9 23.7 27.6
10a 19.3 25.9 19.6 20.4
10b 20.3 24.5 18.7 1747
11a. 25.3 24.9 20.9 21.9
11b 25.7 2.5 22,5 21.8
Strew (at 85% dry matter): cwt per acre
Flot 1 26.4 29.3 i 18.4 13.5
2 1846 25.9 12,8 13.3
3 22.9 4 15.1 12.4
4 26.9 23.0 18.1 13.3
5 19.2 26.7 17.3 12.9
6 22.8 31.2 17.5 15.6
7 23.5 34.7
8 20.3 42
9 29.3 47 ob
10a 22.0 34.8 11.2 13.6
10b 26.8 33a 10.3 11.6
. 11a | + + 13.5 143
11% | 32.4 Llat 15.2 13.3
Mean dry matter © as harvested: Grain 76,6 78.7
Straw 84.5 83.9
+ Not recorded.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1961</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[61/4/842
Cultivations, etc,:

Wheats Ploughed: Sept 26, 1960, Seed drilled at 3 bushels per
acre: Jan 17, 1961, Winter wheat ploughed in owing to bird
damage: Mar 21, 'Nitro-Chalk' applied, seed drilled at 3
bushels per acre: Mar 22, Sprayed with MCPA/TEA at 4 pints

. in 40 gellons per acre: May 9. Corbine harvested: Aug 28.
Variety: Jufy I.

Barley: Floughed twice: Sept 27, 1950 and Feb 10, 1561.
'Nitro-Chalk' applied, seed drilled at 3 bushels per acre:

Mar 9, Sprayed with MCEL/TBA at 4 pints in 40 gellons per
acre: Mey 9. Corbine harvested: Aug 28, Variety:
Plunsge Archer.

Microplots. Basel FK and ploughed in treatment fertilisers
applied: Jan 2, 1961, Plots ploughed: Jan 25.

Potatoes: Basal N and broadcast treatment fertilisers applied
on the flat, chitted seed planted by machine: Mar 22, 1561.
Spreyed twice with demeton methyl at 12 fluid oz in 40
wellons per acre: June 6 and July 11. Sprayed twice with
copper fungicide at 5 1b in 40 gallons per acre: Aug 18 and
Aug 31, Lifted: Scpt 21, Variety: Majestic,

Barley: Basel N and broadcast trectment fertilisers applied,
sced drilled at 2% bushels per acre: Mar 9, 1961, Harvoated:
Aug 10, Variety: Plumage Archer,

Sugar beet: Basal N and broadcest treatment fertilisers applied,
seed drilled at 12 1b per acre: Apr 12, 1961. Lifted:

Oct 16, Veriety: Klein E,
Erratum to "Results of the Field Experiments" 1960,
Paze 60/h/8s1 the 4th line should rend "strips as in 1959 «.. "
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1962</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[62/h/941
OATS, AND MICROPLOTS, SITES OF CONTINUOUS
WHEAT AND BARLEY EXPERIMENTS
WOBURN STACKYARD 1962

For history, treatments, etc,, see "Details of the Classical and Long
Term Experiments" 1956.

In 1962 the sites were sown with oats except for the areas occupied
by microplots in 1961 and 1962,

Microplots 1962, Microplots with treatments similer to those of 1961
were laid dom on perts of plots 7, 8 and 9 of the Continuous
Wheat site; the area used for microplots in 1961 was bare fallow
in 1962, Crop sequences were as follows:- .

1960 1961 1962
Wintergsheat Fallow Sugar begt®
Barley % Fallow Potatogs
Potatoes Fallow Barley

* zi croplots.

On potatoes and barley the residual effects of the 1960 treatments
P,, Ki and K8 were measured, the plots involved receiving basel N
end K or P at appropriate rates,

Note: A strip of land across the south-east end of plot 4 of the
Continuous Barley site wes used for a microplot experiment on
soil structure, the crop being sugar beet,

Area of each main plot (acres): Ares harvested (acres):

10a - 110 0.0274 0.0106 =~ 0,020
Remainder 0.0411 0,0097 - 0.0236

Area of each microplot 0.0026 acres, Area harvested (oores): Potatoes -
0.0010, barley - 0.0013, sugar beet - 0,0012.

Basel dressings per acre: Oats — 0.4 owt N es 'Nitro-Chalk'.
Remainder - as 1961.

CQultivations, etce:-

Oats: Ploughed: Oct 19, 1964. Seed drilled at 4 bushels per
acre, 'Nitro-Chalk' applied: Feb 24, 1962, Spreyed with
MCPA/TBA at 4 pints in 40 gellons per acre: May 15. Combine
hervested: Aug 27. Variety: Condor.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1963</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[63/A/9
FALLOWN AND MICROPLOTS, SITES OF CONTINUOUS
WHEAT AND BARLEY EXPERIMENTS
WOBURN STACKYARD 1963
(WAN and WPB)

For history, treatments, etc., see "Details of the Classical and
Long Term Experiments’ 1956,

In 1963 the sites vere falloved except for a strip of land across
the south east end of plot 6 of the Classical Barley site. This
area was used for a continuation of the 19&@ microplot experiment
on soil structure, the crop being red beet.

Cultivations, etc.: Ploughed: Nov 5, 1962. Rotary cultivated:
June 13, 1963. Plots 1-10b and 7-11b of both the Classical
experiments subsoiled to a depth of 20 {ns, 5 ft between strokes:
Sept 11, and again across the first strokes to a depth of 18 ins,
5 ft between strokes: Sept 23. Ground chalk applied at 46 cwt
per acre: Oct 21.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1964</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[6L4/a/9
SPRING BEANS, SITES OF CONTINUOUS WHEAT AND BARLEY EXPERIMENTS
WOBURN STACKYARD 1964
(WPW and WFB)

For history, treatments etc., see 'Details' 1962,

In 196k all plots were sown with spring beans, except for the area
carrying the microplot experiment on soil structure (see 'Results'
64/c/20).

Cultivations, etc.: Ploughed: Oct 22 - Nov 1, 1963. Seed drilled
at 200 1b: Mar 13, 1964. Sprayed with simazine at 1 1b in LO
gels: Apr 1. Combine harvested - continuous wheat area: Aug 26,
continuous barley area: Sept 1. Variety: Minor Tick.

SUMMARY OF RESULTS
Crop in old
scheme 1877 - 1955 Continuous wheat Continuous barley
Crop 1959 = 61 Wheat Barley Wheat Barley
BEANS, GRAIN
Plot 1 19.0 17.3 20.6 21.8
2 16.0 18.0 17.0 21.4
« °3 18.3 15.6 24.9 19.8
L 20.1 kL 18.4 16.0
5 4h 16.7 15.2 13.7
6 16.4 18.4 27.5 2L.8
T 18.3 19.2
8 19.8 27.2
9 21.2 30.2
10 ax 16.6 21.6 24.8 21.6
10 bx 20.6 19.1 2k.9 21.2
10 ay 15.9 22.6
10 by 16.4 25.2
1 ay 16.0 22.5
11 by 20.0 25.4
1 az 23.6 29.1
11 bz 28.5 29.2
Mean DM. %: 86.2
All plots: 1962 - Oats, 1963 - Fallow
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1965</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[65/A/9
FALLOJ AND MUSTARD, SITES OF CONTINUOUS WHEAT AND BARIEY EXPERIMENTS
WOBURN STACKYARD 1965
(WPW and WEB)
For history, treatments etc., see 'Details' 1962.
In 1965 all plots were fallowed, except the area carrying the micro-
Plot experiment on Soil structure (see 'Results' 65/C/1S5). Plots
7, 8, 9 and the south-easterm parts of lla and 1lb of each site,
vhich were sown to mustard as a precaution against wheat bulb fly
in preparation for the Intensive Cereals Experiment 1966.
Cultivations, etc.:
A1l plots (excluding microplot area): Ploughed: Sept 29, 1964.
Chisel ploughed: Dec 16, 1964 and Apr 27, 1965.
All plots (excluding microplot area and area to be sown to mustard):
Chisel ploughed: July 28, 1965. Ploughed: Oct 13.
Mustard: Seed broadcast, 0.42 cwt N applied as 'Nitro-Chalk':
June 28, 1965. Crop destroyed mechanically: Oct T.
Ploughed in: Oct 13.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1966</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[66/4/9
FALIOW, SITE OF CONTINUOUS WHEAT AND BARLEY EXPERIMENTS
WOBURN STACKYARD 1966
(WPW and WPB)
For history, treatments etc,, see 'Details' 1982,
In 1966 all plots were fallowed except the area carrying the micro-plot
experiment on soil structure (see 'Results' 66/C/11). Plots 7, 8,
9 and the south-eastern parts of lla and 1lb of each site are now
occupied by the Intensive Cereals Experiment (see 'Results' 66/B/9).
Cultivations, etc.: Ploughed: Oct 13, 1965. Spring-tine cultivated:
March 29, 1566, Ploughed: June 21, Spring-tine cultivated:
July 8, Aug 12,
NOTE: The Continuous Wheat and Barley Experiments are now discontinued
and there will be no further entries under this heading.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
</reports>