<reports>
<report>
<year>1964</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[' 66/C/31.2

1964, The experiment began with the sowing of the leys and green

manures (Hybrid Italian ryegrass sown at 30 lb) in spring 196),
Basel manuring:

Ic and Int 0,2 ewt N, 0.5 cwt P205, 0.5 cwt K20 in seedbed,

In only: 0.5 cwt N in spring and after each cut except the last,

Gms 0.5 cwt N, 0.5 cwt P205, 0.5 cwt K20 in seedbed,

The remaining plots were left fallow without manures. Because of
perennial weeds (grasses and Equisetum) all plots were rotery
cultivated in July.

Cultivations, etc.:

Subsoiled: Sept 23, 1963. Ploughed twice: Oct 3, 1963, and

Jan 3, 1964, Fertilisers applied: May 1. Seeds som:
May 7. Previous crops: Winter wheat 1962, spring wheat 1963.
1965. Treatment Le and In were resown (basal manuring as for 1964,
but with 0.5 cwt N in seedded for both).
Treatment Gm was resown with species end manuring as in 1964,
]]>
</rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1965</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
Cultivations, etc.

All plots: Rotary cultivated: July 2, 196% and again July 18,
Deep-tine cultivated: Aug 17. Rotary cultivated: Oct 13.
Ploughedt Nov 16, Rotary cultivated: Apr 21, 1965.

lc and ln plots: Seeds sown, seedbed fertilisers applied:

Apr 23. Sprayed with dinosebd at 1,25 lb in hO gals:
June 3. Cut twice: Aug 12, and Oct 20, ''Nitro-Chalk'
applied: Aug 20,
Gm plots: Seed sown, fertiliser applied: Apr 23.
Seeds mixtures 1964 end 1965:

le Timothy sk8 6 lb
Meadow Fescue S215 10 lb
Smooth-stalked meadow grass 4 lb
Kersey white clover 3 I
Wild white clover 1 ib

2h Ib
Sown at 24 Ib
66/C/31.3
In Timothy Sh8 8 Ib
Meadow Fescue S215 12 ld
Smooth-stalked meadow grass 6 lb
26 Id
Sown at 26 lb
]]>
</rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1966</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
1966. In autum 1965 winter wheat (Cappelle at 180 lb) was som
on all treatments except Ic and In, but it was severely daraced
by vheat bulb fly (Leptohylemia coarcteta) and was repleced by
spring barley (Maris Bedger at 155 lb). Treatment Gz wes
undersown with trefoil (inoculated, but with ro additional menures)
in both wheat and barley.
Fertilisers applied autum 1965 (cwt)
Treatments P205 x20 MeO
Dg 3 Z S
st Ou = =
Pt 0.5 1,0 0.15
Ga   0.15
Fa 1,0 3.0 0.40
Fs 0.5 1.0 0.15
Ie   0.15
In   0,15
Nitrogen to spring barley:
NO, Nl, 2 N3-0.0, 0.2, 0.4, 0.6 cwt Nas 'Nitro-Chalk'.
Cultivations, etc.:
Lc and ln plots: Mg applied: Nov 4, 1965, ''Nitro-Chalk' epplied
to In plots: Mar 17, 1966, June 15, Aug 22. Ic plots cut:
June 8, July 13, Aug 12, Oct 25. In plots crt: June 8, Aug 12,
Oct 25.
Remainder: Peat, straw, dung, P, K, Mg, applied: Sept 2 - 7, 1965.
Plougheds Sept 7. Wheat drilled, trefoil undersown on Gu plots:
Nov 2, 'Nitro-Chalk' applied: Apr 28, 1966. Sprayed with para-
quat at 0.75 lb ion in 34 gals: Apr 28, Barley drilled, trefoil
undersown on Gm plots: Apr 30. Combine harvested: Sept 9.
Standard errors per plot. Barley, grain 1966.
Whole plot: 1.41 or 7.2% (15 4.f.)
Subd plot: 1.82 or 9.3% (54 a.f.)
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1967</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[67/c/24.2
Nitrogen to potatoes:
Ml, N2, N3, N4. 0.2, 0.6, 1.0, 1.4 cwt N as 'Nitro-Chalk',
Cultivations, etc.:
LC and LN plots: P, K and Mg epplied: Nov 4, 1966, 'Nitro-
Chalk' applied to LN plots: Apr 4, 1967, June 19.
P, K and Mg applied: Apr 7. IC plots cut: June 8, July 13.
IN plots cut: June 8,
Potatoes: P, K and Mg applied: Nov 11, 1966, Peat, straw, dung
applied: Nov 28 - 29, Ploughed: Nov 30 - Dec 1.
Additional peat applied: Apr 4, 1967. N,P, K and Mg applied:
Apr 4 - 6, Rotary cultivated, potatoes planted: Apr 5 - 7.
Earthed up: May 10, Rotary ridged: June 10. Sprayed with
mancozeb at 1.2 lb in 30 gals: July 1, July 28, Aug 8.
Sprayed with undiluted BOV at 15 gals: Aug 21. Lifted:
Sept 12 - 13. Variety: Majestic,
Standard errors per plot. Potatoes, total tubers:
Whole plot: 1,340 or 19.2% (15 4.1.)
Sub plot: 0,925 or 13.2% (54 a.f.)
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1968</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[68/c/18,2
ORGANIC MANURING EXPERIMENT
(WOM)
The cumlative effects of organic matter on light land - Woburn

Stackyard B 1968, fourth year.

For previous history, rotation, treatments etc., see 'Results'

66/C/31 and 67/c/24, All plots except those under leys

(LC and LN) carried winter wheat.

Area of each sub plot: 0.0156. Area harvested: Wheat - 0.0104

leys =~ 0.0129,

Fertilisers applied Autumn 1967 (cwt)
Treatment , P205 Ke0 MgO
tG   «
st 0.4 - 0,15
PT 0.5 1,0 -
ce: 0.5 1.4* 0.2
FD 2.2 1.6 0.8
FS O.5 1.0 0,2 ,
Ic 0.5 2,0 0.2
LN 0.5 2,0 0.2
* Including 0,4 applied in spring before undersowing, _
Nitrogen to winter wheat:
NO, Nl, N2, N3. 0.0, 0.4, 0.8, 1.2 as 'Nitro-Chalk' in
addition to basal application of 0,2 cwt N, :
Cultivations, etc.:

LC and LN plots: P, K, and Mg applied: 3 Oct, 1967.
'Nitro-Chalk' applied to LN plots: 27 Mar, 1968, 14 June.
Cut twice 5 June, 10 Oct,

Wheat: Subsoiled: 25 Sept, 1967. PK and Mg applied: 10 Oct.
Peat, straw and FYM applied, ploughed: 11 Oct. Seed .
drilled at 190 lb: 25 Oct. K applied to GM plots: 27 Mar, 1968. GM plots undersown with late flowering red clover at 15 lb:
29 Mar. N applied: 18 Apr, All plots except GM plots ,
sprayed with foxynil/mecoprop (Actril C at 6 pints in'

25 gals): 25 Apr. Combine harvested: 23 Aug. Variety: Cappelle.
Standard errors per plot. Winter wheat:
Whole plot: 2.19 or 6.7% (15 4.f.)
Sub plot: 2,79 or 8.5% (5k a.f.)
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1969</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[101
ORGANIC MANURING EXPERDENT
(69/a/PRN/12)
The cumlative effects of organic matter on light lend - Woburn
Stackyerd B 1969, fifth year.
For previous history, rotation, treatments etc., see 'Results'
66/c/31, 67/c/2s and 68/c/18. All plots except those under
leys (IC and LN) cerried sugar beet.
Area of each sub plot: 0.0156, Area harvested: Leys: 0,0129.
Sugar beet: 0.0034.
Fertilisers epplied Autum 1968 (cwt)
Treatment P205 K20 MgO
De =  
sT 0.4 - 0.15
PT 0.5 1.0 -
at 0.5 1.0 0.2
FD 1.0 3.0 0.8
Fs 0.5 1.0 0.2
1c 0.8 1.0 0.2
iy 0.8 1.0 0.2
Fertilisers applied Spring 1969 (cwt)
Treatment P205 Keo
DB = iS
st 0.5 1.5
PT 0.5 1.0
at 0.7 Lol
FD - 1.6
FS 0.5 1.0
Ic O.& 1.2
wy 0.4 1,0
No megnesium was required in the Spring.
Nitrogen to sugar beet:
™, N3, N5, N7. 0.2, 0.6, 1.0, 1.4 cwt NH as 'Nitro-Chalk',
Basal applications: Ground chalk to whole area at 4.5 tons.
Insecticide to sugar beet: Demeton-s-methyl at 3.5 oz in 0 gals.
Cultivations, etc.:
LC and LN plots: P, K, and Mg applied: 8 Nov, 1968. Ground chalk
applied: 10, 14 Feb, 1969. P, K applied: 3 Mar. N applied to LN
plots: 14 Mar, 3 July. Cut: 25 June, 3 Sept.
Sugar beet: P, K, and Mg applied: 19, 20 Nov, 1968, Peat, straw,
FYM applied: 28 - 29 Nov. Ploughed: 29 Nov. Ground chalk
applied: 10, 14 Feb. NPK applied: 10 - 11 Apr. Power harrowed,
seed drilled at 5 lb: 11 Apr. Singled: 29 May - 3 June.
Insecticide applied: 23 June, Lifted: 29 - 30 Oct. Variety:
Klein E.
Standard errors per plot
Roots (washed), tons: Whole plot: 1.183 or 8.9% (15 4.f.)
Sub plot: 1.342 or 10.1% (54 a.f.)
Total sugar, cwt: Whole plot: 5.31 or 10.2% (15 4.f.)
Sub plot: 5.50 or 10.6 (54 4.f.)
Tops, tons: Wnole plot: 0.759 or 13.0% (15 4.f.)
Sub plot: 1.161 or 10.8% (54 a.r.)
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1970</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[ORGANIC MANURING EXPERIMENT
(To/#/RN/12)

The cumulative effects of organic matter on light lend ~ Woburn
Stackyard B 1970, sixth year,

For previous history, rotation, treatments etc., see 'Results'
66/C/31, 67/c/2h, 68/c/18 and 69/W/RN/12, All plots except those
under leys (LC and LN) carried beans, No nitrogen vas applied to
beans, residual effects of nitrogen applied to sugar beet in 1969
were measured,

Ares of each sub plot: 0.0156. Area harvested: Leys: 0,0129,
Beans: 0,0097,

Fertilisers applied Autum 1969 (cwt)

Treatment P205 K20 MgO

G ~  

st Ob - 0.2
PT 0.5 1.0 -

aM 0.5 1.0 0.3
FD 1.0 4,0 0.3
FS 0.5 1.0 0.3
Ic 0.5 1.0 0.3
IN 0.5 1.0 0.3

Fertilisers applied Spring 1970 (ewt)

Treatment Paps K20 MgO
FD - 0.3 -
st ” 0.3 ©
$544 - 0.4 -

Ly - 0.8 -

Basal applications: 400 lb (0:14:28) to all bean plots.
Weedkiller: Simazine at 0.5 1b in 25 gals. Insecticides
Demeton-s-methyl at 3.5 fl oz in 25 gis,

Cultivations, etc.:

Leys: P, K, and Mg applied: 20 Nov, 1969. K applied, N epplied
to LN plots only: 17 Mar, 1970. NW applied to LN plots: 16 June.
Cut: 11 June, 28 Sept,

Beans: Sugar beet tops spread: 7 - 11 Nov, 1969, PK and Mg
applied: 12 - 14 Nov, Peat, straw and FYM applied: 19 Nov.
Plougneds 20 Nov. Additional K applied to FD and ST plots,
power harrowed, PK epplied, seed drilled at 200 lb:

20 Mar, 1970, Weedkiller applied: 21 Mar, Insecticide
applied: 18 June, Combine harvested: 1 Sept. Variety:
Meris Bead,

Standard errors per plot. Beans: Grain, cwts

Whole plot: 0.99 or 15.1% (15 4.f.)

Sub plot: 1.54 or 23.4% (5h a.f.)
406
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1971</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[Th/W /RN/12
ORGANIC MANURING
Object: To study, from crop yields and soil analyses, the cumilative
effects of a range of types of organic matter - Woburn Stackyard B.
The seventh year, leys and rye,
For previous years see 66/C/31(t), 67/C/24(t), 68/C/18(t), 69/w/RN/12(t)
and 70/w/RN/12(t).
Whole plot dimensions: 8,53 x 30.5. Area harvested: Leys - 0.0052h,
rye - 0.00421,
Fertilisers applied autum 1970 (kg)
Treatment P205 K20 MgO
wG   i
sT 63 - 25
PT 63 126 -
om 63 138 38
FD 3 4O7 38
FS B 126 38
Ic 63 126 38
IN 63 126 38
Fertilisers applied spring 1971 (kg)
Treatment P205 K20
st - 50
Ic 63 126
ui 88 251
No P, K, or Mg was required in spring for DG, PT, GM, FD or FS.
NOTE: Residues of N to sugar beet 1969
(m1), (3), (85), (N7). 25, 75, 125, 175 ke Nas 'Nitro-Chalk' 21,
Basal applications: Rye: 31 kg N as 'Nitro-Chalk' 21.
LN plots: 126 kg N es 'Nitro-Chalk' 21 in spring and
after each cut except the last.
Cultivations, etc.:
LC and LN plots: P, K, Mg applied: 6 Oct, 1970. P, K applied:
9 Mar, 1971. N applied to LN plots: 16 Mar, 29 June. Cut:
23 June, 10 Sept.
Rye: P, K, Mg applied: 17 - 18 Sept, 1970. Peat, straw applied:
15 Oct. FYM applied, ploughed: 16 - 17 Oct, Seed drilled
at 191 kg: 17 Oct. GM plots undersowm with Late Flowering
Red Clover at 72 kg: 19 Oct. K applied to ST plots only:
9 Mar, 1971. WN epplied: 14 Apr. Red Clover resown at 72 kg:
22 Apr. Combine harvested: 31 Aug. Variety: King II.
NOTE: Soil samples were taken in the stubble for P, K and Mg
analysis,
Standard errors per plot. Rye, grain, tonnes/hectare:
Whole plot: 0.266 or 7.3% (15 4.f.)
Sub plot: 0,199 or 5.5% (54 4.f.)
108
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1972</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[e/M/Ru/12
Besal applications: .
Potatoes: 100 kg P205 as superphosphate, 200 kg K20 as mriate
of potash in autum, 100 kg P205 as superphosphate, 200 kg
K20 as mriete of potash, 100 kg MgO as Epsom salts in epring. .
Weedkiller: Linuron at 1,1 kg with peraquat at 0.42 kg ion in
370 1. Fungicides Mancozed at 1.3 kg in 4301, Wmgicide
with insecticide: Mancozeb at 1.3 kg with demeton-s-methyl
at 0.25 kg in 430 1. wae
Rye: 6 kg F205, 120 kg k20 as (0:14:28), 4O kg MgO as Bpsom
salts, 40 kg N as 'Nitro-Chalk',
Leys Lc and Ln: 60 kg P205, 120 kg K20 as (0:14:28), hO kg MgO
as Epsom salts. In only: 126 kg Nas 'Nitro-Chaik' in the spring
and after each cut except the last.
Seed: Potatoes: Pentland Crown,
Rye: King II sown at 190 xe,
Cultivations, etc,:
Potatoes: Basal P and K applied: 26 Oct, 1971. Ploughed: 28 Oct,
: Balancing P, K and Mg applied: 14 Jen, 1972, Basal K applied:
7 Apr. Basal P applied: 8 Apr, Basal Mg and test N applied:
13 Apr. Rotary cultivated, potatoes planted: 19 Apr.
Weedkiller applied: 11 May, Grubbed: 31 May, Rotary ridged: .
19 June. Fungicide applied: 5 July. .Ammgicide with insecticide
applied: 27 July. Sprayed with undiluted BOV at 200 1:
22 Sept. Lifted: 26 Sept.
Ryet PK applied: 11 Oct, 1971. Me applied, ploughed: 12 Oct.
Seed drilled: 23 Oct, N applied: 18 Apr, 1972. GM plots
undersowm with Essex Broad Red Clover at 30 kg: 26 Apr.
Combine harvested: 29 Avg.
Leys: Basal PK and Mg applied: 25 Oct, 1971, Balancing P, K and Mz
. applied: 12 Jan, 1972, W applied to LN plots: 8 Mar, 26 June,
' Cut once: 15 Jime,
NOTE: Soil samples were taken after harvest for P, K and Mg analysis,
Stendard errors per plot,
Potatoes, total tubers: tonnes/hectare: Whole plot: 0,52 or 0.5%
(7 4.f.)
Sub plot: 1.05 or 1.1%
(56 a.f.)
Rye, grain, tomes/hectare: Whole plot: ee or of
5 4.f.
Sub plot: 0,202 or 6.6%
(18 4.f.)
108 .
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1973</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[73/1 /RR/12

Fertilisers applied for potatoes 1973 to balance differential crop
removals in 1972 (kg):

P205 ro

Formyard manure 38 88

Straw None Tone

Peat None Hone

Green manures 25 50

Fertilisers equivalent to FYK None None

Fertilisers equivalent to Straw None None

Gmss/clover ley no N None Wi)

Grass ley with W for each cut 'Hone 126

Basel applications:

Potatoes Manures: Superphospnate at 230 ke P20S, muriate of
potes!: st 240 ke K20 in the autumm and at the sem rates in
spring. Epsom selts at 100 ke MeO. Weedkillers: Limron at
1.2 ke plus paraquat at 0,56 kg ion in 2801. Wmmgicide with
insecticide: Mancozeb at 1.3 kg plus demeton-s-methyl at 0,25
kg in 390 1. Fungictde: Mancozeb at 1.3 kg in 390 1 on the
first occasion and in 370 1 on the second occasion,

Winter wheat: Weedkillers: Peraquat at 0.56 kg ion in 280 1,
Ioxynil at 0.63 ke with mecoprup at 1.9 ke in 280 1.

Seeds Winter wheat: Cappelle sown at 200 ke. Potatoes: Pentland

Crown.

Cultivations, etc, t-

Winter wheat: Deep-tine cultivated: 30 Sept, 1972. Seed sown (mixed
varieties in error): 20 Oct. Paragyat applied: 17 Nov. Seed
resown: 24 Nov. N applied: 13 Apr. Ioxynil ané mecoprop spplied:
26 Apr. Combine harvested: 23 Avg.

Potatoes: Basal K applied: 16 Nov, 1972. Basel P applied: 17 Nov.
Ploughed: 30 Nov, Balancing P and K applied: 26 Mar, 1973. Basel
P epplied: 27 Mer. basal K applied: 29 Mar. WN applied: 5 Apr.
Basal Mg applied, rotary cultivated, potatoes planted: 6 Apr.
Weedkiller applied: 9 May, Grubbed: 1 June. Rotary ridged: 4 June,
Pungicide with insecticide applied: 5 July. Fyngicide applied:
26 July, 13 Aug. Haulm mechanically dectroyed: 19 Sept. Sprayed
with undiluted BOV at 220 1: 24 Sept, Lifter: 19 Oct.

Note: (1) Lee? samples o% both wheat and potatoern were taken for
boron enelysis,

(2) Soil samples were taken in the spring and m'd-season for
P, F and Me analysis.

(3) Winter wheat, One plot treatment MANURE-Fert-Str, NO
was vadly demged by rabbits. Values for grain and
straw ectimeted from visual scores made Just before
harvest were used in the analysis,

122
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1974</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[74 /W/RN/12
Stendard applications:

Sugar beet: Manures: Ground chalk at 5 tonnes. (0:20:20) in autumn
at 1140 kg. (0:20:20) in the seedbed at 580 kg. MgO at 100 kg
as Bpsom salts. Boron at 6.7 kg B203 (as 'Solubor') applied with
the second application of insecticide. Insecticides Demeton-s-methyl
at 0.25 kg in 28 1 followed by 0.21 kg in 390 1. Weedkillers:
Aminotriazole at 4.5 kg with ammonium thiocyanate at 4,1 kg in
370 1. Phenmedipham at 1.1 kg in 340 1.

Winter wheat: Manures: P205 at 110 kg as superphosphate. K20 at 60 kg
as murtate of potash. Weedkiller: Ioxynil at 0,63 kg with mecoprop
at 1.9 kg in 28 1.

Seeds: Sugar beet: Klein B, sown at 8.0 kg.
Winter wheat: Cappelle, dressed with dieldrin, sow at 190 kg.
Cultivations, etc.:

Sugar beet: Aminotriazole with ammonium thiocyanate applied: 13 Sept, 1973.
Ground chalk applied: 27 Sept. Subsoiled, tines 140 cm apart and 50 cm
deep: 20 Oct. PK applied: 25 Oct. Ploughed: 13 Nov. Spring-tine
cultivated: 30 Mar, 1974. NW applied: 4 Apr. PK and Mg applied, power
harrowed, seed sown: 5 Apr. Phenmedipham applied: 26 May. Singled:

29-30 May. Insecticide applied: 5 June. Boron and insecticide applied:
24 June. Lifted: 22 - 29 Nov.

Winter wheat: P and K applied, deep-tine cultivated, spring-tine cultivated:
18 Oct, 1973. Seed sown: 22 Oct. Weedkiller epplied: 5 Apr, 1974.

N applied: 10 Apr. Combine harvested: 29 Aug.
Standard errors per plot.
Sugar beet. Roots (washed), tonnes/hectare: Whole plot: 1.19 or 4.9% (7 4.f.)
Subd plot: 2.01 or 8.3% (56 a:
Total sugar, tonnes/hectare: Whole plot: 0.178 or 4.7% (7 4.f.
Sub plot: 0.317 or 8.5% (56 4.f.)
Tops, tonnes/hectare: Whole plot: 1.78 or 7.9% (7 4.f.)
Sub plot: 3.09 or 13.8% (56 d.f.)
Winter wheat. Grain, tonnes/hectare: Whole plot: 0.454 or 9.4% (7 d.f.)
Sub plot: 0.572 or 11.% (56 4.f.)
114
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1975</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[75/¥/ Ru /I2

Barley: beruress (0:2lsia.) at 280 kv, conbine Grilled. Weedkiller:

Toxyn2.l 91, 0.62 kg und meceprop ai 1.6 kg “1 260 1.
Seeds Sugur beet: Klein B, sown s%. 5.6 kg.

Earley: Julia, dressed with ethirimol, sown at. 1€0 ke.
Cultivetions, etc.t-

Sugar beet: Weedk2ller applied: 16 Sept, 1974. Subsoiled, tines 140 cm
apart and 60 cm deep: 19 Sept. Ground chelk applied: 9 Oct. PK
epplied: 16 Nov. Ploughed 9 Dec. PK and Mg applied, spring-tine
cultiveted with crumbler: 28 Apr, 1975. Seed sown: 29 Apr. N
applied: 29 - 30 Apr. Tractor hoed three times: 29 May, 27 June,

30 June, Insecticide applied: 9 June. Singled: 16 - 18 June.
Insecticice with boron epplied: 1 Aug. Side hoed: 10 - 17 July.
Lifted: 11 - 14 Nov.
Barley: Plovghed in suger beet tops: 14 Jan, 1975. Spring-tine cultivated
with crumblers 8 Mar. Seed sown: 4 Mar. N applied: 18 Mar.
Weedkiller applied: 20 May. Combine harvested: 11 Aug.

TONNES HECTARE
*** TABLES OF MEANS ***
N 0 40 80 120 160 200 240 280 MEAN
MANURE
FYM Sel 4166 1465 1468 1562 1555 15-45 1564 15.6
STRAW 6e4 10-2 1162 1169 12655 13-2 14.0 13.7 11.6
PEAT 5.2 72 105 1160 12062 1369 1569 13-68 11.0
GREE NMNR $3 9.0 8.2 9-0 1260 1263 1205 12.8 10.2
FERT FYM 4.2 41 8.0 8.6 96 11.0 115 12.5 8.6
FERT STR 3.8 73 88 11.66 10.6 11.4 11.5 13.2 908
CLOVRLEY 72 Aled 128 1462 12-7 15-7 16.55 15.0 13.2
GRASSLEY 10.0 1205 13.8 1668 185 13.2 16.5 14.7 14.5
MEAN 65 92 1160 1202 12.9 13.35 13-7 13-9 11.6
waite STANDARD ERRORS OF DIFFERENCES OF MEANS *##+*
TABLE MANURE N MANURE
N
SED 1.37 0-52 1.95
EXCEPT WIEN COMPARING MEANS WITH SAME LEVEL(S) OF:
MANURE 1.43
eeeee STRATUM STANDARD ERRORS AND COEFFICIENTS OF VARIATION *#***
STRATUM DF SE cvs
BLOCK .WP ? 1.37 11.8
BLOCK.WP.SP 56 1.43 12.3
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1976</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[—_ >
a F 76/W/BN/12
Standard applications:
Winter oats: Manures; (0:20:20) at 300 kg, combine drilled. Weedkillers:
? ~ Glyphosate at 1.7 ke in 340 1. loxynil at 0.63 ke-plus mecoprop at
1.9 ke in 260 1.
Barley: Manures: (0:20:20) at 200 kg combine drilled. Weedkiller:
Ioxynil at 0.53 kg plus mecoprop at 1.6 ke in 260 1.
Seed: Winter oats: Peniarth, sown at 200 ke.
Barley: Julia, dressed with ethirimol, sown at i60 ke.
Cultivations, etc.:-
Winter oats: Glyphosate applied: 5 Oct, 1975. Ploughed: 24 Oct.
. Spring-tine cultivated with crumbler attached: 25 Oct. Seed
sown: 27-Oct. loxynil plus mecoprop applied: 20 Apr, 1976.
_ Harvested green: 30 June.

Barley: Ploughed in sugar beet tops: 24 Nov, 1975. Spring-tine
cultivated: 2 Mar, 1976. XM applied: 4 Mar. Seed sewn: & Mare
Weedkiller applied: 28 Apr. Combine harvested: 27 July.

NOTE: Soil samples were taken from the blocks in barley for chemical
analyses and physical measurements.
WINTER OATS
GREEN CROP DRY MATTER TONNES/ HECTARE
#een® TABLES OF MEANS *****
NS (0) (25) (50) (75) (100) (125) (150) (175) MBAN
MANURE
FYH 2010 2.06 1680 2-21 2.29 3.06 2.56 5.29 2-42
STRAV 3095 2612 2.50 2.39 2031 2639 2679 2248 2.36
PEAT 1.58 1.56 1.78 1.67 2.16 2.36 2-42 1.97 1.94
GREENMRR 1.6 1647 2009 1.88 2:34 2.16 1.86 2.34 2.01
FERT FYM 1.67 1641 1.50 1.58 1.81 1.69 1.65 2.25 1.644
FERT STR 1.18 1-52 1.72 1.9 1.85 1.55 1.79 2.00 1.70
CLOVRLEY 2.56 2.51 2.36 2657 2.0 3.00 2-97 4.25 2.89
GRASSLEY 3.14 2015 2062 2697 2.89 4% 5.45 4.27 5.55
MEAN 2001 1085 2002 2.13 2032 2.65 2.68 2.85 2.51
#8288 STANDARD ERRORS OF DIFFERENCES OF MEANS ***#°
TABLE MANURE N % MANURE
K 75
SED 0.524 0.166 0.684
EXCEPT WHEN COMPARING MEANS WITH SAME LEVEL(S) OF:
MANURE 0.470
'nt STRATUM STANDARD ERRORS AND COEFFICIENTS OF VARIATION *****
STRATUM OF SE CV%
BLOCK. WP 7 0.524 2207
BLOCK. WP.SP 6 0.470 20.35
GREENCROP MEAN DH% 47.6
SUB PLOT AREA HARVESTED 0.00056
97
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1977</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[TT/W/RN/12
Standard applications:

Winter oats: Manures: (0:20:20) at 290 kg, combine drilled. Weedkillers:
Glyphosate at 1.7 kg in 280 1. Ioxynil at 0.53 kg plus mecoprop at
1.6 kg in 220 1.

Potatoes: Manures: (0:20:20) at 1140 kg in winter. (0:20:20) at 1210 kg in
spring. 60 kg Mg as kieserite. Weedkiller: Linuron at 1.3 kg plus
paraquat at 0.42 kg ion in 4201. Fungicide: Mancozeb at 1.3 kg on four
occasions, the last three with insecticide, in 420 1, 390 1 and twice in
370 1 successively. Insecticide: Pirimicarb at 0.14 kg on three

. occasions with fungicide.
Seed: Winter oats: Peniarth, sown at 200 kg.
Potatoes: Pentland Crown. A
Cultivations, etc.:

Winter oats: Glyphosate applied: 23 Sept, 1976. Ploughed: 15 Oct. Spring-
tine cultivated, seed sown: 8 Nov. Ioxynil plus mecoprop applied:

- 15 May, 1977. Harvested green: 7-8 July. .
Potatoes: Heavy-tine cultivated: 28 July, 1976. Power harrowed: 16 Aug.
Ploughed: 15 Oct. Winter PK applied: 17 Jan, 1977. Spring PK and

kieserite applied: 6 Apr. Heavy-tine cultivated: 13 Apr. N applied:
19-21 Apr. Power harrowed, potatoes planted: 22 Apr. Grubbed and earthed
up, weedkiller applied: 25 May. Fungicide applied: 23 June. Fungicide
with insecticide applied: 8 July, 21 July, 12-Aug. Haulm mechanically
destroyed: 21 Oct. Lifted: 1 Nov.

. &2
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1978</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[78/W/RN/12
ORGANIC MANURING

Object: To study, from crop. yields and soil anelyses, the residual effects
of a range of types of organic matter - Woburn, Stackyard B.

Sponsor: G.E.G. Mattingly.

The 1uth year, winter wheat, potatoes.

For previous years see "Details' 1973 and 74~77/W/RN/12.

Design for each crop: 2 blocks of 8 plots split into 8.

whole plot dimensions: 8.52 x 30.5.

Treatments: From 1966 to 1971 the experiment had a2 preliminary period designed
to build up organic matter, derived from different sources. An arable
rotation was started on two blocks in 1972 and the remaining two blocks
in 1973. Orgenic manures were last applied in 1971, the leys were :
ploughed in autum 1971 and 1972 before starting the rotation. The experi-
ment now tests all combinations of:-

Whole plots :

1. MANURE Organic manures and fertilisers in the preliminary period:
FYM Farmyard manure
STRAW Straw
PEAT Peat Y
GREENMNR Green manures .

FERT-FYM Fertilisers equivant to FYM
FERT-STR Fertilisers equivaJent to straw -
CLOVRLEY Grass/clover ley, no N :
GRASSLEY Grass ley with N for each cut

Sub plots

2.N Fertiliser nitrogen (kg N) as 'Nitro-Chalk 25°:

WHEAT POTATOES ,
0 0
30 15
60 150
90 225
120 300
150 375
180 450
210 525

Standard applications:

Winter wheat: Manures: 110 kg P,0, es superphosphate, 60 kg Ko as muriate
of potash. Weedkillers: MecSprop, bromoxynil, and ioxynil“('Brittox'
at 3.5 kg in 280 1).

Potatoes: Manures: (0:20:20) at 1210 kg in winter, (0:20:20) at 1210 kg in
spring. 60 kg Mg as kieserite. Weedkillers: Linuron at 1,3 kg plus
paraquat at 0.42 kg ion in 280 1. Fungicides: Mancozeb at 1.3 kg on
three occasions, in 280 1 on the first, in 420 1 on the second, in
420 1 with insecticide on the third. Fentin acetate with maneb ('Fennite
At at 1.7 kg in 2801). Insecticide: Pirimicarb at 0.14 kg, on one
occasion with fungicide, in 420 1. Haulm desiccant: Undiluted BOV
at 1701.
Seed: Winter wheat: Maris Huntsman at 210 kg.
Potatoes: Pentland Crown.
Cultivations, etc.:~
Winter wheat: PK applied: 10 Nov, 1977. Ploughed: 11 Nov. Spring-tine
cultivated with crumbler attached, seed sown: 14 Nov. N applied:
11 Apr, 1978. Weedkiller applied: 10 May. Combine harvested: 25 Aug.
Potatoes: Heavy spring-tine cultivated three times: 15 July, 1977,
18 July, 9 Aug. Ploughed: 30 Sept. Winter PK applied: 6 Jan, 1978.
Reploughed: 9 Feb. Spring PK applied: 30 Mar. Deep-tine cultivated:
31 Mar. N applied: 14 Apr. Kieserite applied: 20 Apr. Rotary cultivated,
potatoes planted: 24 Apr. Weedkillers applied: 15 May. Grubbed:
6 June. Earthed up: 9 June. Mancozeb applied: 5 July, 20 July. Mancozeb
applied with insecticide: 11 Aug. Fentin acetate with maneb applied:
23 Aug. Haulm desiccant applied: 23 Sept. Lifted: 11 Oct.

NOTE: Because of an error in weighing, yield of one plot of potatoes, treatment
combination MANURE FERT FYM, N 0, was lost. An estimated value was used
in the analysis.

100
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1979</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[T9/W/RN/12 ~
Standard applications:

Winter wheat: Manures: P,0. at 110 kg as superphosphate, K0 at 60 kg as
auriate of potash. Wéedkiller: Methabenzthiazuron at 1°75 kg in 220 l.

Sugar beet: Manures: Chalk at 5 t, (0:20:20) at 1210 kg in autumn, (0:20:20)
at 605 kg in spring. Mg at 60 kg as kieserite. Boron at 8.0 kg 8,03 (as
"Solubor') applied with the insecticide. Insecticide: Pirimicarb
at 0.14 kg in 250 1.

clover grass ley: Manures: Chalk at 5 t, (0:20:20) at 1210 kg in autumn,
(0:20:20) at 605 kg in spring, Mg at 60 kg as kieserite.

Seed: Winter wheat: Flanders, sown at 180 kg.
Sugar beet: Klein E, sown at 5.6 kg.
clover grass ley: sow) at 22.4 kg.

Cultivations, ete.:-

Winter wheat: Heavy spring-tine cultivated, P and K applied, spring-tine
cultivated with crumbler attached: 13 Oct, 1978. Seed sown: 14 Oct.
Weedkiller applied: 18 Oct. N applied: 18 Apr, 1979. Combine harvested: 29
Aug.

Sugar beet: Chalk applied: 7 Nov, 1978. Autumn PK applied: 24 Nov. Spring PK
and Mg applied, spring-tine cultivated: 30 Apr, 1979. Spring-tine cultivated
with crumbler attached, seed sow: 1 May. N applied: 4 May. Singled:

11-15 June. Tractor hoed three times: 18 June, 2 July, 16 July. Boron
and insecticide applied: 30 June. Lifted: 1 Nov.

Clover grass ley: Chalk applied: 7 Nov, 1978. Autumn PK applied: 24 Nov.
Spring PK and Mg applied, spring-tine cultivated: 30 Apr, 1979. Spring-
tine cultivated with crunbler attached: 1 May. N applied: 4 May. Spring-
tine cultivated with crumbler attached, seeds sown: 4 June. Topped: 30 July.

]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1980</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[80/W/ RN/12 :
Standard applications:

S. barley: Manures: P20s5 at 110.kg as superphosphate, K20 at 60 kg
as muriate of potash. Weedkillers: Mecoprop with bromoxynil and
foxynil fas 'Brittox' at 3.5 1) in 280 1. Fungicides: Tridemorph at
0.53 kg in 280 1, ethirimol (as 'Milgo E' at 1.3 1) in 280 1.

Sugar beet: Manures: Chalk at 5.0 t, (0:20:20) at 1210 kg in autumn,
(0:20:20) at 610 kg in spring, Mg at 60 kg as kieserite, Boron at 8.0
kg 8203 (as 'Solubor') in 300 1.

first year Clover grass ley: Chalk at 5.0 t, (0:20:20) at 1210 kg and

; later at 610 kg, Mg at 60 kg as kieserite, N at 60 kg as
'Nitro-Chalk'. Weedkiller: Paraquat at 0.84 kg ion in 450 1.

second year Clover grass ley: P205 at 110 kg as superphosphate, K20

at 60 kg as muriate of potash.
Seed: S$. barley: Georgie, dressed with ethirimol, sown at 160 kg.
Sugar beet: Bush Mono G, sown at 5.6 kg.
clover grass ley: Climax timothy at 7 kg, $.215 meadow fescue
at 14 kg, Huia white clover at 2 kg, mixture sown at 23 kg.
Cultivations, etc.:-

S. barley: Ploughed in sugar beet tops: 22 Nov, 1979. P and K applied:
14 Jan, 1980. Heavy spring-tine cultivated: 29 Feb. Spring-tine
cultivated with crumbler attached: 3 Mar. Seed sown: 4 Mar. N
applied: 21 Mar. Weedkiller applied: 8 May. Tridemorph applied: 13
May. 'Milgo E' applied: 5 June. Combine harvested: 28 Aug.

Sugar beet: Chalk applied: 13 Nov, 1979. Ploughed: 22 Nov. Autumn PK
applied: 4 Mar, 1980. Ploughed: 11 Mar. Spring PK and Mg appl fed:
31 Mar. Heavy spring-tine cultivated: 8 Apr. Rotary cultivated: 9
Apr. N applied, seed sown: 11 Apr. Tractor hoed: 22 May, 4 June, 20
dune, Singled: 29 May. Side-hoed by hand: 16 June. Boron applied:
19 June. Lifted: 4-7 Nov.

first year Clover grass ley: Chalk apptied: 13 Nov, 1979. Ploughed: 22
Nov. PK applied: 4 Mar, 1980. Ploughed: 11 Mar. PK and Mg applied:
31 Mar. Heavy spring-tine cultivated: 8 Apr. Rotary cultivated: 9 '
Apr. N applied: 11 Apr. Seeds sown: 17 Apr. Topped: 9 June.
Paraquat applied because of poor germination: 26 June. Rotary
cultivated: 30 June. Spring-tine cultivated: 2 July. Spring-tine
cultivated with crumbler attached, seeds re-sown: 11 July.

second year Clover grass ley: P and K applied: 20 Mar, 1980. Cut: 4 June,
8 Sept. Topped: 18 Sept.

84
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1981</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[81/W/RN/12
S. beans tested:

MANURE Organic manures and fertilisers in 1981, cumulative to

those applied in the preliminary period:

FYM Farmyard manure at 50 tonnes

STRAW Straw at 7.5 tonnes plus Poos at 140 kg, K20 at

140 kg, MgO at 50 kg
FERT-FYM P205 at 280 kg, K20 at 560 kg, MgO at 100 kg
FERT-STR P205 at 140 kg, K20 at 280 kg, MgO at 50 kg
All leys are clover grass (LC) without N except to seedbed in first

year. lst year leys tested:

PREV LEY Previous ley:

LC(LC) clover grass ley in preliminary period

LC(LN) Grass ley with N in preliminary period

second & third year leys tested:

PREV MAN Previous manure:

: LC(GM) Green manures in preliminary period

LC(PT) Peat in preliminary period

Standard applications:

S. barley: Manures: P205 at 110 kg as superphosphate, K20 at 60 kg
as muriate of potash. Weedkillers: Mecoprop with bromoxynil and
ioxynt] (as 'Brittox' at 3.5 1) in 280 1 with the fungicide.
Fungicide: Tridemorph at 0.53 kg.

S. beans: Weedkiller: Simazine at 0.84 kg in 280 t. Insecticides:
Phorate at 5.6 kg, pirimicarb at 0.14 kg in 280 1 on two occasions.

first second and third year clover grass leys: Manures: (0:14:28) at 1000
kg, MgO at 50 kg as kieserite. N at 50 kg to lst year and 60 kg to
second year as 'Witro-Chalk'.

Seed: S. barley: Georgie, dressed with ethirimol, sown at 160 kg.
S. beans: Minden, sown at 220 kg.
clover grass ley: Climax timothy at 13.4 kg, S215 Meadow fescue at
11.2 kg, Huia white clover at 3.4 kg. Mixture sown at 28 kg.
Cultivations, etc.:-

S. barley: Ploughed in sugar beet tops: 11 Dec, 1980. P and K applied:
16 Feb, 1981. Spring-tine cultivated: 18 Feb. Spring-tine
cultivated with crumbler attached, seed sown: 27 Feb. N applied: 26
Mar. Weedkillers and fungicide applied: 15 Apr. Combine harvested:
17 Aug.

S. beans: Mg applied: 3 Dec, 1980. PK applied: 4 Dec. Organic manures
applied: 16 Jan, 1981. PK and Mg applied: 16 Feb. Spring-tine
cultivated: 18 Feb. Phorate applied, rotary cultivated with
crumbler attached, seed sown: 6 Apr. Weedkiller applied: 7 Apr.
Pirimicard applied: 18 June, 27 July. Combine harvested: 3 Sept.

first year clover grass ley: Ploughed: 16 Jan, 1981. PK and Mg applied: 16
Feb. Spring-tine cultivated twice: 18 Feb, 8 Apr. Rotary
cultivated, N applied: 7 May. Seeds sown: 13 May. Topped twice: 25
June, 20 July. Cut: 8 Sept.

second year clover grass ley: Mg applied: 3 Dec, 1980. PK applied: 4 Dec.
N applied: 13 May, 1981. Cut: 10 June, 8 Sept.
third year clover grass ley: Mg applied: 3 Dec, 1980. PK applied: 4 Dec.
Cut: 12 June, 1981, 8 Sept.
GRAIN TONNES/HECTARE
week TABLES OF MEANS ***** t
N 0 30 60 90 120 150 180 210 MEAN
MANURE
FYM 3.44 4.47 6.59 6.36 7.21 6.49 5.84 5.22 5.70
STRAN 3.84 5.73 6.73 7.48 6.46 6.81 5.95 5.64 6.08
FERT-FYM 2.39 4.17 5.56 6.12 5.50 5.64 5.27 5.16 4.98
FERT-STR 3.57 4.79 6.20 6.83 7.17 7.00 5.73 5.52 5.85
CLOVRLEY 4.14 5.80 6.89 7.12 7.07 6.48 5.88 5.84 6.15
GRASSLEY 3.58 5.35 5.90 6.82 6.80 5.68 6.03 5.36 5.69
MEAN 3,49 5.05 6.31 6.79 6.70 6.35 5.78 5.46 5.74
#k*®*® STANDARD ERRORS OF DIFFERENCES OF MEANS *****
TABLE MANURE N MANURE
N
SED 0.604 0,157 0.704
EXCEPT WHEN COMPARING MEANS WITH SAME LEVEL(S) OF:
MANURE 0.386
wkae** STRATUM STANDARD ERRORS AND COEFFICIENTS OF VARIATION *****
STRATUM OF SE cvs
BLOCK.WP 5 0.604 10.5 . :
BLOCK .WP.SP 42 0.386 6.7
GRAIN MEAN OMZ 88,0
STRAW TONNES/HECTARE
week* TABLES OF MEANS *****
N 0 30 60 90 120 150 180 210 MEAN
MANURE
FYM 1.50 2.40 4.84 4.94 6.02 4.88 6.55 5.33 4.56
STRAW 1.81 3.02 4.45 5.32 6.40 6.31 7.80 6.65 5,22
FERT-FYM 1.37 2.19 3.30 4.90 5.18 4.93 4.80 5.04 3.97
FERT-STR 1.64 2.79 4.01 5.39 5.93 6.17 6.05 5.68 4.71
CLOVRLEY 1.71 2.82 4.50 5.48 5.95 5.67 5.67 6.35 4.77
GRASSLEY 1.63 2.43 4.54 5.88 6.28 5.22 6.16 6.91 4.88
MEAN 1.61 2.61 4.27 5.32 5.96 5.53 6.17 5.99 4.68
STRAW MEAN DMZ 77.5
SUB PLOT AREA HARVESTED 0.00168
85
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1982</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[82/W/RN/12
ORGANIC MANURING

Object: To study, from crop yields and soil analyses, the effects of a
range of types of organic matter ~ Woburn, Stackyard 8.

Sponsor: A.E. Johnston.

The 1eighth year, w. beans, w. wheat, ley.

For previous years see 'Details' 1973 and 74-81/W/RN/12.

Design for w. beans and w. wheat: 2 blocks of 4 plots

first, second, third and fourth year leys: 2 blocks of 2 plots.

Whole plot dimensions: 8.53 x 30.5.

Treatments: From 1966 to 1971 the experiment had a preliminary period
designed to build up organic matter, derived from different sources. An
arable rotation was started on two blocks in 1972 and the remaining two
blocks in 1973. After a period of testing the residues built up, a
further period of accumulation was started; on two blocks (which
included ley sown in 1979) in 1981 and on the other two (which included
Jey sown in 1980) in 1982. In addition to leys the first pair included
w. wheat in 1982 and the second pair w. beans.

W. beans and w. wheat tested:

MANURE Organic manures and fertilizers in 1982, cumulative to
1981 (w. wheat only) and to those applied in the
preliminary period:

FYM Farmyard manure at 50 tonnes

STRAW Straw at 7.5 tonnes plus Pads at 140 kg, K20 at
140 kg, MgO at 50 kg

FERT-FYM P205 at 280 kg, K20 at 560 kg, MgO at 100 kg

FERT-STR P205 at 140 kg, K20 at 280 kg, MgO at 50 kg

All leys are clover grass (LC) without N except to seedbed in first
year. lst and second year leys tested:

PREV LEY Previous ley: 4

LC(LC) clover grass ley in preliminary period

LC(LN) Grass ley with N in preliminary period

third and fourth year leys tested:

PREV MAN Previous manure:

LC(GM) Green manures in preliminary period

LC(PT) Peat in preliminary period

Standard applications:

W. wheat: Manures: N at 150 kg as 'Nitro-Chalk'. Weedkillers:

Glyphosate at 1.5 kg in 280 1, isoproturon at 2.1 kg in 280 1.
W. beans: Weedkillers: Glyphosate at 1.5 kg in 280 1. Propyzamide at
0.84 kg in 280 7.

clover grass leys, first, second, third and fourth years: Manures: P205 at
140 kg, K20 at 280 kg as (0:14:28), MgO at 50 kg as kieserite. N
at 50 kg as 'Nitro-Chalk' to ist year ley only. Weedkiller:
Glyphosate at 1.5 kg in 280 1 for ist year ley only.

Seed: W. wheat: Avalon, sown at 190 kg.
W. beans: Throws MS, sown at 250 kg.
clover grass ley: Climax timothy at 13.4 kg, $215 Meadow fescue at
11.2 kg, Huia white clover at 3.4 kg. Mixture sown at 28 kg.
Cultivations, etc.:-

W. wheat: Glyphosate applied: 16 Sept, 1981. PK and Mg applied to
FERT-FYM plots only, FYM applied to FYM plots only: 8 Oct. PK and
straw applied to STRAW vee only, ploughed: 6 Nov. PK applied to
FERT-FYM and FERT-STR plots only. Mg applied to FERT-FYM, FERT-STR
and STRAW plots only, spring-tine cultivated with crumbler attached:
9 Nov. Seed sown: 10 Nov. N applied: 14 Apr, 1982. Isoproturon
applied: 15 Apr. Combine harvested: 16 Aug.

W. beans: Glyphosate applied: 1 Oct, 1981. PK and Mg applied to
FERT-FYM plots only, FYM applied to FYM plots only: 8 Oct. PK and
Straw apptied to STRAW plots only, ploughed: 6 Nov. PK applied to
FERT-FYM and FERT-STR plots only, Mg applied to FERT-FYM, FERT-STR
and STRAW plots only: 9 Nov. Spring-tine cultivated with crumbler
attached, seed sown: 10 Nov. Propyzamide applied: 13 Nov. Combine
harvested: 13 Aug, 1982.

lst year clover grass ley: Glyphosate applied: 1 Oct, 1981. Ploughed:
6 Nov. PK and Mg applied: 9 Nov. Spring-tine cultivated with
crumbler attached: 10 Nov, 15 Apr, 1982, 19 Apr. N applied: 15 Apr,
23 June. Seed sown: 29 Apr. Topped: 16 June, 29 June, 26 July.

second, third and fourth year clover grass ley: PK and Mg applied: 9 Nov, 1981.
Cut: 7 July, 1982.

GRAIN TONNES/HECTARE
wekee TABLES OF MEANS *****

MANURE FYN STRAW FERT-FYM FERT-STR MEAN

4.77 5.05 4.41 4.67 4.73
GRAIN MEAN DMZ 84.2
PLOT AREA HARVESTED 0.02471
* 76
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1983</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[83/W/RN/12
Standard applications:

w. wheat: Manures: N at 150 kg as 'Nitro-Chalk'. Weedkillers:
Glyphosate at 1.5 kg in 280 1, Mecoprop with bromoxynil and foxyni?
(as 'Brittox' at 4.2 1) in 280 1.

Sugar beet: Manures: Ground chalk at 5.0 t, NW at 150 kg as 'Nitro-
Chalk'. Weedkillers: Glyphosate at 1.5 kg in 280 1. Phenmedipham
= kg in 280 1. Insecticide: Demeton-s-methy!] at 0.24 kg in
2 °

second, third, fourth and fifth year leys: Manures: Ground chalk at 5.0 t to third
and fifth years only. P205 at 140 kg, K20 at 280 kg as
(0:18:36), MgO at 50 kg as kfeserite.

Seed: W. wheat: Avalon, sown at 190 kg.
Sugar beet: Monoire, sown by precision drill.
Cultivations, etc.:-

W. wheat: Glyphosate applied: 10 Sept, 1982. Half PK and Mg applied to
FERT-FYM plots: 5 Oct. Treatment FYM and straw applied, ploughed:

5 Nov. Half PK and Mg applied to FERT-FYM, all PK and Mg applied to
FERT-STR and STRAW plots only: 8 Nov. Spring-tine cultivated with
crumbler attached, seed sown, spring-tine cultivated: 11 Nov. W
applied: 28 Apr, 1983. 'Brittox' applied: 29 Apr. Combine
harvested: 12 Aug.

Sugar beet: Glyphosate applied: 10 Sept, 1982, Half PK and Mg applied
to FERT-FYM plots: 5 Oct. Ground chalk applied: 3 Nov. Treatment
FYM applied and these plots ploughed: 5 Nov. Treatment straw
applied, remaining plots ploughed, PK applied to STRAW plots: 8 Nov.
Half PK and Mg applied to FERT-FYM, all PK and Mg applied to FERT-STR
plots, all Mg appifed to STRAW plots: 9 Nov. Deep-tine cul tivated:
12 Jan, 1983. Heavy spring-tine cultivated, spring-tine cul tivated,
N applied: 22 Mar. Spring-tine cultivated with crumbler attached:
14 Apr. Rotary cultivated, seed sown: 30 Apr. Phenmedipham
applied: 7 June. Singled: 9-14 June. Tractor hoed: 20 June,

1 July. Insecticide applied: 29 June. Hand hoed: 4-11 July.
Lifted: 10 Oct.

second, third, fourth and fifth year leys: Ground chalk applied to third and Sth
years only: 3 Nov, 1982. PK and Mg applfed: 9 Nov. Cut: 16 June,
1983, 24 Aug.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1984</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[84/W/RN/12
Standard applications:
W. oats: Manures: Nat 90 kg as 'Nitro-Chalk'. Weedkiller:
Methabenzthiazuron at 2.4 kg in 250 1.
Sugar beet: Manures: Ground chalk at 5.0 t, N at 150 kg as 'Nitro-
Chalk'. Insecticide: Demeton-S-methy] at 0.24 kg in 250 1.
Leys, third, fourth, fifth and sixth years: Manures: P205 at 140 kg, K20
at 280 kg as (0:18:36), Mg@ at 50 kg as kieserite.
Seed: W. oats: Panema, sown at 200 kg.
Sugar beet: Monoire, sown by precision drill.
Cultivations, etc.:-
W. oats: Half PK and Mg applied to FERT-FYM plots, treatment FYM and
straw applied, sugar beet tops spread over arable plots, ploughed:
19 Oct, 1983. Half PK and Mg applied to FERT-FYN, all PK and Mg
applied to FERT-STR and STRAW plots only, spring-tine cultivated with
crumbler attached, seed sown: 20 Oct. Weedkiller applied: 21 Oct.
N applied: 3 Apr, 1984. Combine harvested: 3 Aug.
Sugar beet: Ground chalk applied: 30 Sept, 1983. Half PK and Mg applied
to FERT-FYM plots, treatment FYM and straw applied: 20 Oct.
Ploughed: 21 Oct. PK applied to STRAW plots: 11 Nov. Half PK and
Mg applied to FERT-FYM plots, all PK and Mg applied to FERT-STR plots
and all Mg applied to STRAW plots: 15 Nov. Heavy spring-tine
cultivated: 14 Dec. N applied and spring-tine cultivated: 3 Apr,
1984, Spring-tine cultivated with crumbler attached, seed sown:
4 Apr. Singled: 16-18 May. Tractor hoed: 31 May, 11 June. Hand
hoed: 11-12 June, 29 June-4 July. Insecticide applied: 29 June,
Lifted: 26 Oct.
third, fourth, fifth and sixth year leys: PK and Mg applied to fourth and sixth
years: 20 Oct, 1983. third and fifth years: 15 Nov. Cut: 12 June, 1984,
10 Sept.
86
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1985</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[85/W/RN/12
Standard applications:

W. oats s. oats: Manures: N at 50 kg as 'Nitro-Chalk' (27.5% N).
Weedkillers: Mecoprop at 1.2 kg with bromoxynil at 0.3 kg and
ioxynil at 0.3 kg in 250 1.

W. rye: Manures: N at 30 kg as 'Nitro-Chalk' (27.5% .N). Weedkillers:
Mecoprop at 1.2 kg with bromoxynil at 0.3 kg and foxynil at 0.3 kg
in 250 1.

Leys, fourth, Sth, sixth and seventh years: Manures: P205 at 140 kg, K20 at
280 kg as (0:18:36). MgO at 50 kg as kieserite.

Seed: W. oats: Panema, sown at 180 kg.
S. oats: Trafalgar, sown at 200 kg.
W. rye: Animo, sown at 220 kg.

NOTE: S. oats were sown in place of the w. oats that failed because of
bird damage.

Cultivations, etc.:-

W. oats s. oats: Sugar beet tops spread over arable plots, PK and Mg
applied to FERT-FYM, treatment FYM and STRAW applied, ploughed, PK
and Mg applied to STRAW, Mg applied to FERT-FYM and FERT-STR:

5 Nov, 1984, Rotary harrowed, w. oats sown: 12 Nov. Spring-tine
cultivated: 18 Mar, 1985. Power harrowed, s. oats sown: 20 Mar.
N applied: 24 Apr, Weedkillters applied: 16 May. Combine
harvested: 27 Aug.

W. rye: Half PK and Mg applied to FERT-FYM plots, treatment FYM
applied: 20 Sept, 1984. Ploughed FYM plots only: 21 Sept.
Treatment STRAW applied, FERT-FYM, FERT-STR and STRAW ploughed:

3 Oct. PK applied to STRAW plots: 15 Oct. PX and Mg applied.

FERT-STR and half PK and Mg applied to FERT-FYM, Mg applied to

STRAW: 16 Oct. Rotary harrowed, seed sown: 24 Oct. N applied:

Hy Apr, 1985. Weedkillers applied: 16 May. Combine harvested:
Sept.

fourth, fifth, sixth and seventh year leys: PK and Mg applied to fourth and sixth
years: 5 Nov, 1984, fifth and seventh years: 9 Nov. Chain harrowed:
12 Apr, 1985. Cut: 2 July, 11 Nov.

GRAIN TONNES/HEC TARE
weenie TABLES OF MEANS *****
MANURE FYM STRAW FERT-FYM FERT-STR MEAN
4.96 4.74 4.15 4.65 4.62
GRAIN MEAN OM% 81.7
STRAW TONNES/HEC TARE
weeks TABLES OF MEANS ***#**
MANURE FYM STRAW FERT-FYM FERT-STR MEAN
4.05 3.80 3.55 3.89 3.82
STRAW MEAN DM% 86.3 PLOT AREA HARVESTED 0.00796
78
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1986</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[86/W/RN/12
Standard applications:

S. oats: Manures: N at 90 kg as 'Nitram', Weedkillers: Clopyralid at
0.05 kg with bromoxynil octanoate at 0.24 kg and mecoprop at
1.8 kg with the fungicide in 250 1, Fungicide: Tridemorph at
0.56 kg.

W. rye: Manures: N at 30 kg as 'Nitram'.

fifth, sixth, seventh and eighth year leys: Manures: P205 at 140 kg, K20 at
280 kg as (0:18:36), MgO at 50 kg as kieserite.

Seed; S, oats: Dula, sown at 180 kg.
W. rye: Animo, sown at 220 kg.
Cultivations, etc.:-

S. oats: Ploughed: 4 Dec, 1985. Rotary harrowed, seed sown: 10 Apr,
1986. N applied: 30 Apr. Weedkillers and fungicide applied:

30 May. Combine harvested: 14 Aug.

W. rye: Half PK and Mg applied to FERT-FYM plots: 7 Oct, 1985.
Treatment FYM and STRAW applied, al] plots ploughed, remaining PK
applied to FERT-FYM, PK applied to FERT-STRAW, PK applied to STRAW
plots: 7 Nov. Rolled, Mg applied to FERT-FYM, FERT-STRAW and
STRAW plots: 8 Nov. Heavy spring-tine cultivated: 12 Nov. Rotary
harrowed, seed sown: 13 Nov. N applied: 30 Apr, 1986. Combine
harvested: 29 Aug.

fifth, sixth, seventh and eighth year leys: PK and Mg applied: 29 Nov, 1985.
All leys cut: 16 June, 1986. sixth and eighth year leys topped:

25 July. fifth and seventh year leys cut: 12 Nov.

GRAIN TONNES/HEC TARE
waeee TABLES OF MEANS *****
MANURE FYM STRAW FERT-FYM FERT-STR MEAN
4.86 4.55 4.09 4.15 4.41
GRAIN MEAN DM% 79.5
STRAW TONNES/HEC TARE
wee TABLES OF MEANS tkkee
MANURE FYM STRAW FERT-FYM FERT-STR MEAN
1.92 2.67 1.81 1.94 2.09
STRAW NEAN DM% 71.8
PLOT AREA HARVESTED 0.00796
75
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1987</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[87/W/RN/12
W. oats tested:

MANURE Organic manures and fertilizers in 1986 (not applied
in 1987), cumulative to 1985, 1983 and 1982 and to
those applied in the preliminary period:

FYM Farmyard manure at 50 tonnes

STRAW Straw at 7.5 tonnes plus P205 at 140 kg, K20 at 140 kg,
UgO at 50 kg

FERT~FYM P205 at 280 kg, K20 at 560 kg, MgO at 100 kg

FERT=STR P205 at 140 kg, K20 at 280 kg, MgO at 50 kg

All leys were clover grass (LC) without N. sixth year leys tested:

PREV LEY Previous ley:

ete clover grass ley in preliminary period

LC(LN Grass Tey with N in preliminary period

eighth year leys tested:

PREV MAN Previous manure:

1C (GM) Green manures in preliminary period

LC(PT) Peat in preliminary period

Standard applications;

W. wheat: Manures: (0:18:36) at 560 kg. Mn at 0.16 kg as manganese
sulphate in 240 1 applied with the prochloraz, carbendazim and
growth regulator. Weedkillers: Glyphosate at 1.4 kg fn 200 1.
Chiortolturon at 5.6 kg in 200 1. Clopyraltd at 0.07 kg,
bromoxynil at 0.34 kg with mecoprop at 2.5 kg in 240 ,
Fungicides: Prochtoraz at 0.34 kg with carbendazim at 0.13 kg.
Fenpropimorph at 0.75 kg with chlorothalonil at 0.75 kg in 200 1.
Propiconazole at 0.12 kg with carbendazim and maneb (as 'Septa}'
at 2.5 kg) in 200 1. Growth regulator: Chlormequat chloride at
1,1 kg. Insecticide: Carbofuran at 7.5 kg. Molluscicide:
Methiocarb at 0.22 kg.

W. oats: Manure: N at 90 kg as 'Nitram', Weedkiller: Clopyralid at
0.07 kg, bromoxynil at 0.34 kg with mecoprop at 2.5 kg in 240 1.

sixth and eighth years leys: Manures: MgO at 50 kg as kieserite.
(0:18:36) at 780 kg.

Seed: W. wheat: Mercia, sown at 190 kg.
W. oats: Bulwark, Sown at 140 kg.
Cultivations, etc.:-

W. wheat: After leys only: Plough and roll: 25 July, 1986.
Subsoiled, with 25 cm wings on tines 30 cm deep and 70 cm apart,
tn two directions at right angles: 28 Aug. Al) wheat plots:
Glyphosate applied: 16 Sept. Methiocarb applied: 18 Sept.
Ploughed plots after oats: 24 Sept. PK applied, insecticide
applied, rotary harrowed with crumbler attached: 24-Sept. Seed
sown: 25 Sept. Chlortoluron applied: 9 Oct. Clopyralid,
bromoxynt] and mecoprop applied: 14 Apr, 1987. N treatments
applied: 16 Apr. Manganese, prochloraz, carbendazim and
chlormequat applied: 21 Apr, Fenpropimorph and chlorothalonil
applied: 5 June, Propiconazole, carbendazim and maneb applied:
29 June. Combine harvested: 1 Sept.

W. oats: Ploughed: 25 Sept, 1986. Rotary cultivated with crumbler
attached, seed sown: 2 Oct. Clopyralid, bromoxyni! and mecoprop
applied: 27 Apr, 1987. N applied: 5 May. Combine harvested:
20 Aug. .

sixth and eighth years leys: PK and Mg applied: 10 Mar, 1987, Cut:

18 June and 12 Aug.

GRAIN TONNES/HEC TARE
#axxk Tables of means *****
N 0 50 100 150 200 250 Mean
TREATMNT
LC 8 GM 5.23 7.74 8.46 8.72 8.40 7.78 7.72
LC 8 PT 5.32 7.37 7.51 8.43 8.37 8.39 7.57
Lc 6 LC 5.98 7,04 8.59 8.49 7.62 8.40 7.69
Lc 6 LN 6.15 7.73 8.05 7.97 8.60 8.21 7.78
FYM 4.03 5.82 7.22 6.48 7.51 8.00 6.51
STRAW 2.95 3.89 5.82 7.16 6.50 7.75 5.68
FERT-FYM 1.36 3.05 4.48 5.06 §.25 5.77 4.16
FERT-STR 2.07 4.18 4.92 4.84 5.15 6.19 4.56
Mean 4.14 5.85 6.88 7.14 7.18 7.56 6.46
**xt Standard errors of differences of means ***
Table TREATMNT N TREATMNT
N
$.e.d. 0.832 0.192 0.968
Except when comparing means with the same level(s) of
TREA TMNT 0.543
«eee Stratum Standard errors and coefficients of variation *****
Stratum d.f. $.e. cv%
BLOCK .WP 7 0,832 12.9
BLOCK .WP.SP 40 0.543 8.4
GRAIN MEAN DM% 81.6
SUB PLOT AREA HARVESTED 0,00254
66
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1988</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[88/W/RN/12 ;
second test crop potatoes tested all combinations of:

Whole plots

1. TREATMNT Previous treatments, after w. wheat 1987:

LC 8 GM Eight-year clover grass ley until 1986, green manure in

the preliminary period

LC 8 PT As above, peat in the preliminary period

“we 6 ic Six-year clover grass ley until 1986, clover grass ley

in the preliminary period

LC 6 LN As above, grass ley with N in the preliminary period

FYM Farmyard manure annually 1981 to 1985 and in the

preliminary period

STRAW Straw in both periods

FERT-FYM Fertilizers only in both periods, rates of P, K & Mg

equivalent to amounts in FYM

FERT-STR Fertilizers only in both periods, rates of P, K & Mg

equivalent to amounts in straw (+P)
Sub plots
2.N Nitrogen fertilizer in 1988 (kg N) as 'Nitro-Chalk':
0
70
140
210
280
350
Standard applications:

lst test crop:

W. wheat: Manures: (0:18:36) at 560 kg. Mn at 0.16 kg as
manganese sulphate in 220 1. Weedkillers: Glyphosate at 1.4 kg
in 200 1. Isoproturon at 2.1 kg with bromoxynil at 0.20 kg,
ioxynil at 0.20 kg and mecoprop at 1.6 kg in 220 1.
Fungicides: Propiconazole at 0.12 kg and tridemorph at 0.25 kg
in 220 1. Insecticide: Carbofuran at 7.5 kg. Molluscicide:
Methiocarb at 0.22 kg.

second test crop:

Potatoes: Manures: (0:18:36) at 1400 kg. Weedkillers: Glyphosate
at 1.4 kg in 200 1. Linvuron at 1.$ kg in 220 1. Fungicides:
Mancozeb at 1.4 kg in 220 1 on five occasions applied with the
Pirimicarb on the first, second and fifth. Fentin hydroxide at
0.28 kg in 220 1. Insecticide: Pirimicarb at 0.14 kg on three
occasions. Nematicide: Oxamyl at 5.0 kg. Desiccant: Diquat at
0.80 kg ion in 400 1.

Seed: W. wheat: Mercia, sown at 190 kg.

Potatoes: Pentland Crown.

Cultivations, etc. :-

W. wheat: Glyphosate applied: 22 Sept, 1987. Subsoiled, tines 56 cm
deep and 142 cm apart: 6 Oct. Ploughed: 14 Oct. Methiocarb
applied: 21 Oct. PK applied: 22 Oct. Carbofuran applied, power
harrowed, seed sown, harrowed: 23 Oct. Isoproturon, bromoxynil,
ioxynil and mecoprop applied: 26 Apr, 1988. N treatments applied:
27 Apr. Manganese applied: 5 May. Fungicides applied: 22 June.
Combine harvested: 26 Aug.


Potatoes: Glyphosate applied: 22 Sept, 1987. Ploughed: 24 Feb, 1988.
Heavy spring-tine cultivated: 5 Apr. PK applied: 8 Apr. N
treatments applied: 14 Apr. Oxamyl epplied, spring-tine
cultivated: 20 Apr. Rotary harrowed, potatoes planted: 21 Apr.
Rotary ridged, linuron applied: 13 May. Mancozeb applied: 15 July
and 1 Aug. Mancozeb applied with pirimicarb: 14 June, 5 July and
1S Aug. Fentin hydroxide applied: 30 Aug. Desiccant applied:
1S Sept. Haulm mechanically destroyed: 29 Sept. Potatoes lifted:
19 Oct.

NOTES: (1) W. wheat: Because of water logging the yield of one plot was
lost, with treatments FERT-FYM 0. An estimated value was used
in the analysis.

f2) Potatoes: Because of a weighing error yields from two plots
were lost. Those with treatment combinations
LC 6 LN LC 6 LN
140 350
Estimated values were used in the analysis.

WINTER WHEAT

GRAIN TONNES/HECTARE

eeaee Tables of means *****

N 9 $0 100 150 200 250 Mean
TREATMNT
Lc 8 GM 4.42 5.78 6.41 5.66 $.77 6.83 §.81
LC 8 PT 3.89 5.45 6.04 6.85 6.35 6.21 5.80
LC 6 LC 4.39 6.16 7.13 6.27 6.96 7.04 6.32
LC 6 LN 4.30 6.91 6.85 6.36 293 6.22 6.36
FYM 3.94 5.44 5.69 $.82 6.60 6.63 5.68
STRAW 2.81 3.78 5.12 3.77 4.46 3.92 3.98
FERT~FYM 1.96 2.64 3.71 4.00 2.79 3.03 3.02
FERT-STR 2.30 3.18 4.26 3.72 4.67 4.82 3.82
Mean 3.50 4.92 5.65 5.31 5.64 5.58 $5.10
*** Standard errors of differences of means ***
TREATMNT N TREATMNT
N
0.272 0.233 0.660
Except when comparing means with the same level(s) of
TREATMNT 0.658

*eee* Stratum standard errors and coefficients of variation *****

Stratum d.f. 8.e. cvt

BLOCK . WP 7 0.272 5.3

BLOCK .WP. SP 39 0.658 12.9

GRAIN MEAN DM$ 79.5

SUB PLOT AREA HARVESTED 0.00252

63
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1989</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[89/W/RN/12
second test crop potatoes, after w. wheat 1988, tested all combinations of:
Whole plots
1. TREATMNT Previous treatments:
LC 8 GM Bight-year clover grass ley until 1987, green manure in
the preliminary period
Le 8 PT As above, peat in the preliminary period
“LC 61 Six-year clover grass ley until 1987, clover grass ley
< in the preliminary period
LC 6 LN As above, grass ley with N in the preliminary period
FYM Farmyard manure annually 1981 to 1986 and in the
preliminary period
STRAW Straw in both periods
FERT-FYM Fertilizers only in both pericds, rates of P, K & Mg
. equivalent to amounts in FYM
. FERT~STR Fertilizers only in both periods, rates of P, K & Mg
equivalent to amounts in straw (+P)
Sub plots
2.4N Nitrogen fertilizer in 1989 (kg N) as 'Nitram':
0
70 .
140
210
280
350
Standard applications:
second test crop:

Potatoes: Manures: Magnesian limestone at 5.0 t. Kieserite at
$80 kg. (0:18:36) at 1380 kg. Weedkiller: Linuron at 1.2 kg
in 220 1. Fungicides: Mancozeb at 1.4 kg in 220 1 on two
occasions and at 2.0 kg in 220 1 on two occasions. Fentin
hydroxide at 0.28 kg in 220 1. Nematicide: Oxamyl at 5 kg.
Desiccant: Dilute sulphuric acid at 280 1.

third test crop:

W. wheat: Manures: Magnesian limestone at 5.0 t. (0:18:36) at
560 kg/ha. Mn at 0.096 kg as manganese sulphate in 220 1,
applied on two occasions. Weedkillers: Mecoprop at 2.5 kg with
bromoxynil at 0.34 kg and clopyralid at 0.07 kg in 220 1.
Fungicides: Prochloraz at 0.40 kg and carbendazim at 0.15 kg
applied with the growth regulator in 220 1. Propiconazole at
0.12 kg in 220 1. Fenpropimorph at 0.75 kg with carbendazim at
0.25 kg and maneb at 1.6 kg in 220 1. Molluscicide: Methiocarb
at 0.20 kg, also applied with seed. Nematicide: Carbofuran at
7.5 kg. Growth regulator: Chlormequat chloride at 1.6 kg.

Seed: Potatoes: Pentland Crown dressed 'Seedtect'.
W. wheat: Mercia, sown at 160 kg with methiocarb pellets.
Cultivations, etc. :-

Potatoes: Magnesian limestone applied: 28 Oct, 1988. Ploughed $9 Dec,
Kieserite applied: 3 Jan, 1989. PK applied: 4 Jan. Spring-tine
cultivated: 4 May. N applied: S May. Nematicide applied: 6 May.
Rotary cultivated, seed planted: 9 May. Weedkiller applied: 25
May. Mancozeb applied: 6, 17, 28 July and 16 Aug. Fentin
hydroxide applied: 31 Aug. Desiccant applied: 25 Sept.

Lifted: 6 Oct.
W. wheat: Ploughed: 27 Oct, 1988. Magnesian limestone applied:
28 Oct. Molluscicide applied: 29 Oct. PK applied, nematicide
applied, spring-tine cultivated, seed sown: 31 Oct. Weedkillers
applied: 28 Apr, 1989. Mn applied: 29 Apr, 22 May. N applied: 2
May. Prochloraz, carbendazim and growth regulator applied: 17
May. Propiconazole applied: 5 June. Fenpropimorph, carbendazim
and maneb applied: 3 July. Combine harvested: & Aug.
GRAIN TONNES/HECTARE
seee* Tables of means *****
N ° 50 109 150 200 250 Mean
TREATMNT
1c 8 GM 3.00 5.06 6.01 6.92 6.8€ 6.28 5.68
le 8 PT 3.06 5.67 5.63 6.84 6.16 6.42 5.63
wen 3.07 4.28 6.03 6.46 6.62 6.09 5.43

1 6 LN 3.20 §.41 6.22 6.97 6.43 7.34 $.93
FYM 2.48 3.64 4.98 $.28 5.99 6.30 4.77

STRAW 2.57 3.52 4.30 3327 5.46 5.80 4.49

PERT-FYM 1.32 3.31 4.92 4.21 $.24 $.40 4.07
FERT-STR 1.06 2.70 3.65 3.96 4.21 4.56 3.34
Mean 2.47 4.20 5.22 5.73 5.86 6.02 4.92
*** Standard errors of differences of means ***
TREATMNT N TREATMNT
N
0.437 0.242 0.760
Except when comparing means with the same level(s) of
TREATMNT 0.681
sees Stratum standard errors and coefficients of variation *****
Stratum d.f. $.e. eve
BLOCK. WP 7 0.437 8.9
BLOCK.WP .SP 40 0.681 13.9
GRAIN MEAN DM% 87.7
SUB PLOT AREA HARVESTED 0.00252
61
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1990</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[90/W/RN/12

fourth test crop w. beans, after w.wheat 1987, potatoes 1988, w. wheat
1989, tested all combinations of:

Whole plots

1. TREATMNT Previous treatments:

1 8 GM Eight-year clover grass ley until 1986, green manure in

the preliminary period

LC 8 PT As above, peat in the preliminary period

i 6 1c Six-year clover grass ley until 1986, clover grass ley

in the preliminary period

Lc 6 LN As above, grass ley with N in the preliminary period

FYM Farmyard manure annually 1981 to 1985 and in the

preliminary period

STRAW Straw in both periods

FERT-FYM Fertilizers only in both periods, rates of P, K and Mg

equivalent to amounts in FYM

FERT-STR Fertilizers only in both periods rates of P, K and Mg

equivalent to amounts in straw (+P)
Sub plots
2. N RES Residues of nitrogen fertilizer to w. wheat in 1989
(kg N):
(0)
(50)

(100) .

(150)

(200)

(250)

Standard applications:

third test crop:

W. wheat: Manures: (0:18:36) at 560 kg. Weedkillers; Bromoxynil
at 0.34 kg and clopyralid at 0.07 kg with isoproturon at 2.1 kg
and fluroxypyr at 0.15 kg in 220 1. Fungicides: Propiconazole
at 0.12 kg with chlorothalonil at 0.50 kg in 300 1.
Insecticide: Carbofuran at 7.5 k. Molluscicide: Methiocazrb
at 0.20 kg applied with seed.

fourth test crop:

W. beans: Manures: (0:24:24) at 420 kg. Muriate of potash at
170 kg. Manganese at 0.19 xg in 220 1. Weedkillers: Paraquat at
0.80 kg ion in 220 1. Propyzamide at 0.85 kg with simazine at
0.85 kg in 220 1. Fungicide: Fenpropimorph at 0.75 kg in
220 1. Insecticide: Deltamethrin at 7.5 g in 220 1 applied on
two occasions.

Seed: W. wheat: Mercia, sown at 180 kg with methiocarb pellets.

W. beans: Banner, sown at 18 seeds per square metre.

Cultivations, etc.:-

W. wheat: Ploughed: 20 Oct, 1989. Carbofuran applied, spring-tine
cultivated: 30 Oct. PK applied: 31 Oct. Seed sown: 1 Nov. N
applied: 27 Mar, 1990. Weedkillers applied: 24 Apr. Fungicides
applied: 22 May. Combine harvested: 3 Aug.


W. beans: Subsoiled with tines, 50 cm apart and 40 cm deep: 13 Sept,
1989. Disced: 15 Sept. PK and K applied: 19 Sept. Paraquat
applied: 10 Oct. Disced: 12 Oct. Seed broadcast by drill,
ploughed in and rolled: 13 Oct. Propyzamide and simazine applied:
15 Oct. Mn applied: 5 Apr, 1990. Deltamethrin applied: 23 Apr
and 18 May. Fenpropimoxrph applied: 11 July. Combine harvested:

10 Aug.

NOTES: (1) W. wheat. Because of bird damage and errors in harvesting,
the yields of one whole plot and 2 sub plots were lost, with
treatment combinations TREATMNT FERT-STR FERT-STR

N 100 150
and FERT-FYM whole plot (6 sub plots)
Estimated values were used in the analysis.
(2) W. beans. Because of bird damage the yields of one block
were treated as lost. The means presented are those of the
: remaining block.


GRAIN TONNES /HECTARE '

axexe Tables of means *****

_“ nu 0 50 100 150 200 250 Mean

TREATMNT

Le 8 GM 3.00 4.53 5.65 4.95 5.53 5.68 4.89

1c 8 PT 3.11 5.47 7.02 6.63 6.38 6.53 $.86

wew 3.65 5.65 7.90 6.41 6.28 6.63 5.94

1c 6 LN 3.72 $.88 6.70 6.79 6.37 6.32 5.96

¥FYM 3323 5.27 5.02 6.13 6.02 §.25 5.14
STRAW 3.18 5.20 6.25 6.63 6.08 6.23 5.59

FPERT-FYM 2.99 4.62 5.97 6.81 5.10 5.61 $.18

FERT-STR 2.53 4.87 5.15 4.74 6.38 5.68 4.89
Mean 3.18 5.17 6.09 6.14 6.02 $5.99 $.43

*** Standard errors of differences of means ***

TREATMNT N TREATUNT
. N
0.419 0.150 0.570
Except when comparing means with the same level(s) of
TREATMNT 0.424

*taeex Stratum standard errors and coefficients of variation *****

Stratum d.f, s.e. evt

BLOCK.WP - 6 0.419 7.7

BLOCK.WP.SP 33 0.424 7.8

GRAIN MEAN DM@ 90.4

SUB PLOT AREA HARVESTED 0.00183

50
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1991</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[91/W/RN/12
Sth test crop w. wheat, after w. wheat 1987, potatoes 1988, w. wheat '
1989, w. beans 1990 tested all combinations of:
Whole plots
1. TREATMNT -Previous treatments:
Le 8 GM Eight-year clover grass ley until 1986, green manure in
the preliminary period
Lc 8 PT As above, peat in the preliminary period
Lc 6 Le Six-year clover grass ley until 1986, clover grass ley
in the preliminary period
Lc 6 LN As above, grass ley with N in the preliminary period
FYM Farmyard manure annually 1981 to 1985S and in the
preliminary period
STRAW Straw in both periods
FERT-FYM Fertilizers only in both periods, rates of P, K and Mg
equivalent to amounts in FYM
FERT-STR Fertilizers only in both periods rates of P, K and Mg
equivalent to amounts in straw (+P)
Sub plots
2. uN Nitrogen fertilizer to w. wheat in 1991 (kg N as 'Nitro-
Chalk'):
9
50
100
150
200
250
Standard applications:
fourth test crop:
W. beans: Manures: (0:16:36) at 560 kg. Manganese at 0.16 kg in
300 1. Weedkillers: Glyphosate at 0.54 kg in 220 1. Simazine
at 0.14 kg and trietazine at 0.97 kg in 220 1. Pungicides:
Chlorothalonil at 1.5 kg applied with the pirimicarb in 300 1.
Insecticides: Azinphos-methyl at 0.28 kg and demeton-S-methyl
sulphone at 0.085 kg in 400 1. Pirimicarb at 0.14 kg.
Sth test crop:
W. wheat: Manures: (0:16:36) at 560 kg. Manganese at 0.16 kg in
300 1. Weedkillers: Glyphosate at 0.54 kg in 220 1. §
Diflufenican at 0.10 kg and isoproturon at 1.0 kg applied with
insecticide in 220 1. Mecoprop at 0.80 kg also applied with
insecticide in 220 1. Fungicides: Fenpropimorph at 0.38 kg in
210 1, and on a second occasion with chlorothalonil at 0.49 kg
and flutriafol at 0.078 kg in 300 1. Insecticide: Deltamethrin _
at 5.0 g on two occasions.
Seed: W. beans: Banner, sown at 120 kg.
W. wheat: Mercia, sown at 150 kg. .
Cultivations, etc. :-
W. beans: Glyphosate applied: 10 Sept, 1990. P and K applied:
27 Sept. Disced: 12 Oct. Seed broadcast, ploughed: 23 Oct.
Remaining weedkillers applied: 21 Nov. Manganese applied: 9 May,
1991. Azinphos-methyl and demeton-S-methyl sulphone applied:
10 May. Chlorothalonil and pirimicarb applied: 10 July. Combine
harvested: 3 Sept.
W. wheat: Glyphosate applied: 10 Sept, 1990. Ploughed: 19 Sept. P
and K applied, rotary harrowed with crumbler attached, seed sown:
27 Sept. Diflufenican, isoproturon and deltamethrin applied:
8 Nov. Mecoprop and deltamethrin applied: 30 Nov. Nitrogen
treatments applied: 4 Apr, 1991. Fenpropimorph applied: 24 May.
Manganese applied: 19 May. Fenpropimorph, chlorothalonil and
flutriafol applied: 20 June. Combine harvested: 22 Aug.
GRAIN TONNES/HECTARE
skeet Tables of means *****
N (0) (50) (100) (150) (200) (250) Mean
TREATMNT
Le 8 GM 4.53 4.24 4.83 3.75 4.73 4.37 4.41
Le 8 PT 4.98 4.88 4.87 4.91 §.05 4.90 4.93
Le 6 LC 5.06 5.27 4.93 4.42 4.85 $.28 4.97
Le 6 LN 5.23 5.10 4.91 4.74 4.41 4.75 4.86
FYM 4.35 4.29 4.31 4.46 4.51 4.52 4.41
STRAW 4.81 4.88 4.85 4.81 4.68 $.18 4.87
FERT-FYM 4.06 4.08 4.14 4.15 4.16 4.70 4.21
FERT-STR 5.08 4.90 5.02 4.49 4.89 5.01 4.90
Mean 4.76 4.70 4.73 4.47 4.66 4.84 4.69
*** Standard errors of differences of means ***
TREATMNT WN RES TREATMNT
N RES
0.461 0.151 0.604
Except when comparing means with the same level(s) of
TREATMNT 0,428
xeeee Stratum standard errors and coefficients of variation *****
Stratum d.f. 3.e. cvt
BLOCK .WP 7 0.461 9.8
BLOCK .WP .SP 40 0.428 9.1
GRAIN MEAN DM¥ 86.3
SUB PLOT AREA HARVESTED 0.00192
44
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1992</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots
18-Sep-91 : B : CROPSEQ WHEAT 1: Bean straw baled and carted.
25-Sep-91 : B : Ploughed.
02-Oct-91 : B : Rolled.
03-Oct-91 : B : PK as (0:16:36) at 560 kg. Rotary harrowed, Mercia drilled at 140 kg.
30-Oct-91 : B : Stomp 400 at 2.5 1, Arelon WDG at 0.75 kg and Decis at 0.20 1 in 200 1.
18-Mar-92 : B : Vytel Liquid Chelated Manganese (Chelated Mn as Mn EDTA in solution equivalent to 6.4% w/v Mn) at 2.5 1 in200 1.
01-Apr-92 : B : Duplosan New System CMPP at 1.5 1 in 200 1.
09-Apr-92 : T : 27.5% N 50 kgN/ha
09-Apr-92 : T : 27.5% N 100 kgN/ha
09-Apr-92 : T : 27.5% N 150 kgN/ha
09-Apr-92 : T : 27.5% N 200 kgN/ha
09-Apr-92 : T : 27.5% N 250 kgN/ha
03-May-92 : B : Dorin at 1.0 1 in 300 1.
09-Jun-92 : B : Impact Excel at 2.0 1 in 200 1.
01-Aug-92 : T : CROPSEQ WHEAT 2: Combine harvested.
01-Sep-92 : T : CROPSBQ WHEAT 1: Combine harvested.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1993</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots
11-Aug-92 : T : CROPSEQ WHEAT 3: Subsoiled to 45 cm with tines 1.5 m apart.
05-Oct-92 : B : Ploughed.
06-Oct-92 : B : PK as (0:18:36) at 560 kg.
07-Oct-92 : B : Rotary harrowed, Mercia, dressed Cerevax, drilled at 380 seeds per square metre.
13-Apr-93 : T : 27.5% N 50 kgN/ha
13-Apr-93 : T : 27.5% N 100 kgN/ha
13-Apr-93 : T : 27.5% N 150 kgN/ha
13-Apr-93 : T : 27.5% N 200 kgN/ha
13-Apr-93 : T : 27.5% N 250 kgN/ha
15-Apr-93 : B : Ally at 30 g and New SC Cycocel at 2.5 1 in 200 1.
01-Jun-93 : B : Bayleton at 0.50 kg and Mistral at 0.50 1 in 200 l.
19-Aug-93 : B : Roundup at 5.3 1 in 200 1.
25-Aug-93 : B : Combine harvested.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1994</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots
10-Sep-93 : B : Ploughed.
16-Oct-93 : B : Rotary harrowed, Mercia, dressed Panoctine, drilled at 325 seeds per m'.
11-Apr-94 : T : 27.5% N 50 kgN/ha
11-Apr-93 : T : 27.5% N 100 kgN/ha
11-Apr-93 : T : 27.5% N 150 kgN/ha
11-Apr-93 : T : 27.5% N 200 kgN/ha
11-Apr-93 : T : 27.5% N 250 kgN/ha.
01-May-94 : B : Oxytril CM at 1.5 1 with Duplosan New System CMPP at 2.0 1 and Halo at 1.5 1 in 200 1.
24-May-94 : B : Vytel Liquid Chelated Manganese (chelated Mn as Mn EDTA in solution equivalent to 6.4% w/v M:) at 1.5 1 in 200 1.
30-May-94 : B : Cyclone at 1.0 1 with Mistral at 0.5 1 in 200 1.
14-Jun-94 : B : Hostathion at 0.84 1 in 200 1.
21-Aug-94 : T : CROPSEQ WHEAT 4: Combine harvested.
22-Aug-94 : 2 : CROPSEQ WHEAT 3: Combine harvested.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1995</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots:
09-Sep-94 : B : Dolomite at 7.5 ct.
26-Sep-94 : B : Barclay Gallup at 4.0 1 in 200 1.
03-Oct-94 : B : Ploughed.
07-Oct-94 : B : Rotary harrowed, Mercia, dressed Rappor, drilled at 300 seeds per m*.
28-Nov-94 : B : Panther at 2.0 1 with Decis at 0.20 1 in 200 1.
21-Apr-95 : B : 34.5% N 100 kgN/ha at 290 kg.
28-Apr-95 : B : Halo at 2.0 1 in 200 1.
01-Jun-95 : B : Cyclone at 1.0 1 with Mallard at 0.30 1 in 200 1.
29-Jun-95 : B : Pirimicarb 50 DG at 280 g in 300 1.
03-Aug-95 : B : Combine harvested. 
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1996</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots
15-Sep-95 : B : Ploughed.
23-Sep-95 : B : Rolled.
03-Oct-95 : B : Rotary harrowed, Mercia, dressed Sibutol, drilled at 375 seeds per ni'.
13-Nov-95 : B : Panther at 2.0 1 in 200 1.
02-Apr-96 : B : Vytel Manganese at 3.0 1 in 300 1.
16-Apr-96 : B : 34.5% N at 100 kgN/ha in 290 kg.
30-Apr-96 : B : Halo at 1.5 1 in 200 1.
06-Jun-96 : B : Silvacur at 1.0 1 in 300 1.
17-Aug-96 : B : Combine harvested.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1997</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots
27-Sep-96 : B : Ploughed.
28-Sep-96 : B : Rolled.
30-Sep-96 : B : PK as (0:20:32) at 500 kg.
01-Oct-96 : B : Rotary harrowed, Amando, dressed Baytan Flowable, drilled at 400 seeds per m.
11-Dec-96 : B : Stomp 400 SC at 3.3 1 in 200 1.
04-Jun-97 : B : Mistral at 1.0 2 in 300 1.
12-Aug-97 : B : Combine harvested.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1998</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots:
17-Sep-97 : 3 : Ploughed. Rolled.
29-Sep-97 : B : PK as (0:20:32) at 500 kg.
30-Sep-97 : B : Rotary harrowed, Mereward, dressed Sibutol, drilled at 385 seeds per m.
13-Nov-97 : B : Stomp 400 SC at 2.0 1 with Isoproturon 500 at 1.0 1 and Cyperkill 10 at 0.25 1 in 200 2.
19-Mar-98 : B : Mn and Cu as Phosyn Manganese at 2.0 1 with Profol Copper at 0.25 1 in 200 1.
31-Mar-98 : B : 34.5% N at 278 kg.
04-May-98 : B : Alto 100 SL at 0.6 1 in 200 1.
29-May-98 : B : Ally at 15 g in 200 1.
31-May-98 : B : Opus at 0.8 1 in 200 1.
12-Jun-98 : B : Folicur at 0.3 1 with Bavistin DF at 0.3 kg in 200 1.
02-Aug-98 : B : Roundup Biactive at 3.0 1 in 200 1.
12-Aug-98 : B : Combine harvested.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1999</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots
27-Aug-38 : B : Ploughed.
29-Aug-98 : B : Cambridge rolled.
19-Sep-98 : B : PK as (0:24:24) at 217 kg. Muriate of potash at 52 kg
12-Oct-98 : B : Rotary harrowed. Drilled, Hereward, tr. Sibutol, at 380 seeds/m® with the Accord drill.
25-Feb-99 : B : Platform S at 1.0 kg with Isoguard at 2.0 1 in 2001.
03-Apr-99 : B : 34.5% N at 278 kg.
25-Apr-99 : B : Tripart Brevis at 2.0 1 with Folicur at 0.5 1 in 2001.
27-May-99 : B : Folicur at 0.75 1 with Sipcam UK Rover 500 at 1.0 1 in 200 1.
22-Aug-99 : B : Combine harvested.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>2000</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots
13-Sep-99 : B : Potassium sulphate at 200 kg. Triple superphosphate at 106 kg.
14-Sep-99 : B : Ploughed,
17-Sep-99 : B : Rolled.
03-Oct-99 : B : Spring-tine cultivated.
04-Oct-99 : B : Rotary harrowed. Drilled, Hereward, tr. Sibutol, at 380 seeds/m? with the Accord drill.
11-Nov-99 : B : Hallmark at 100 mi in 100 1.
31-Dec-99 : B : Panther at 2.0 1 in 200 1.
21-Mar-00 : B : tm)Ally at 30 g in 200 1.
: B : tm)Topik at 125 ml in 200 1.
: B : tm)Cropoil at 1.0 1 in 200 1.
11-Apr-00 : B : 34.5% N at 278 kg.
30-Apr-00 : B : tm)Marshland Liquid Manganese Complex at 2.0 1 in 200 1.
: B : tm)Opus at 0.3 1 in 200 1.
: B : tm)BASF 3C Chlormequat 720 at 2.0 1 in 200 1.
20-May-00 : B : Opus at 0.75 1 in 200 1.
20-Aug-00 : B : Combine harvested,
25-Aug-00 : B : Straw baled and carted.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>2001</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots:
01-Sep-00 : B : Potassium sulphate at 200 kg.
: B : Triple superphosphate at 106 kg.
03-Sep-00 : B : : Azural at 4.0 1 in 200 1.
26-Sep-00 : B : Ploughed.
04-Oct-00 : B : Rotary harrowed.
: B : WW: Drilled, Claire, tr. Sibutol + Rhodoman, at 350 seeds/m*, with the 4.0 m Accord drill.
20-Oct-00 : B : Avadex Excel 15 g at 15.0 kg.
18-Jan-01 : B : tm)Stomp 400 SC at 2.0 1 in 200 l.
: B : tm)Tolkan liquid at 1.01 in 200 l.
29-Mar-01 : T : Nl : 33.5% N at 119 kg.
: T : N2 : 33.5% N at 119 kg.
08-May-01 : B : tm)Landmark at 0.5 1 in 200 l.
: B : tm)BASF 3C Chlormequat 720 at 2.0 1 in 200 1.
: B : Harmony M at 75 g in 200 l.
11-May-01 : T : N1 : 33.5% N at 238 kg.
: T : N2 : 33.5% N at 238 kg
18-May-2001 : T : topped up with 33.5% N at 119 kg
0l-Jun-01 : B : Landmark at 0.7 1 in 200 1.
06-Jun-01 : T : N2 : 33.5% N at 119 kg.
: T : N2 : 33.5% N at 119 kg.
22-Aug-01 : B : Combine harvested, plots for yield, and discards.
: B : Swathed straw.
23-Aug-01 : B : Baled.
06-Sep-01 : B : Carted bales.
10-Sep-01 : B : Azural at 4.0 1 in 200 l.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>2002</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots:
20-Sep-01 : B : Sulphate of potash at 200 kg. 
20-Sep-01 : B : Triple superphosphate at 106 kg. 
20-Sep-01 : B : Ploughed.
21-Sep-01 : B : Rolled.
22-Sep-01 : B : Drilled, Claire, tr. Sibutol + Aventis Manganese 500, at 300 seeds/m? with 4.0 m Accord drill.
13-Oct-01 : T : Avadex Excel 15g at 15.0 kg.
16-Nov-01 : B : tm)Stomp 400 SC at 4.0 1 in 200 l.
: B : tm)Tolkan liquid at 2.5 1 in 200 l.
12-Mar-02 : T : 1st N split applied as 33.5% N.
09-Apr-02 : T : 2nd N split applied as 33.5% N.
14-Apr-02 : B : tm)Ally at 30 g in 200 l.
: B : tm)Opus at 0.5 1 in 200 l.
: B : tm)BASF 3C Chlormequat 720 at 2.0 1 in 200 l.
08-May-02 : T : 3rd N split applied as 33.5% N.
27-May-02 : B : tm)Amistar at 0.8 1 in 200 l.
: B : tm)Opus at 0.5 1 in 200 l.
22-Aug-02 : T : Combine harvested, plots for yield.
24-Aug-02 : P : Combine harvested all remaining wheat. Swathed straw. Baled and removed straw.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>2003</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots:
19-Sep-02 : B : CleanCrop Egret at 4.0 1 in 200 l
25-Sep-02 : B : Chalk applied at 5.0 t.
01-Oct-02 : B : Ploughed 35cm wide furrows
: B : Rolled.
04-Oct-02 : T : Power harrowed Lc plots.
: T : Rolled Lc plots.
08-Oct-02 : T : Power harrowed rye plots.
: T : Drilled, Picasso/Nikita mix, tr. Baytan, at 302 seeds/m* with 4.0 m Accord drill.
T : : Rolled.
26-Nov-02 : T : tm)Lexus Class WSB at 60 g in 200 l.
: T : tm)Hallmark with Zeon Technology at 25 ml in 200 l. to rye plots.
03-Apr-03 : T : Triple superphosphate at 97.5 (not to Dg25 plots).
: T : Sulphate of potash at 200 kg (not to Dg25 plots).
04-Apr-03 : T : N as 33.5% N applied (not to Dg25, Co or Lc).
06-May-03 : T : Opus at 0.75 1 in 200 1 to rye plots.
07-May-03 : T : Quantum 75 DF at 20 g in 200 1 to rye plots.
15-May-03 : T : Setter 33 at 5.0 1 in 200 1 to Le plots.
10-Aug-03 : T : Combine harvested, plots for yield.
11-Aug-03 : T : Combine harvested all remaining wheat.
: T : Weighted straw.
13-Aug-03 :T : Baled straw.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>2004</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots:
14-Aug-03 : T : Drilled Albatross, White mustard, at 10 kg with Moore Unidrill to CC plots.
22-Sep-03 : T : Chopped straw applied at 7.5 t to St plots.
09-Mar-04 : T : Compost applied at 40 t to CO plots.
10-Mar-04 : T : FYM applied at 25 t to Dg25 plots and at 10 t to Dg10 plots.
12-Mar-04 : B : tm)PDOQ at 5.5 1 in 200 l
: B : tm)Enhance Low Foam at 100 ml in 200 l.
22-Mar-04 : B : Ploughed 35cm wide furrows
12-Apr-04 : B : Power harrowed.
: B : Drilled, Optic, tr. Sibutol, at 400 seeds/m* with 4.0 m Accord drill.
: B : Rolled.
07-May-04 : T : Nitrogen treatments applied as Nitro-chalk 27% N by hand.
24-May-04 T : Sulphate of Potash at 200 kg (not to Dg25)
: T : Triple Superphosphate at 97.5 kg (not to Dg25).
02-Jun-04 : B : Harmony M at 60 6 in 200 1 to barley plots.
03-Jun-04 : B : tm)Opus at 0.4 1 in 200 1 to barley plots.
: B : tm)Acanto at 0.5 1 in 200 1 to barley plots.
06-Jul-04 : T : Cut, samples and weighed grass/clover, Lc plots only.
14-Jul-04 : T : Mowed Lc plots.
15-Jul-04 : T : Turned hay Lc plots.
17-Jul-04 : T : Turned hay Lc plots.
19-Jul-04 : T : Turned hay Lc plots.
20-Jul-04 : T : Rowed up hay and baled Lc plots.
04-Sep-04 : T : Combine harvested, barley plots for yield.
: T : Swathed straw.
08-Aug-04 : T : Baled straw.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>2005</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots
09-Sep-04 : T : Chopped straw applied at 7.5 t to St plots.
11-Nov-04 : B : Glyphosate 360 at 4.0 1 in 200 l.
17-Nov-04 : T : Compost applied at 40 t to CO plots.
: T : FYM applied at 25 t to Dg25 plots and at 10 t to Dg10 plots.
23-Nov-04 : B : Clipper broadcast at 30 seeds/m*, to bean plots.
24-Nov-04 : B : Ploughed 35cm wide furrows, to bean plots.
07-May-05 : T : Sulphate of Potash at 200 kg (not to Dg25).
: T : Triple Superphosphate at 97.5 kg (not to Dg25).
11-May-05 : B : tm)Bravo 500 at 1.0 1 in 200 1 to bean plots.
: B : tm)Folicur at 0.5 1 in 200 1 to bean plots.
: B : tm)Hallmark with Zeon Technology at 0.75 1 in 200 1 to bean plots.
13-Jul-05 18 cut yield strips Lc plots only, weighed and sampled.
01-Aug-05 : T : Topped, Lc plots only.
03-Sep-05 : T : Combine harvested, bean plots for yield, swathed straw.
03-Sep-05 : T : Combine harvested discards, swathed straw.
O8-Sep-05 : T : Baled straw.
20-Dec-05 : T : 2nd cut yield strips Lc plots only, weighed and sampled.
21-Dec-05 : T : Discards mown and cuttings removed.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>2006</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots:
21-Sep-05 : B : Azural at 3.0 1 in 200 l.
11-Oct-05 : T : Chopped wheat straw applied at 7.5 t to St plots.
: T : Compost applied at 40 t to CO plots.
: T : FYM applied at 25 t to Dg25 plots and at 10 t to Dg10 plots.
: B : Ploughed 35cm wide furrows and rolled wheat plots.
14-Oct-05 : B : Power harrowed.
15-Oct-05 : B : Power harrowed, combination drilled Hereward, tr. Sibutol Secur at 350 seeds/m*, wheat plots.
13-Nov-05 : B : : tm)Alpha IPU 500 at 2.0 1 ain 200 1
: B : tm)Stomp 400 SC at 2.5 1 in 200 l
: B : tm)Hallmark with Zeon Technology at 50 ml in 200 1
: B : tm)Mantrac 500 at 1.01 in 200 1, to wheat plots.
01-Mar-06 T : Sulphate of Potash at 200 kg (not to Dg25).
: T : Triple Superphosphate at 97.5 kg (not to Dg25).
13-Mar-06 1st N applied as 27% N to wheat plots.
20-Apr-06 Main dressing applied as 27% N to wheat plots.
24-Apr-06 : B : tm)Bravo 500 at 1.25 1 in 200 1
: B : : tm)Opus at 0.75 1 in 200 1
B tm)Mantrac 500 at 1.25 1 in 200 1 to wheat plots.
16-May-06 tm)Quantum SX at 30 g in 200 l
tm)Copper Man at 2.0 kg in 200 1 to wheat plots.
07-Jun-06 : B : tm)Bravo 500 at 1.01 in 200 1
: B : : tm)Opus at 0.75 1 in 200 1
: B : tm)Vivid at 0.4 1 in 200 1 to wheat plots.
28-Jun-06 1st cut yield strips Lc plots only, weighed and sampled. Mowed discards.
29-Jun-06 : B : Baled.
25-Aug-06 : T : Combine harvested, wheat plots for yield, swathed straw. Combine harvested discards, swathed straw.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>2007</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots
25-Sep-06 p Azural 4.00 V200 Vha
29-Sep-06 a Direct Drill Rivona Mustard, CC plots 350.00 seeds/m?®
27-Mar-07 p Clinic Ace maize plots 4.00 v200lha
12-Apr-07 f DG 10 plots, F.Y.M. 10.00 tha
12-Apr-07 f DG 25 plots, F.Y.M. 25.00 tha
12-Apr-07 f CO plots. Compost 40.00 vha
13-Apr-07 f ST plots, Wheat straw 7.50 vha
13-Apr-07 a Topped ST plots, to chop straw 2.00
16-Apr-07 a Plough / NW
30-Apr-07 t Sulphate of Potash all plots except Dg25 200.00 kg/ha
30-Apr-07 f Triple Superphosphate all plots except Dg25 97.50 kg/ha
01-May-07 a Nodet Drilled Hudson tr Mesurol 10.20 seeds/m?
23-May-07 a Nitraprill - N plots, maize 145.00 kg/ha
01-Jun-07 p Callisto - maize 1.50 ¥200 Vha
11-Jun-07 a 1st cut grass/clover
12-Jun-07 a Turned hay - grass plots
19-Jun-07 a Rowed up hay — grass/clover plots
19-Jun-07 a Baled grass plots
22-Jun-07 a Topped grass/clover plots, to tidy
26-Jun-07 f Nitraprill - Post emergent N, Maize, N2 plots, 145.00 kg/ha
26-Jun-07 f Nitraprill - Post emergent N, Maize, N3 plots, 290.00 kg/ha
26-Jun-07 f Nitraprill - Post emergent N, Maize, N4 plots, 345.00 kg/ha
26-Jun-07 f Nitraprill - Post emergent N, Maize, NS plots, 580.00 kg/ha
25-Jul-07 p Alpha Bromotril P - maize plots 2.50 ¥200 Vvha
19-Sep-07 a Cut harvest strips, weighed and sampled
25-Sep-07 a Mowed maize plots
25-Sep-07 a Baled maize plots
27-Sep-07 a Rowed up and baled remaining maize tops
12-Nov-07 a 2nd cut grass/clover, harvest strips, weighed and sampled
12-Nov-07 a Mowed and baled
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>2008</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots
2-Oct-07 p Azural stubbles 4.00 200 Vha
12-Oct-07 f FYM, Dg 10 plots 10.00 wha
12-Oct-07 f FYM, Dg 25 plots 25.00 wha
12-Oct-07 f Compost, Co plots 40.00 wha
12-Oct-07 f Straw, St plots 7.50 Uha
13-Oct-07 a Topped to chop wheat straw
13-Oct-07 a Plough / SE, completed 14-Oct-07 (Rye plots)
18-Oct-07 a Power harrowed rye plots
23-Oct-07 a Accord Drilled Matador recleaned rye plots 350.00 seeds/m?
23-Oct-07 a Rolled
13-Dec-07 p Stomp 400 SC Rye plots 3.30 200 Vha
14-Mar-08 f Sulphate of potash all except Dg 25 plots 200.00 kg/ha
15-Mar-08 f Triple Superphosphate all except Dg 25 plots 97.50 kg/ha
2-May-08 p Quantum SX rye plots 30.00 9/200 Vha
8-May-08 f Nitraprill N1 plots, completed 9-May-08 87.00 kg/ha
8-May-08 t Nitrapnill N2 plots, completed 9-May-08 174.00 kg/ha
8-May-08 f Nitraprill N3 plots, completed 9-May-08 261.00 kg/ha
8-May-08 f Nitraprill N4 plots, completed 9-May-08 348.00 kg/ha
8-May-08 f Nitrpnill NS plots, completed 9-May-08 435.00 kg/ha
25-Jun-08 a Cut harvest strips, weighed and sampled ley plots
25-Jun-08 a Mowed all grass discards
26-Jun-08 a Rowed up hay Ley plots
26-Jun-08 a Baled Ley plots
14-Sep-08 a Combine harvest discards
14-Sep-08 a Swath straw
18-Sep-08 a Combine harvest, plots for yield
18-Sep-08 a Swath straw
19-Sep-08 a Combine harvest discards
19-Sep-08 a Swath straw
21-Sep-08 a Baled
19-Nov-08 a Cut harvest strips. weighed and sampled, ley plots, second cut
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>2009</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots
30-Sep-08 a Direct drill - CC plots 004, 010, 019 and 032 Zlata (Mustard) - CC plots 10.00 kg/ha
28-Oct-08 f Chopped wheat straw - plots 003,015,017 and 031, all chopped using McConnell topper 7.50 tha
17-Mar-09 s Potassium Sulphate - all plots except 005,011, 023 and 026 200.00 kg/ha
17-Mar-09 t Tripie Superphosphate - all plots except 005, 011, 023 and 026 97.5 kg/ha
19-Mar-09 f FYM, Dg 10 plots 10.00 wha
19-Mar-09 f FYM, Dg 25 plots 25.00 wha
19-Mar-09 f Compost. Co plots 40.00 wha
02-Apr-09 a Combination drilled Tipple Tr Raxil Pro 350.00 seedsim2
02-Apr-09 a Rolled
14-May-09 p Ally 30.00 g/200 l/ha
14-May-09 p Cherokee 1.25 l/200 l/ha
14-May-09 p Cycocel 2.25 l/200 l/ha
14-May-09 p Headland Manganese 500 1.00 l/200 l/ha
14-May-09 p Fandango 1.00 l/200 l/ha
14-May-09 p Flexity 0.20 l/200 l/ha
14-May-09 p Ally Max SX 30.00 g/200 l/ha
14-May-09 p Headland Manganese 500 1.00 l/200 l/ha
28-May-09 a Nitro-chalk N1 plots 130.00 kg/ha
28-May-09 a Nitro-chalk N2 plots 259.00 kg/ha
28-May-09 a Nitro-chalk N3 plots 389.00 kg/ha
28-May-09 a Nitro-chalk N4 plots 519.00 kg/ha
28-May-09 a Nitro-chalk N5 plots 648.00 kg/ha
03-Jun-09 p Opus 0.50 L in 200 Vha
03-Jun-09 p Amistar 0.40 L in 200 Vha
24-Jun-09 a Cut harvest strips ley plots, weighed and sampled
28-Jun-09 a Baled
17-Jul-09 a Topped Ley plots
23-Aug-09 a Combine harvest, plots for yield a Combine harvest, spring barley plots for yield
24-Aug-09 a Combine harvest discards
26-Aug-09 a Baled
02-Sep-09 a Remove bales
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>2010</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots
11-Sep-09 a Load straw 7.50 vha
21-Sep-09 p Nufosate Ace - 200 It water 4.00 Vha
09-Nov-09 f Chalk 5.00 vha
09-Nov-09 a Spread straw
11-Nov-09 f Chalk - Finished 5.00 vha
11-Nov-09 a Spread straw
28-Jan-10 a Compost - Co plots 40.00 Vha
02-Feb-10 a FYM-Dg, 10plot 10.00 vha
03-Feb-10 a FYM-ODG, 25 plot 25.00 Vha
08-Mar-10 a Plough - Bean plots
09-Mar-10 s Combination Drilled Fuego 42.00 s/m2
17-Mar-10 p Skirmish - 200 It water on Beans 1,00 Vha
23-Apr-10 a Harrowed
24-Apr-10 s Combination Drilled Fuego 32.00 seeds/m2
26-May-10 a Baled - Ley plots
24-Jun-10 a Cut harvest strips, weighed and sampled Ley plots
09-Sep-10 a Combine harvest, plots for yield
22-Sep-10 a Baled - removed
10-Oct-10 a Other operation - straw treatments applied as scheduled, chopped and spread
11-Oct-10 f compost - as scheduled
11-Oct-10 f FYM - as scheduled
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>2011</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots
30-Sep-10 p Sprayed Gallup 360 in 2001 4.0 Vha
10-Oct-10 a Straw treatment applied, chopped and spread -Straw plots only.
11-Oct-10 a Compost and FYM treatments applied by manure spreader as scheduled.
12-Oct-10 a Ploughed - With Ransomes 3 furrow. Arable plots only.
14-Oct-10 s Rotary Harrowed, drilled Gallant. dressed Redigo, arable plots only. 360 seeds/m?.
21-Mar-11 f Broadcast Nitrochalk, 27%N Early N application (N1) as scheduled to N1, N2, N3, N4 and N5 plots. 185 kg/ha
25-Mar-11 f Broadcast Potassium Sulphate  - All plots except Dg 25 200 kg/ha
25-Mar-11 f TSP - All plots except Dg 25. 97.5 kg/ha
28-Mar-11 p Sprayed Cherokee 1.25 Vha with Manganese in 200V/ha - Wheat 1.5 Vha
13-Apr-11 f Broadcast Nitrochalk, 27%N. Main N application to wheat, as scheduled - N2, N3, N4 or N5 plots 370-926 kg/ha
11-May-11 p Sprayed Tracker. - Wheat only. 1.0  l/200 l/ha
11-May-11 p Sprayed  Bravo. - Wheat only. 500 1.0  l/200 l/ha
11-May-11 p Sprayed  Justice. - Wheat only. 0.25  l/200 l/ha
11-May-11 p Sprayed  CCC. - Wheat only. 2.25 l/200 l/ha
21-Jun-11 a Yield strip mown, sampled and weighed. - Ley plots only.
22-Jun-11 a Mown with Kuhn. Leys only.
25-Jun-11 a Leys tedded.
26-Jun-11 a Windrowed - Leys only.
27-Jun-11 a Round baled - Ley plots only.
15-Aug-11 p Sprayed Hoedown in 200! - Wheat only. 4.0 Vha
01-Sep-11 a Combined plots for yield
02-Sep-11 a Combined O+Es
07-Sep-11 a Baled and removed straw
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>2012</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots
01-Sep-11 a Combined Plots -
30-Sep-11 s Spread mustard by hand, as per plan -
30-Sep-11 a Shallow power harrow to incorporate mustard seeds : as per plan
24-Nov-11 a Cut and weighed grass plots for yield (yield cut 2 in -2011).
30-Nov-11 a Cut and removed grass - grass plot only -
01-Dec-11 a Topped grass a second time to tidy up -
29-Mar-12 f Spread Fert TSP with Kuhn, as per plan 97.5 kg/ha
29-Mar-12 f Spread Fert SOP with Kuhn, as per plan 200 kg/ha
29-Mar-12 f Applied basal fertilisers as plans, except plots 5,11,23,26. 97.5 kg/ha 
29-Mar-12 f Sulphate of Potash applied except plots 5,11,23,.26. 200 kg/ha
19-Apr-12 a Spread FYM, straw, compost by hand - kg/ha
20-Apr-12 a Spread FYM, straw, compost by hand to finish - kg/ha
20-Apr-12 a chopped straw with orsi -
18-May-12 a Ploughed soil to the south :
23-May-12 a Powerharrowed maize areas :
24-May-12 f Applied N treatments, as per plan - kg/ha
25-May-12 s Drilled Maize, Hudson Maize trt Mesurol, rolled plots after drilling 10.1 seeds/m?
26-Jun-12 p Spray Samson Extra n maize areas only 0.75 l/200 l/ha
26-Jun-12 p Spray Callisto on maize areas only 1.0 l/200 l/ha
12-Jul-12 f Applied Nitro-chalk as per plan See above
17-Jul-12 a Cut and weighed grass plots for yield - cut 1 -
17-Jul-12 a Cut paths -
24-Jul-12 a Grass areas topped -
25-Jul-12 a Turned hay :
28-Jul-12 a Rowed up hay :
28-Jul-12 a Baled and Removed :
15-Aug-12 a Cut paths :
02-Oct-12 a Cut Maize for yields :
03-Oct-12 a Cut Maize for yields -
10-Oct-12 a Mowed, Baled and removed maize :
05-Nov-12 a Cut and weighed grass plots for yield cut 2 -
05-Nov-12 a Applied FYM as per plan see plan
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>2013</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots
20-Oct-12 p Sprayed glyphosate, grass plots not sprayed. 4 Vha
24-Oct-12 a Applied compost. plots 7, 12, 21 and 27 40 vha
24-Oct-12 a Applied straw, Plots 3, 15, 17, 31. 7.5 vha
06-Nov-12 a Applied FYM -finished — _
06-Nov-12 a Topped grass plots, unable to bale and remove, too little grass.
06-Nov-12 a Ploughed - East = —
08-Nov-12 a Ploughed: finished _- _-
10-Dec-12 a Power harrowed- prep site _ _-
12-Dec-12 s Drilled Kapitan, drilled as a solid block 450 seeds/m?
13-Dec-12 s Drilled Kapitan - finished 450 seedsim?
20-Apr-13 f  Applied Sulphate of Potash, applied to whole trial except plots 5, 11, 23 and 26. 200 kg/ha
20-Apr-13 f Applied TSP- applied to all plots except 5, 11, 23 and 26 97.5 kg/ha
01-May-13 p Sprayed Ally Max Sprayed alll rye plots but not the grass. 42 g/200 l/ha
01-May-13 p Sprayed Folicur Sprayed alll rye plots but not the grass. 0.5 l/200 l/ha
01-May-13 p Sprayed Amistar Sprayed alll rye plots but not the grass. 0.5 l/200 l/ha
01-May-13 p Sprayed Moddus Sprayed alll rye plots but not the grass. 0.25 l/200 l/ha
01-May-13 p Sprayed New 5C Cycocel Sprayed alll rye plots but not the grass. 1.5 l/200 l/ha 
07-May-13 f Applied Nitro-chalk, applied to treated plots.
03-Jun-13 p Sprayed Amistar Rye only 0.5 Vha
03-Jun-13 p Sprayed Folicur Rye only 0.5 Vha
01-Jul-13 a  Cut grass plots, cut for yield 
03-Jul-13 a Mowed grass, mowed rest of grass plots
08-Jul-13 a Rowed up grass, ley plots
08-Jul-13 a Baled and removed, ley plots 
31-Aug-13 a Cut plots for yield 
04-Sep-13 a Combined 
06-Sep-13 a Baled 
13-Nov-13 a Cut and weighed grass plots for yield, plots 1,13,24 and 29
13-Nov-13. a Topped grass plots, grass too short to bale and remove
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>2014</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots
10-Sep-13 s Broadcast mustard cv. Asta undressed - Plots 4, 10, 19 and 32 10 kg/ha
10-Sep-13 a Power harrowed to cover mustard. Plots 4,10,19 and 32
10-Sep-13 a Rolled plots 4, 10, 19 and 32 
27-Sep-13 p Sprayed Samurai - Grass and Mustard plots NOT sprayed 4.0 Vha
27-Sep-13 p Sprayed Firebrand - Grass and Mustard plots NOT sprayed 1.0 Vha
05-Mar-14 p Sprayed Gallup 360. Prep for spring crop Grass plots not sprayed. 1.0 Vha
18-Mar-14 f Applied FYM Plots 8, 14, 18, 28. 10 tha
18-Mar-14 f Applied FYM Plots 5, 11, 23, 26. 25 vha
18-Mar-14 a Applied straw Plots 3, 15, 17 and 31 7.5 Vha
18-Mar-14 a Applied compost Plots 7, 12, 21 and 27. 40 vha
20-Mar-14 a Ploughed - :
01-Apr-14 s Drilled Barley var. Tipple 350 seeds/m?
15-Apr-14 f Applied TSP - Applied to all plots apart from 5,11,23 and 26 97.5 kg/ha
15-Apr-14 t Applied SOP - Applied to all plots apart from 5,11,23 and 26 200 kg/ha
30-Apr-14 p Sprayed Hallmark with Zeon Technology in 40 l/200 ml/ha
13-May-14 f Applied Nitro Chalk applied by hand at rates given above
21-May-14 p Sprayed Refine Max in 150 I'/ha water volume 75 g/ha
21-May-14 p Sprayed Kingdom in 150 Vha water volume 1,25 Vha
21-May-14 p Sprayed Bravo 500 in 150 Vha water volume 1.0 Vha
21-May-14 p Sprayed Hatchet Xtra in 150 I/ha water volume 0.75 Vha
13-Jun-14 p Sprayed Fezan - barley only 0.6 vha
14-Jun-14 p Sprayed Hallmark - barley only 40 misha
26-Jun-14 a Cut grass plots for yield : 
30-Jun-14 a Mowed grass plots :
01-Jul-14 a Turned hay 
02-Jul-14 a Turned hay :
03-Jul-14 a Baled and Removed hay  
24-Aug-14 a Combined plots for yield :
06-Sep-14 a Baled and Removed : 
11-Sep-14 p Sprayed Firebrand in 200 ha water volume. Problem with "Auto control” on sprayer, switched to manual. 1.0 Vha
11-Sep-14 p Sprayed Samurai in 200 I/ha water volume. Problem with "Auto control” on sprayer, switched to manual. 4.0 Vha
03-Dec-14 a Cut grass plots for yield  
10-Dec-14 a Topped grass plots  
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>2015</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots
07/10/2014 a Applied Compost to allocated plots 7, 12, 21, 27 40 vVha
08/10/2014 a Applied Straw to plots 3, 15, 17, 31 75 vha
08/10/2014 a Topped straw
09/10/2014 a Applied FYM - plots S, 11, 23, 26 25 wha
20/10/2014 a Ploughed (thrown east)
29/10/2014 a Power harrowed
05/11/2014 s Orilied Wizzard Winter beans 35 seedim?
18/02/2015 p Sprayed Crawler in 200 ha water volume 35 Wha
26/05/2015 a Cut paths
27/08/2015 p Sprayed San 703 in 131 ha water volume 15 Wha
27/05/2015 p Sprayed Hallmark with Zeon Technology in 75 l/131 ml/ha
08/07/2015 a Cut grass plots for yield --
09/07/2015 a Mowed grass plots --
09/07/2015 a Turned grass 7
10/07/2015 a Turned grass es
16/07/2015 a Turned hay -
17/07/2015 a Rowed up hay -
17/07/2015 a Baled hay 7
23/07/2015 a Cut paths 7 +
03/09/2015 a Cut paths --
11/09/2015 a Combined plots for yield
11/09/2015 a Combined O+Es
25/09/2015 Pp Sprayed Firebrand in 150 /ha water volume - Bean stubble 1 wha
25/09/2015 p Sprayed Samurai in 150 Vha water volume - Bean stubble 4 Uha
09/12/2015 a Cut grass plots for yield - second and final cut -
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>2016</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots
29/10/2015 f Applied FYM; Plots 5,11,23,26 25.00 t/ha
29/10/2015 f Applied FYM; Plots 8,14,18,28 10.00 tha
30/10/2015 f Applied compost; Plots 7 and 21 40.00 t/ha
02/11/2015 f Applied compost; Plots 12 and 27 40.00 t/ha
02/11/2015 f Applied straw; Plots 3,15,17,31 7.50 tha
09/11/2015 f Topped straw plots; Plots 3,15,17,31.  
10/11/2015 a Ploughed; Thrown west ss
12/11/2015 a Power harrowed = 4
16/11/2015 s Drilled Gallant, tr Redigo Pro; 4m tine drill 400.00 seeds/m?
29/02/2016 f Applied SOP; all plots except plots 5,11,23 and (Dg25) 26 200.00 kg/ha
04/03/2016 f Applied TSP Fertilizer; all plots including grass except plots 5,11,23 and 26 (Dg25) 97.50 kg/ha
31/03/2016 p Sprayed Atlantis (in 150 It/ha water volume); wheat only 0.40 kg/ha
31/03/2016 p Sprayed Compitox Plus (in 150 It/ha water volume); wheat only 1.00 Itha
31/03/2016 p Sprayed Biopower (in 150 It/ha water volume); wheat only 1.00 Itha
11/04/2016 f Applied Nitro-chalk (27% N); 1st nitrogen treatment; by hand to wheat only 185.00 kg/ha
27/04/2016 f Applied Nitro-chalk (27% N); second nitrogen treatment; by hand to wheat only 185.00 kg/ha
27/04/2016 f Applied Nitro-chalk (27% N); second nitrogen treatment; by hand to wheat only 370.00 kg/ha
27/04/2016 f Applied Nitro-chalk (27% N); second nitrogen treatment; by hand to wheat only 556.00 kg/ha
27/04/2016 f Applied Nitro-chalk (27% N); second nitrogen treatment; by hand to wheat only 741.00 kg/ha
30/04/2016 p Sprayed Sprinter (in 150 It/ha water volume); wheat only 2.00 It/ha
30/04/2016 p Sprayed Simba (in 150 It/ha water volume); wheat only 20.00 g/ha
30/04/2016 p Sprayed Cortez (in 150 It/ha water volume); wheat only 0.75 It/ha
30/04/2016 p Sprayed Bravo 500 (in 150 It/ha water volume); wheat only 1.00 It/ha
23/05/2016 p Sprayed Sprinter (in 150 It/ha water volume); wheat only 2.00 It/ha
23/05/2016 p Sprayed Vortex (in 150 It/ha water volume); wheat only 1.50 Itvha
23/05/2016 p Sprayed Hunter (in 150 It/na water volume); wheat only 1.50 Itha
26/05/2016 a Cut paths
09/06/2016 p Sprayed Cello (in 150 It/ha water volume); wheat only 0.60 = It/ha
09/06/2016 p Sprayed Cyflamid (in 150 It/ha water volume); wheat only 0.15 It/ha
09/06/2016 p Sprayed Hallmark (in 150 It/ha water volume); wheat only 50.00 mi/ha
11/07/2016 a Cut paths  
12/07/2016 a Cut paths -“
13/07/2016 a Cut grass plots for yield 3
14/07/2016 a Mowed all grass plots a
14/07/2016 a Turned grass - :
18/07/2016 a Turned hay  
18/07/2016 a Rowed up and baled hay; Grass plots only -
13/08/2016 a Combined plots for yield; All wheat plots  
15/08/2016 a Combined; Commercial combine swathed rest of the plots
19/08/2016 a Removed all bales 3
08/09/2016 a Baled Straw
12/09/2016 a Removed bales
10/11/2016 a Cut grass plots for yield (second Cut) 
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>2017</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
all plots
09/09/2016 s Hand broadcast mustard Zlata - plots 4, 10, 19 and 32 only. Cover Crop plots (CC). 10.00 kg/ha
09/09/2016 a Power harrowed - Cover crop plots lightly.
13/04/2017 p Sprayed Firebrand - Sprayed off stubble only. 1.00 It/ha
13/04/2017 p Sprayed Samurai - Sprayed off stubble only. 4.00 It/ha
20/04/2017 f Applied Chalk - all plots 5.00 t/ha
21/04/2017 f Applied SOP (50% K20, 45% SO3) - all plots apart from 5, 11, 23, 26. 200.00 kg/ha
21/04/2017 f Applied MOP - all plots a part from 5,11,23,26. 97.50 kg/ha
24/04/2017 f Applied compost - plots 7, 12, 21, 27 40.00 t/ha
25/04/2017 f Applied straw - plots 3, 15, 17, 31 7.50 t/ha
25/04/2017 f Applied FYM - plots 5, 11, 23, 26 25.00 t/ha
25/04/2017 f Applied FYM - plots 8, 14, 18, 28 10.00 t/ha
26/04/2017 a Topped straw plots  
27/04/2017 a Ploughed - thrown south east  
03/05/2017 a Power harrowed  
04/05/2017 a Rolled prior to drilling  
04/05/2017 s Drilled maize Severus tr. Mesurial 10.10 s/m42
25/05/2017 f Applied Nitro-chalk (27% N) by hand - N1 to N5 treatments 185.00 kg/ha
19/06/2017 a Cut paths  
22/06/2017 f Applied Nitro-chalk (27% N) by hand. To plots 0025, 0033, 0044, 0054, 0064, 0076, 0085, 0091, 0102, 0111, 0123, 0142, 0154, 0162, 0176, 0181, 0192, 0201, 0211, 0223, 0236, 0252, 0262, 0273, 0283, 0305, 0312, 0323 - Maize plots only 185.00 kg/ha
22/06/2017 f Applied Nitro-chalk (27% N) by hand. To plots 0023, 0034, 0042, 0051, 0061, 0074, 0086, 0094, 0103, 0114, 0125, 0141, 0152, 0165, 0172, 0183, 0191, 0204, 0216, 0221, 0234, 0254, 0264, 0275, 0281, 0306, 0316, 0321 - Maize plots only 370.00 kg/ha
22/06/2017 f Applied Nitro-chalk (27% N) by hand. To plots 0026, 0031, 0041, 0052, 0066, 0075, 0081, 0096, 0101, 0115, 0122, 0145, 0151, 0161, 0174, 0184, 0196, 0203, 0213, 0224, 0233, 0251, 0261, 0276, 0285, 0301, 0314, 0322 - Maize plots only 556.00 kg/ha
22/06/2017 f Applied Nitro-chalk (27% N) by hand. To plots 0024, 0032, 0045, 0053, 0065, 0073, 0084, 0093, 0106, 0116, 0126, 0146, 0155, 0163, 0171, 0185, 0193, 0202, 0215, 0226, 0235, 0256, 0266, 0272, 0282, 0304, 0311, 0325 - Maize plots only 741.00 kg/ha
26/06/2017 p Sprayed Callisto in 200 It/ha water volume - maize plots only 1.50 It/ha
26/06/2017 p Sprayed Samson Extra in 200 It/ha water volume 0.75 It/ha
27/06/2017 a Cut grass plots for yield (1% Cut)  
06/07/2017 a Mowed all remaining grass on plots  
10/07/2017 a Baled and removed all remaining grass  
11/08/2017 a Topped Surrounds and paths  
20/09/2017 a Started Harvesting Maize for Yield  
21/09/2017 a Finished Harvesting Maize for Yield  
29/09/2017 a Topped Trial Site  
17/11/2017 a Cut grass plots for yield (2nd Cut)  
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
</reports>