<reports>
<report>
<year>1964</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[64/c/20.1
SOIL STRUCTURE 2
Effects of peat and subsoiling - Woburn Stackyard Field, plot 6 of
Continuous Barley site red beet 1963, carrots 196k.
Design: 4 randomised blocks of 5 plots each, with plots split in
1964 for test of P, Two blocks were subsoiled,
Area of each plot: Red beet 1963: 0.0016, carrots 196k: 0,0008.
Area harvested: Red beet 1963: 0,0011, cerrots 1964: 0,0006.
Treatments, All combinations of:-
Blocks 1. Subsoiling: None (SO), subsoiled (S1) by hand to depth
of 20 inches in 1963.
Whole plots 2, Peat: None (0) - 2 plots per block, 62,5 cwt peat
dry matter, applied to top 2 inches of soil alone
(Sb), or with peat dug in to a depth of 8 inches, either at
the same rate (Dgl) or at twice the rate (D2).
Sub plots 3. P test (1964 only): None (PO), 0.6 cwt (P1) P20S5
as triple superphosphate,
Basal dressings: Monoammonium phosphate, potassium nitrate and
magnesium sulphate to supply the following:-
Red beet 1963: 200 1b N, 250 1b K and 500 1b Mg, 211 applied
before digging except 82 1b N, applied as ammonium nitrate,
half before and half after digging.
Carrots 1964: 100 1b NX, 75 1b P, 200 1b K and 50 1b Mg. All
Mg and four fifths NPK were dug in. The remaining NPK was
applied to seedbed,
Cultivations, etc,:
Red beet 1963: Ground chalk applied at 30 cwt, basal dressings and
half Dg2 peat applied, all plots rotary cultivated, remainder of
Dg2 peat and all Dg! applied, all plots rotary cultivated second
time: Apr 18, 196k, Plots dug, appropriate blocks subsoiled,
ground chalk applied at 10 cwt: Apr 19, Sb peat applied and
pricked in: Apr 23. Seedbed N applied, seed drilled at 15 1b:
Mey 15. Sprayed with DDT at 0.6 1b in 20 gals: June 7,
Singled: July 2. Sprayed with a mixture of menazon, DDT and
gamma BHC at 1.5 fluid oz in 40 gals: July 31, Lifted:
Aug 8. Variety: Detroit Globe.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1965</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[65/c/19.1
SOIL STRUCTURE 2
Effects of peet (anmel applications) and subsoiling (1953 only)

Woburn Stackyard Field, plot § of the Continuous Barley site,

red beet 1953, cerrots 1964, red beet 1965.

Design: 4 randomised blocks of 5 plots each, Two blocks subsoiled.
Aree of each plot: 0,0016. Area harvested: 0.0010.
Treatments: All combinations of:-

Blocks 1. Subsoiling: None (0) subsoiled (S) by hand to depth
of 20 inches in 1963.

Whole plots 2. Peat: None, 52.5 cwt peat dry metter applied to
top 2 inches of soil in 1965 only (Sb 65), 1363 = 65
cumlative dressings, 62.5 cwt peet dry metter applied
enmally to top 2 inches soil elone (Sb), or with peat
dug in anmelly to & depth of 8 inches either at the
same rete (Dg 1) or at twice the rate (Dg 2).

Basal dressings: Moncammenium phosphate, potassium nitrate, ammonium

nitrate and megnesium sulphate to supply 200 1b K, 75 1b F,

250 1b XK, 50 1b Mg: ¥ 4 of the fertilisers being dug in, 1/4 worked

into the seedbed.

Cultivaticns, etc.:

Fertilisers for digging in applied: Mar 10, Peat for digging in

applied and plots dug: Mer 31 - Apr 1. Seedbed peat applied:
Apr 21. Seedbed fertilisers applied and seedbed rrepered:
My 5. Seed, rubbed and graded, drilled et 30 1b: May 6.
Singled first to 2'' spacing: Mey 27 end 31, then to 4'' spacing:
Jue 28. Srreyed with & mixture of menazon, DIT and gamm
BHC at 1.5 fluid oz in 0 gals: May 21 and June 21. Lifted:
Aug 12, Variety: Detroit Globe.

NOTE: Crop samples taken for estimation of dry ratter and FX analysis.

Soil samples taken for determinations of pE end readily soluble FX.

Standard errors per plot.

Roots: 0.723 or k.5% (12 4.f.)

Tops: 0.615 or 5.6% (12 d.f.)

Roots and Tops: 1.215 or 4.5% (12 d.f.)
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1966</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[66/c/11.1
SOIL STRUCTURE 2
Effects of peat (annual applications) and subsoiling (1963 only)
Woburn Stackyard Field, plot 6 of the Continuous Earley site,
early potatoes followed by red beet 1966, the fourth year,
Design: 4 randomised blocks of 5 plots split into two for P,
Two blocks subsoiled,
Area of each plot: 0,0016, Area harvested: Potatoes - 0.0005,
red beet - 0,0011,
Treatments: All combinaticns ofi-
Blocks, 1. Subsoiling: None (0), subsoiled (S) by hand
to a depth of 20 inches in 1963,
Whole plots. 2, Peat: lione (0), 62.5 cwt peat dry retter
applied to top 2 inches of soil in 1965 only
(sr65), 1963-66 cumilative dressings, 52,5 owt
peat dry matter applied annually to top
2 inches of soil alone (Sb), or with peat dug in
annually to a depth of 8 inches either at ire
sare rate (Dgl), or at twice the rate (D:z2),
Helf plots. 3, Pnosphate*: None (0), 75 1b F205 (P) arplied
as triple superphosphate taree quarters dug in,
and a quarter in the seedted,
*not tested on red beet,
Basal applicetions: Monocammonium phosphate, potassium nitrete,
ammonium nitrate and magnesium sulphate to supply 120 1b IN,
75 1b P, 150 1b K, 50 1b Mg, to the potatoes, and 20C 1b ¥,
75 1b P, 250 1b K, and 50 1b Mg to red beet, Three quarters
being dug in, and a quarter in the seedbed in eech case,
Cultivations, etc.:
Early potatoess
Fertilisers and peat for digging in epplied: Mar 25, 1966, All
plots dug: Mar 28, Seedbed fertilisers end peat applied, setts
planted: Apr 4, Earthed upt May 20. Lifted: July 7.
Variety: Arran Pilot,
Red beet:
Chalk epplied at 1 ton: July 15, 1966, Fertilisers applied to
seedbed, seedbed prepared, and seed drilled at 30 1b: July 27.
Singled to b inch spacing: Aug 24, Lifted: Oct 28, Variety:
Crimson Globe,
66/c/11.2
NOTE:
1. Crop samples were taken for estimetion of dry matter and
PK snalysis,
2, Soil samples taken O-12 inches Dec 15, 1965, for
determination of pH and readily soluble P and K,
3. For previous years' results see 'Results' 64/C/20, 55/C/19.
Standard errors per plot,
Early potatoes, Total tubers, whole plot: 0.810 or 8,3% (8 4.f.)
sub plots 0,625 or 6.4% (10 4.f.)
Red beet, Whole plots, Rootss 0,239 or 4.7% (8 4.f.)
Tops: 0.485 or 4,8% (8 d.f.)
Roots and tops: 0.698 or b.6 (8 a.f.)
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1967</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[67/c/8.1
SOIL STRUCTURE 2
(WBAH)

Effects of peat (annual applications) and subsoiling (1963 only)
Woburn Stackyard Field, plot 6 of the Continuous Barley Site,
carrots 1967, the fifth year,

Design: 4 randomised blocks of 5 plots with treatments to blocks.

Area of each plot: 0,0016, Area harvested: 0.0010.

Treatments: All combinations ofi-

Blocks? 1. Date of preparation of seedbed: Blocks 1 and 2
seedbed worked down Jan 30, 1967 (J). Blocks 3
end 4 seedbed worked down Mar 20, 1967 (M).

whole plots: 2, Peat: None (0), 62.5 cwt peat dry matter a
to top 2 inches of soil in 1965 only (Sb 65).
Cumulative dressings 1963 - 67, 62.5 cwt peat
dry matter applied annually to top 2 inches of
soil alone (Sb), in addition with peat dug in
annually to a depth of 8 inches either at the
seme rate (Dgl), or at twice the rate (Dg2).

Basal applications: Moncammonium dihydrogen phosphate, potassium
nitrate and magnesium sulphate to supply 100 1b N, 75 1b P,

200 1b X and 50 1b Mg, All fertilisers applied to the seedbed
before drilling, Weedkiller: Linuron at 0,75 1b in 100 gals,
Insecticide: Dimethoate at 0,2 1b in LO gals, on three
occasions,

Cultivations, etc,: Ground chalk applied at 20 cwt, peat applied
and all plots dug: Dec 15, 1966, Seedbed fertiliser applied, seed
drilled at 6 1b: Mar 20, 1967, Weedkiller applied: Mar 21. Insecticide
applied: June 9, June 23, July 10, Lifted: July 24, Variety:
Chantenay Red cored, Monarch strain,

NOTES: (1) Crop samples were taken for estimation of dry matter and

PK analysis,
(2) For previous years' results see 'Results’' 64/C/20,
65/C/19 and 66/C/11.
Standard error per whole plot,
Marketable roots: 0.719 or 5.9% (8 a.f.)
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1968</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[68/c/31.1
SOIL STRUCTURE 2
(WEAH)
Effects of peat (annual applications) and subsoiling (1963 only)
Woburn Stackyard Pield, plot 6 of the Continuous Barley Site,
red beet 1968, the sixth year.
Design: 4 rendomised blocks of 5 plots with treatments to blocks

and strips of sub plots,

Ares of each plot: 0,0016, Area harvested: Sub plots without tractor

wheelmarks - 0,0008, with - 0,0005,

Treatments: All combinations ofi-

Blocks; 1. Subsoiling: None (0), subsoiled (8) by hand to e
depth of 20 inches in 1963 (this factor is now
ignored in the analysis).

Whole plots: 2, Peat (cwt dry matter): None (0), 62.5 applied to top
2 in, of soil in 1965 only (Sb65), 62.5 (DG1), 125 (DG2),
187.5 (DG3) dug in to a depth of 8 in. in 1968.
(DG1 after Sb 1967, DG2 after .Dgl 1967, DG3
after Dg2 1967).

Strips of 5 Wheelmerks: 5 rows without wheelmerks (0),

sub plots: 3 rovs with wheelmarks (W).

Basal applications: Monoammonium dihydrogen phosphate, potassium
nitrate, ammonium nitrate, and magnesium sulphate to supply

200 1b N, 75 1b P, 250 1b K, 50 1b Mg. All fertilisers ¢

applied to the seedbed before drilling. Insecticide: Dimethoate

at 0.2 pints in 50 gals, :

Cultivetions, etc,: Peat applied, all plots dug: 29 Jan, 1968, Trector
wheelmarks made, seedbed fertiliser applied, raked, seed drilled at

30 1b: 15 May. Singled: 20 June. Insecticide applied: 3 July.

Lifted: 9 Sept, Variety: Avon Early,

NOTES: (1) For previous years' results see 'Results’ 64/C/20, 65/C/19,
66/c/11, and 67/C/8,
. (2) soil samples for PK enalysis were taken in May.
Standard errors per plot,
Marketeble roots: Whole plot: 1,506 or 8,4% (12 4.f.)
Sub plot: 1.908 or 10.6% (15 d.f.)
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1969</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[138
SOIL STRUCTURE 2
(69/w/cs/11)

Effect of peat (anmual applications 1963-1968) Woburn, Stackyard
II, plot 6 of the Continuous Barley Site, spring beans 1969 the
seventh year,

Design: UL randomised blocks of 5 plots with weedkiller treatments
to blocks,

Area of each plot: 0.0016. Area harvested: 0,0015,

Treatments: All combinations of:-

Blocks: 1, Weedkiller: No sprey (SO), simazine at
0,42 1b in 50 gels (S1), 0.8% 1b in 100 gnls (S2),
1.68 Iv in 200 gals (sk),

Whole 2, Residues of Peat: None (0), peat at 62,5 cwt dry

plots: ratter applied in 1955 only (Sb 65). Annual
dressings of peat repested 1963-1968 et 62.5 (DG 1),
125 (DG 2), 187.5 cwt dry matter (DG 3) dug in to
depth of 8 inches,

NOTE: The 1968 sub plot test of wheel-marks wes ignored in 1969

yields being taken from whole plots.

Basal aprlications: 20 cwt ground chalk, Triple superphosphate,
potassium dicerbonate, and magnesium sulphate to supply 75 1b P,
250 1b K, 50 1b Mg applied to the seedbed before drilling,

Cultivations, etc,: Ground chalk, P,K,Mg applied: 3 Feb, 1969,
Plots duz: 6 Feb, Seed drilled at 200 lb: 11 Feb, Weedkiller
treatments applied: 16 Feb, Harvested by hand: 29 Aug.
Variety: Tarvin,

NOTES: (1) For previous years' results see 'Resulis' 54/C/20,

é5/c/19, 66/c/11, 67/c/8 end 68/c/31.

(2) Crop samples were teken on 3 occasions in June for
growth studies,

(3) Soil samples for PX enalysis were taken in September,
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1970</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[SOIL STRUCTURE 2
(To/m/cs/1r)

Effect of peat (annual applications 1963 - 1968) Woburn, Stackyard II,
plot 6 of the Continuous Barley site, the eighth year, Spring beans.

Design: 4 randomised blocks of 5 plots with weedkdiller treatments to
blocks,

Area of each plot: 0,0016, Ares harvested: 0,0016,

Treatments: All combinations ofie
Blocks: 1, Weedkiller: No spray (SO), simezine at 0,84 1b in

100 gals 1969 and 0,75 1b in 60 gals 1970 (SA),
1.68 1b in 200 gals 1969 and none in 1970 (SB),
0.42 1b in 50 gals 1969 and 1.50 1b in 120 gals
1970 (sc).
Whole 2, Residues of Peat: None (0), peat at 62.5 cwt dry
plotss metter applied in 1965 only (Sb65), Annual
dressings of peat repeated 1963 - 1968 at 62,5 (DG1),
125 (DG2), 187.5 cwt dry matter (DG3) dug in to
a depth of 8 inches,

Basal applications: 20 cwt ground chalk, Triple superphosphate,
potassium bicarbonate, and magnesium sulphate to supply 75 1b P,
250 1b K, 50 1b Mg applied to the seedbed before drilling,
Insecticide: Dimethoate at 4,8 f1 oz in 40 gals on one occasion,
menazon 0,25 1b in UO gals on two occasions.

Cultivations, etc,: Ground chalk, P, K, Mg applied, plots dug:

16 Dec, 1969, Seed drilled at 200 1b, weedkiller treatments
applied: 28 Apr, 1970, Dimethoate applied: 17 June,
Menazon applied: 6 July, 29 July, Rarvested by hand: 10 Sept,
Variety: Tarvin,
NOTES: (1) For previous years' results see 'Results' 64/C/20, 65/C/19,
66/c/11, 67/c/8, 68/C/31 and 69/W/CS/11.
(2) Soil samples for PK analysis were taken after harvest.
141
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1971</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[nf/es/n
SOIL STRUCTURE
Object: To study the residual effects of peat, applied 1963 - 1968,
and simazine, applied 1969 - 1970, on the yield of wheat - Woburn
Stackyard II,
The ninth year, winter wheat,
For previous years see 64/C/20(t), 65/C/19(t), 66/c/11(t), 67/C/8(t)
68/c/31(t) and 69-T0/W/CS/11(t). ’
Design: 4 randomised blocks of 5 plots,
Wnole plot dimensions: 2,13 x 3.05. Area harvested: 0,00054,
Basal applications: 597 kg 'Nitro-Chalk',
Cultivations, etc,: Hand cultivated, seed drilled: 7 Oct, 1970.
N applied: 19 Apr, 1971. Eand harvested: 17 Aug, Variety:
Cappelle,
137
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1972</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[rfu/cs/1
SOIL STRUCTURE
Object: To study direct end residual effects of peat, at a renge of
: nitrogen levels, on the yield of barley - Wobur Stackyard II,

Sponsor: AE, Jomston, .

The tenth year, barley,

For previous years ree Sycpmis 6s5/c/19(t), 66/c/11(t), 67/c/8(t),.
68fc/3n(r), 69fu/cs/1a(t), 70/u/CS/1L(%) and T2/fW/CS/11.

Design: L randomised blocke of 5 plots, each block containing all
levels of peat,

Wiaole plot dimensions: 2,13 x 3.05.

Treatments: All combinations oft-

1, Peat (tommes dry matter/nectare)
Avplied 1963-68 1972 Total
Kone Rene Tone (0)
7.8 None 7.8 (1)
47.0 7.8 54.8 (2)
9k,0 16,0 110.0 (3) :
1.0 240 165.0 (4)
2, Nitrogen: None, 50, 100, 150 kg N as 'Ritro-Chalk’', :

Basal applications: 2,5 tonnes ground chalk, 84% kg P as triple
superphosphate, 280 kg K as potassium bicarbonate, 56 kg Mg as
magnesium sulphate. Weedkiller: Dichlorprop and MCPA ("Mepnetol |
Plus' at 5,6 1 in 340 1), :

Seed: Julia, dressed with ethirimol, sown at 17C kg.

Cultivetions, etc.: Ground chalk, P, K, Mg and peat applied, plots *
dug by hand: 7 Dec, 1971. Seed drilled, W applied: 14 Mer, 1972.
Weedkiller applied: 17 lay.

IOI: Birds caused severe darage to the crop and yields were not taken,

142
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1973</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[BN/Ccs/1
SOIL STRUCTURE
Object: To study the residual effects of peat, at a range of nitrogen
levels, on the yield of potatoes - Woburn Stackyard II.
Sponsor: A.E, Johnston,
The eleventh year, potatoes.
For ous years see 64/C/20(t), 65/C/19(t), 66/c/11(t) Sa
&Jc/a(e), Seo lt: TOM/CS/11(t), TM/CS/1L and T2fW/CS/Na(%).
Design: Single replicate of 5 x 4, Levels of peat in I randomised blocks
of 5 plots.
Whole plot dimensions: 2,13 x 3.05, Area harvested: 0.00065.
Treatments: All combinations of:i-
1. Peat (tonnes dry matter - total applied 1963-72): PEAT
None 0
8 8
55 55
110 110
165 165
2. Nitrogen fertiliser (kg N) N
None 0
100 100
200 200
300 300
Basal applications: Manures: Ground chalk at 2.5 tonnes, P at 85 kg, as
triple superphosphate, K at 300 kg, as potassium bicarbonate, Mg at
55 kg as magnesium sulphate, Weedkiller: Linuron at 0,85 kg with
peraquat at 0,42 kg fon in 340 1, Insecticide: Menazon at 0.28 kg in
340 1. Insecticide with fungicide: Menazon at 0,28 kg plus mancozeb
at 1,3 kg in 340 1.
Seed: Pentland Crown,
153
T3/W/cs/1
Cultivetions, 2ic,3- Ground chalk applied, plots dug by hand: 28 Nov, 1972.
P, K nd Mg applied, plots rotary cultivated ané potetces planted:
6 for, 1973. Weedkiller applied: © May, Insecticide applied: 15 Jine,
Insecticide with fungicide upplied: 18 June, Lifted: 25 Sept.
NOTE: Sof) samples vere talen al “arvent for anslysis of P and K,
TABLES OF MEAS
TOTAL TUBZRS: TONNES/HECTARE
PEAT
c C 55 10 165 Mean
N
0 34.8 36.2 36.5 35.2 35.1 35.7
100 48,2 54.2 53.3 57.9 55.5 53.6
200 63.3 36.5 [SX 72.8 67.3 6.1
3% 59.1 65.3 83.0 81.1 83.6 Thal
lees 51.3 53.0 58.3 61.2 60.1 56.9
154
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1974</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[/u/cs/11
SOIL STRUCTURE

Object: To study the residual effects of peat, at a range of nitrogen
levels, on the yield of wheat - Woburn Stackyard II.

Sponsor: A.E. Johnston,

The twelfth year, winter wheat.

For previous years see S1/c/s08)s 65/c/19(t), 66/c/11(t), 67/C/8(t),
68/c/31(t), 69/W/cs/11(t), To/w/CsS/1L(t), TAfW/cs/11, T2/W/CS/11(t) and
T3/W/Cs/11.

Design: Single replicate of § x 4. Levels of peat in 4 randomised blocks
of 5 plots.

Whole plot dimensions: 2.13 x 3.05. Area harvested: 0.00026.

Treatments: All combinations ofi-

1. Peat (tonnes dry matter - total applied 1963-72): PEAT
None 0

8 8

95 55

110 110

165 165

2. Nitrogen fertiliser (kg N), cumulative to previous treatments:

N

None 0

50 50

100 100

150 150

Basal applications: Manures: P at 85 kg, as triple superphosphate,

K at 300 kg, as potassium bicarbonate, Mg at 55 kg as magnesium
sulphate. Weedkiller: Ioxynil at 0.42 kg and mecoprop at 1.26
ke in 3% 1.

Seed: Cappelle, sown at 150 kg.

Cultivations, etc,:= P, K and Mg applied, plots dug ty hand: 28 Sept, 1973.
Seed sown: 8 Oct, Weedkdller applied: 8 Apr, 1974. NK appiied:

24 fpr. Hervested by hand: 19 July.
153
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1975</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[75% [csi
SOIL. STRUCTURE

Object: Wo study the residral effects of peat, at a range of pitrogen
levels, on the yield of potatoes - Webum Steckyard I),

Sponsor: AE. Joehnastor.,

The 12th yesr, potatoes.

For previcus years sec Sli, 65/c/10(t), 66/c/11(%), 67/c/bit),
SRjefote); 69 /cs/11(t), To/M/cs/1a(t), T/W/CS/11, T2f/cs/11(t) exd
T3-Tu/MjCs/ 1.

lesigrn: Single replicste of 5 x li, Tevele of pest In I 1mndoniced tlocks
of 5 plots.

Whole plot dimensions: 2,12 x 3.05.

Treatrerts: All combinations ofi-

1. Pest (tonnes dry meiter - total applied 1963-72): PEAY
None Cc
8 8
53 25
110 1c
165 165
2. Fitrcgen fertiliser (kg I), cimwletive ic previous treatment. :
A
Ncne 0
100 20C
200 2cC
3C0 300

Pasel applications: Merures: CGrcund ctalk ot 2.5 tomes, P ot 85 kg,
as triple superphosphate, K et 300 kz, ss potussium bicerbonate, Mg
at 55 kg, es magnesium sulphate. Insecticide: Menazon at C.28 kg
in 280 1. Fungicides Mexcozeb at 1.3 kg ir 280 3.

Seed: Maris Fiper,

148
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1976</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[%M/CS/11
SOIL STRUCTURE

Object: To study the residual effects of peat, at a range of nitrogen
levels, on the yield of ryegrass - Woburn Stackyard II. .

Sponsar: A.E. Johnston.

The 13th year, ryegrass.

For previous years see 64/C/20(t), 65/C/19(1), 65/¢/11(t), 67/c/8(t),
8/L/31(t), 69/N/Cs/11(t), 70/%/CS/11(t), 71/%/CS/11, 72/w/CS/11(t)
and B-75/¥/Cs/11.

Design: Single replicate of 5 x 4. Levels of peat in 4 randomised blocks
of 5 plots.

Whole plot dimensions: 2.13 x 3.05.

Treatments: All combimations of:-

1. PEAT Peat (tonnes dry matter - total applied 1963-72):

0 0

8 8

85 55
110 110
165 165

2. NPERCUT Nitrogen fertiliser as ammonium nitrate (kg N per cut),
cumulative to previous treatments:

0 0
30 30
60 60
90 90

Basal applications: Manures: Ground chalk at 2.5 tonnes. P at 85 kg,
as triple superphosphate, K at 300 kg, as potassium bicarbonate, Mg
at 55 kg, as magnesium sulphate. Weedkillers: Benazolin with
2,4-DB and MCPA ( “Ley Cornox” at 8.4 1 in 280 1).

Seed: RvVP ryegrass, sown at S50 kg.

Cultivations, etc.:- Ground chalk, P, K and Mg applied, plots dug by
hand: 11 Dec, 1975. N applied, seed sown: 22 Mar, 1976. Weedkiller
applied: 25 May. Cut, N applied: 24 June. Cut: 5S Nov.

NOTES: (1) Soil samples were taken after the second cut for P and K

analysis.
(2) Crop samples were taken for N, P, K and Mg analysis.
126
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1977</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[T7/N/CS/ 1
‘ SOIL STRUCTURE ’

Object: To study the residual effects of peat, at a range of nitrogen levels,
on the yield of ryegrass - Woburn Stackyard II.

Sponsor: A.E. Johnston.

The 14th year, ryegrass.

For previous years see 64/C/20(t), 65/C/19(t), 66/C/11(t), 67/C/8(t),
68/C/31(t), 69/W/CS/11(t), TO/W/CS/11(t), T1/W/CS/11, T2/W/CS/11(t)
and 73-76/W/CS/11.

Design: Single replicate of 5 x 4. Levels of peat in 4 randomised blocks of
5 plots.

Whole plot dimensions: 2.13 x 3.05. ’ d

Treatments: All cambinations of:-

1. PEAT Peat (tonnes dry matter - total applied 1963-72):

0
8 .
55
110
165
2. NPERCUT Nitrogen fertiliser as ammonium nitrate (kg N per cut),
cumulative to previous treatments:
0 .
30
60
90

Basal applications: Manures: Ground chalk at 2.5 tonnes. P at 85 kg, as triple
superphosphate, K at 300 kg, as potassium bicarbonate, Mg at 55 kg, as
magnesium sulphate in 1976. None in 1977.

Seed: RvP ryegrass, sown at 50 kg in 1976.

Cultivations, etc.:- N applied: 25 Mar, 1977, 1 June, 26 July. Cut three
times: 1 June, 20 July, 29 Sept.

NOTE: Crop samples were taken for N, P, K and Mg analysis.

1ST CUT MEAN DME 27.3

2ND CUT MEAN DM% 31.3 %"

3RD CUT MEAN DM% 23.6 '

TOTAL OF 3 CUTS MEAN DM§ 27.4

12
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1978</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[T8/W/CS/ 11
SOIL STRUCTURE

Object: To study the residual effects of peat, at a range of nitrogen levels,
on the yield of ryegrass - Woburn Stackyard II.

Sponsor: A.E. Johnston.

The 15th year, barley.

For previous years see 64/C/20(t), 65/C/19(t), 66/C/11(t), 67/C/8(t),
68/C/31(t), 69/W/CS/11(t), T0/W/CS/11(t), T1/W/TS/11, T2/W/CS/11(L)
and 73-77/W/CS/11.

Design: Single replicate of 5 x 4.

Whole plot dimensions: 2.13 x 3.05.

© Treatments: All combinations of :~
1. PEAT Peat (tonnes dry matter - total applied 1963-72):
0
8
55
110
165

2. N Nitrogen fertiliser as ammonium nitrate (kg N)

cumulative to previous treatments:
0
50
100
150

Basal applications: Manures: Ground chalk at 2.5 tonnes. P at 85 kg, as triple
superphosphate, K at 300 kg, as potassium bicarbonate, Mg at 55 kg, as
magnesium sulphate. Weedkillers: Ioxynil at 0.52 kg with mecoprop at 1.6 kg in
280 1 applied with the fungicide. Fungicide: Tridemorph at 0.53 kg.

Seed: Porthos, dressed with ethirimol, sown at 160 kg.

Cultivations, ete.:- Hand dug: 14 Dec, 1977. Ground chalk, P, K, Mg applied,
raked in, seed sown: 7 Mar. Weedkiller with fungicide applied: 19 May.
Hand harvested: 16 Aug.

124
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1979</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[79/W/C3/11
SOIL STRUCTURE

Ooject: To stuly the residual effects of peat, at a range of nitrogen levels,
on the yield of wheat - Woburn Stackyard II.

Sponsor: A.E. Johnston.

The 16th year, wheat.

For previous years see 64/C/20(t), 65/C/19(t), 66/C/11(t), 67/C/8(%),
68/C/31(t), 69/W/C/11(t), T0/W/CS/11(t), TI/W/CS/11, T2/W/C/11(L)
and 73-78/WCS/11.

Design: Single replicate of 5 x 4.

Whole plot dimensions: 2.13 x 3.05.

"Treatments: All combinations of:-

1. PEAT Peat (tonnes dry matter - total applied 1963-72):

0
8
55
110
165
2. N Nitrogen fertiliser as ammonium nitrate (kg N)
cumul ative to previous treatments:
0
50
100
150

Basal applications: Manwres: P at 85 kg, as triple superphosphate,

K at 300 kg, as potassium bicarbonate, Mg at 55 kg, as magnesium
sulphate. Weedkillers: Ioxynil 0,32 kg with mecoprop at 0.94 kg in
280 1 on the first occasion, ioxynil at 0.42 kg with mecoprop at 1.3 kg
in 280 1 on the second occasion, applied with tridemorph on both
occasions. Fungicides: Tridemorph at 0.53 kg applied with weedkillers.

© Carbendazim at 0.25 kg with zineb at 1.6 kg in 280 1.

Seed: Maris Hobbit, sown at 210 kg.

Qultivations, etc.:- Hand dug: 12 Sept, 1978. P, K, Mg applied and raked in,
Seed sown: 3 Oct. Weedkillers and tridemorph applied: 17 Nov. N applied:
23 Apr, 1979. Weedkillers and tridemorph applied: 9 May. Carbendazim and
zineb applied: 20 June. Hand harvested: 16 Aug.

NOTE: Soil and crop samples were taken for N, P, K and Mg analysis.

94
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1980</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[80/W/CS/11
SOIL STRUCTURE

Object: To study the residual effects of peat, at a range of nitrogen
levels, on the yield of a sequence of crops - Woburn Stackyard II.

Sponsor: A.E. Johnston.

The 18th year, w. barley.

For previous years see. 64/C/20(t), 65/C/19(t), 66/C/11(t), 67/C/8(t),
68/C/31(t), 69/W/CS/11(t), 70/W/CS/11(t), 71/W/CS/11. 72/W/CS/11(t)
and 73-79/W/CS/11. *

Design: Single replicate of 5 x 4.

Whole plot dimensions: 2.13 x 3.05.

Treatments: All combinations of:-

1. PEAT Peat (tonnes dry matter - total applied 1963-72):

0
8
55
110
165

2. N Ni trogen fertiliser (kg N)

cumulative to previous treatments:
0
50
100
150

Basal applications: Manures: P at 85 kg, as triple superphosphate, K at
300 kg, as potassium bicarbonate, Mg at 55 kg, as magnesium sulphate.
Weedkillers: loxynil at 0.32 kg with mecoprop at 0.94 kg in 280 1
applied twice, with tridemorph on the first occasfon, with benomyl on
the second. Fungicides: Tridemorph at 0.53 kg. Benomyl at 0.28 kg.
Carbendazim at 0.25 kg plus tridemorph at 0.53 kg in 280 1.

Seed: Sonja, sown at 210 kg.

Cultivations, etc.:- P, XK, Mg applied: 12 Sept, 1979. Hand dug: 20 Sept.
Seed sown: 1 Oct. Weedkillers with tridemorph applied: 28 Nov.
Weedkillers with benomyl applied: 1 Apr, 1980. N applied: 9 Apr.
Carbendazim plus tridemorph applied: 29 Apr. Hand harvested: 18 July.

NOTE: (1) Soil and crop samples were taken for N, P, K and Mg analysis.

(2) N, P, K & Mg contents of soils and crop were measured.
C99
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1981</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[81/W/CS/11
SOIL STRUCTURE

Object: To study the residual effects of peat, at a range of nitrogen
levels, on the yield of a sequence of crops ~- Woburn Stackyard II.

Sponsor: A.E. Johnston.

The 19th year, potatoes.

For previous years see 64/C/20(t), 65/C/19(t), 66/C/11(t), 67/C/8(t),
68/C/31(t), 69/W/CS/11(t), 70/W/CS/11(t), 71/N/CS/1%, 72/W/CS/11(t)
and 73-80/W/CS/11.

Design: Single replicate of 5 x 4.

Whole plot dimensions: 2.13 x 3.05.

Treatments: All combinations of:-

1. PEAT Peat (tonnes dry matter - total applied 1963-72):

0
8
55
110
165

2. % Nitrogen fertiliser (kg N)

cumulative to previous treatments:
0
100
200
300

Basal applications: Manures: P at 85 kg, as triple superphosphate, K at
300 kg, as potassium bicarbonate, Mg at 55 kg, as magnesium sulphate.
Weedkillers: Linuron at 0.92 1 with paraquat at 0.28 kg ion in 280 1.
Fungicide: Mancozeb at 1.3 kg in 280 1 with the insecticide on three
occasions, Insecticide: Pirimicarb at 0.14 kg.

Seed: Maris Pfper.

Cultivations, etc.:- P, K, Mg applied, hand dug: 10 Feb, 1981. N applied,
potatoes planted: 30 Apr. Weedkillers applied: 21 May. Fungicide and
insecticide applied: 25 June, 30 July, 17 Aug. Lifted: 15 Sept.

NOTE: Soil and crop samples were taken for N, P, K and Mg analysis.

105
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1982</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[82/W/CS/11
SOIL STRUCTURE

Object: To study the direct effects of sowing dates and times of applying
nitrogen and the residual effects of peat on the nutrient contents and
yields of s. barley - Woburn Stackyard II.

Sponsor: A.E. Johnston.

The 20th year, s. barley.

For previous years see 64/C/20(t), 65/C/19(t), 66/C/11(t), 67/C/8(t),
68/C/31(t), 69/W/CS/11(t), 70/W/CS/11(t), 71/W/CS/11, 72/M/CS/11(t)
and 73-81/K/CS/11.

Design: Single replicate of 20 plots.

Whole plot dimensions: 2.13 x 3.05.

Treatments: Combinations of:-

1. PEAT Peat (tonnes dry matter - total applied 1963-72):

0 0
1 8
2 55
3 110
y 4 165
2. SON DATE Dates of sowing:
9 FEB 9 February, 1982
9 MAR 9 March
24 MAR 24 March
13 APR 13 Apri)

3. N Times of applying nitrogen fertilizer at 96 kg N:
- Never
NS On the date of sowing
NL On 11 May for SOW DATE 9 FEB and 9 MAR; on 17 May for

SON DATE 24 MAR; on 28 May for SON DATE 13 APR

Basal applications: Manures: P at 85 kg as triple superphosphate, K at
300 kg as potassium bicarbonate, Mg at 55 kg as magnesium sulphate.
Fungicides: Carbendazim with maned and tridemorph (as 'Cosmic' at
4.0 kg) with captafol at 1.0 1 in 280 1 with the insecticide on two
occasions. Insecticide: Pirimicarb at 0.14 kg.

Seed: Georgie, dressed with ethirimol, sown at 160 kg.

Cultivations, etc.:- P, K, Mg applied: 6 Jan, 1982. Hand dug: 1 Feb.
Fungicides with insecticide applied: 19 May, 4 June. Hand harvested:
16 Aug.

NOTE: Crop samples were taken at regular intervals during the season for N,

P, XK and Mg analysis.
94
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
</reports>