<reports>
<report>
<year>1964</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##Red beet 1963: 
Ground chalk applied at 30 cwt: Apr 18, 1963
basal dressing N at 200 lb N as Monoammonium phosphate: Apr 18, 1963 
basal dressing K at 250 1b K as potassium nitrate: Apr 18, 1963 
basal dressing Mg at 500 1b Mg as magnesium sulphate: Apr 18, 1963
half Dg2 peat applied at 62.5 cwt/acre dug to 8 inches: Apr 18, 1963 
all plots rotary cultivated: Apr 18, 1963
remainder of Dg2 peat applied at 62.5 cwt/acre: Apr 18, 1963
all Dg1 applied at 62.5 cwt/acre dug to 8 inches: Apr 18, 1963
all plots rotary cultivated second time: Apr 18, 1963, 
Plots dug, S1 blocks subsoiled by hand to a depth of 20 inches, ground chalk applied at 10 cwt: Apr 19, 
Sb peat applied at 62.5 cwt/acre and pricked in: Apr 23. 
Seedbed N applied at 82 lb N as ammonium nitrate, seed drilled Detroit Globe at 15 1b: May 15. 
Sprayed with DDT at 0.6 1b in 20 gals: June 7,
Singled: July 2. Sprayed with a mixture of menazon, DDT and
gamma BHC at 1.5 fluid oz in 40 gals: July 31, Lifted: Aug 8.

##Carrots 1964
Dg1 peat at 62.5 cwt: Mar 6 1964
Dg2 peat at 125 cwt: Mar 6 1964 
basal dressing N at 75 lb N as Monoammonium phosphate: Mar 6 1964
basal dressing P at 56 lb N as Monoammonium phosphate: Mar 6 1964
basal dressing K at 150 1b K as potassium nitrate: Mar 6 1964
basal dressing Mg at 50 1b Mg as magnesium sulphate: Mar 6 1964
plots dug: Mar 6 1964
Sb peat at 62.5 cwt applied and worked in: Apr 23
N to seedbed at 25 lb N as Monoammonium phosphate: Apr 23
P to seedbed at 19 lb N as Monoammonium phosphate: Apr 23
K to seedbed at 50 1b K as potassium nitrate: Apr 23.
Seed drilled Autumn King Red Cored at 7 lb: apr 27
Sprayed with DDT at 0.6 lb in 20 gals: May 20
Singled: June 4
sprayed with a mixture of menazon, DDT and gamma BHC at 1.5 fluid oz in 40 gals: June 25, July 14, 21, 28, Aug 7
lifted: sept 2
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1965</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[65/c/19.1
##Red beet
N for digging in applied at 75 lb N as Monoammonium phosphate: Mar 10 1965
P for digging in applied  at 56 lb N as Monoammonium phosphate: Mar 10 1965
K for digging in applied  at 150 1b K as potassium nitrate: Mar 10 1965
Mg for digging in applied  at 50 1b Mg as magnesium sulphate: Mar 10 1965
Dg1 Peat for digging in applied at 62.5 cwt/acre and plots dug: Mar 31 - Apr 1.
Dg2 Peat for digging in applied at 125 cwt/acre and plots dug: Mar 31 - Apr 1. 
Seedbed peat applied to plots Sb at 62.5 cwt: Apr 21. 
N to seedbed at 25 lb N as Monoammonium phosphate: May 5
P to seedbed at 19 lb N as Monoammonium phosphate: May 5
K to seedbed at 50 1b K as potassium nitrate: May 5
seedbed prepared: May 5. 
Seed Detroit Globe, rubbed and graded, drilled at 30 1b: May 6.
Singled first to 2 inch spacing: May 27 and 31, 
Singled to 4 inc spacing: June 28. Sprayed with a mixture of menazon, DDT and gamma BHC at 1.5 fluid oz in 40 gals: May 21 and June 21. 
Lifted: Aug 12
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1966</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##Early potatoess
N for digging in applied at 90 lb N as Monoammonium phosphate: Mar 25, 1966
test P for digging in applied at 56 lb N as triple superphosphate: Mar 25, 1966
K for digging in applied  at 112 1b K as potassium nitrate: Mar 25, 1966
Mg for digging in applied  at 50 1b Mg as magnesium sulphate: Mar 25, 1966
Dg1 Peat for digging in applied at 62.5 cwt/acre and plots dug: Mar 25, 1966.
Dg2 Peat for digging in applied at 125 cwt/acre and plots dug: Mar 25, 1966. 
All plots dug: Mar 28, 
Seedbed peat applied to plots Sb at 62.5 cwt: Apr 4. 
N to seedbed at 25 lb N as Monoammonium phosphate: Apr 4
P to seedbed at 19 lb N as triple superphosphate: Apr 4
K to seedbed at 38 1b K as potassium nitrate: Apr 4
setts planted Arran Pilot: Apr 4, Earthed up May 20. Lifted: July 7.

##Red beet:
Chalk applied at 1 ton: July 15, 1966, 
N to seedbed at 200 lb N as Monoammonium phosphate: July 27
P to seedbed at 75 lb N as triple superphosphate: July 27
K to seedbed at 250 1b K as potassium nitrate: July 27
Mg to seedbed at 50 1b Mg as magnesium sulphate: July 27
seedbed prepared, and seed drilled Crimson Globe at 30 lb: July 27.
Singled to 4 inch spacing: Aug 24, 
Lifted: Oct 28, 
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1967</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##carrots
Ground chalk applied at 20 cwt: Dec 15, 1966 
Dg1 Peat for digging in applied at 62.5 cwt/acre and plots dug: Dec 15, 1966.
Dg2 Peat for digging in applied at 125 cwt/acre and plots dug: Dec 15, 1966. 
all plots dug: Dec 15, 1966, 
Blocks 1 and 2 seedbed worked down (J plots): Jan 30, 1967
Blocks 3 end 4 seedbed worked down (M plots): Mar 20, 1967
N to seedbed at 100 lb N as Monoammonium dihydrogen phosphate: Mar 20, 1967
P to seedbed at 75 lb N as Monoammonium dihydrogen phosphate: Mar 20, 1967
K to seedbed at 200 1b K as potassium nitrate: Mar 20, 1967
Mg to seedbed at 50 1b Mg as magnesium sulphate: Mar 20, 1967
seed drilled Chantenay Red cored, Monarch strain at 6 1b: Mar 20, 1967, 
Linuron at 0.75 1b in 100 gals: Mar 21. 
Dimethoate at 0.2 1b in 40 gals: June 9, June 23, July 10, Lifted: July 24
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1968</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##wheat: 
Dg1 Peat for digging in applied at 62.5 cwt/acre and plots dug: 29 Jan, 1968
Dg2 Peat for digging in applied at 125 cwt/acre and plots dug: 29 Jan, 1968
Dg3 Peat for digging in applied at 187.5 cwt/acre and plots dug: 29 Jan, 1968
all plots dug: 29 Jan, 1968, 
Treatment tractor wheelmarks made
N to seedbed at 200 lb N as ammonium nitrate: 15 May. 
P to seedbed at 75 lb N as Monoammonium dihydrogen phosphate: 15 May. 
K to seedbed at 250 1b K as potassium nitrate: 15 May. 
Mg to seedbed at 50 1b Mg as magnesium sulphate: 15 May. 
raked, seed drilled Avon Early at 30 1b: 15 May. 
Singled: 20 June. Dimethoate at 0.2 pints in 50 gals: 3 July.
Lifted: 9 Sept
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1969</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[138
SOIL STRUCTURE 2
(69/w/cs/11)

Effect of peat (anmual applications 1963-1968) Woburn, Stackyard
II, plot 6 of the Continuous Barley Site, spring beans 1969 the
seventh year,

Design: UL randomised blocks of 5 plots with weedkiller treatments
to blocks,

Area of each plot: 0.0016. Area harvested: 0,0015,

Treatments: All combinations of:-

Blocks: 1, Weedkiller: No sprey (SO), simazine at
0,42 1b in 50 gels (S1), 0.8% 1b in 100 gnls (S2),
1.68 Iv in 200 gals (sk),

Whole 2, Residues of Peat: None (0), peat at 62,5 cwt dry

plots: ratter applied in 1955 only (Sb 65). Annual
dressings of peat repested 1963-1968 et 62.5 (DG 1),
125 (DG 2), 187.5 cwt dry matter (DG 3) dug in to
depth of 8 inches,

NOTE: The 1968 sub plot test of wheel-marks wes ignored in 1969

yields being taken from whole plots.

Basal aprlications:  ground chalk, Triple superphosphate,
potassium dicerbonate, and magnesium sulphate to supply 75 1b P,
250 1b K, 50 1b Mg applied to the seedbed before drilling,

##Beans
Ground chalk 20 cwt: 3 Feb, 1969, 
P as triple superphosphate to seedbed before drilling at 75 lbP/acre: 3 Feb, 1969,
K as potassium dicarbonate to seedbed before drilling at 250 lbK/acre: 3 Feb, 1969,
Mg as magnesium sulphate to seedbed before drilling at 50 lbMg/acre: 3 Feb, 1969,
Plots dug: 6 Feb, 
Seed drilled Tarvin at 200 lb: 11 Feb, 
sprayed treatment S1 simazine at 0.42 lb in 50 gals: 16 Feb,
sprayed treatment S2 simazine at 0.84 lb in 100 gals: 16 Feb,
sprayed treatment S4 simazine at 1.68 lb in 200 gals: 16 Feb, 
Harvested by hand: 29 Aug.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1970</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##spring beans
Ground chalk 20 cwt: 16 Dec, 1969, 
P as triple superphosphate to seedbed before drilling at 75 lbP/acre: 16 Dec, 1969,
K as potassium dicarbonate to seedbed before drilling at 250 lbK/acre: 16 Dec, 1969,
Mg as magnesium sulphate to seedbed before drilling at 50 lbMg/acre: 16 Dec, 1969
plots dug: 16 Dec, 1969
Seed drilled Tarvin at 200 1b, 28 Apr, 1970 
sprayed treatment SC(S1) simazine at 1.50 lb in 120 gals: 28 Apr, 1970
sprayed treatment SA(S2) simazine at 0.75 lb in 60 gals: 28 Apr, 1970
Dimethoate at 4.8 f1 oz in 40 gals: 17 June,
menazon at 0.25 1b in 40 gals: 6 July, 29 July, Harvested by hand: 10 Sept,
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1971</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[,
##winter wheat
Hand cultivated, seed drilled Cappelle: 7 Oct, 1970.
N applied at 597 kg 'Nitro-Chalk': 19 Apr, 1971. 
hand harvested: 17 Aug
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1972</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##barley
Ground chalk at 2.5 tonnes/ha: 7 Dec, 1971 
P applied at 84 kgP as triple superphosphate: 7 Dec, 1971 
K applied at 280 kg K as potassium bicarbonate: 7 Dec, 1971
Mg applied at 56 kg Mg as magnesium sulphate: 7 Dec, 1971
test peat 2 at 7.8 tonnes/ha: 7 Dec, 1971
test peat 3 at 16 tonnes/ha: 7 Dec, 1971
test peat 4 at 24 tonnes/ha: 7 Dec, 1971
plots dug by hand: 7 Dec, 1971. 
Seed drilled Julia, dressed with ethirimol, sown at 170 kg: 14 Mar, 1972
test N1 at 50 kgN as nitro-chalk: 14 Mar, 1972
test N2 at 100 kgN as nitro-chalk: 14 Mar, 1972
test N3 at 150 kgN as nitro-chalk: 14 Mar, 1972.
Dichlorprop and MCPA (Mephetol Plus) at 5.6 1 in 340 1: 17 May.
Note: Birds caused severe darage to the crop and yields were not taken,
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1973</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##potatoes
Ground chalk applied at 2.5 tonnes/ha, plots dug by hand: 28 Nov, 1972.
P applied at 85 kg as triple superphosphate: 6 Apr, 1973
K applied at 300 kg, as potassium bicarbonate: 6 Apr, 1973
Mg applied at 55 kg as magnesium sulphate: 6 Apr, 1973
plots rotary cultivated, potatoes planted Pentland Crown: 6 Apr, 1973. 
Linuron at 0.85 kg with peraquat at 0.42 kg fon in 340 1: 9 May, 
Menazon at 0.28 kg in 340 1: 15 June,
Menazon at 0.28 kg plus mancozeb at 1.3 kg in 340 1: 18 June, Lifted: 25 Sept.
note: N applied at none, 100, 200 and 300 kgN/ha. No date provided
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1974</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##wheat 
P applied at 85 kg, as triple superphosphate: 28 Sept, 1973
K applied at 300 kg, as potassium bicarbonate: 28 Sept, 1973
Mg applied at 55 kg as magnesium sulphate: 28 Sept, 1973
plots dug by hand: 28 Sept, 1973.
Seed sown Cappelle, sown at 150 kg: 8 Oct, 
Ioxynil at 0.42 kg and mecoprop at 1.26 kg in 340 1: 8 Apr, 1974. 
Test N50 at 50 kgN/ha: 24 Apr.
Test N100 at 100 kgN/ha: 24 Apr.
Test N150 at 150 kgN/ha: 24 Apr. 
Harvested by hand: 19 July.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1975</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##potatoes
Ground ctalk at 2.5 tonnes, plots dug by hand: 13 Dec 1974
test N1 at 100 kgN/ha 13 May 1975
test N2 at 200 kgN/ha 13 May 1975
test N3 at 300 kgN/ha 13 May 1975
P applied at 85 kg, as triple superphosphate: 3 May 1975
K applied at 300 kg, as potussium bicarbonate:  13 May 1975
Mg applied at 55 kg, as magnesium sulphate  13 May 1975. 
potatoes planted Maris Piper:  13 May 1975
Menazon at 0.28 kg in 280 1 16 June, 1 July. 
Menazon at 0.28 kg and Mancozeb at 1.3 kg in 280 l: 21 July 7 Aug.
lifted: 29 Sept
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1976</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##ley
Ground chalk at 2.5 tonnes: 11 Dec, 1975 
P applied at 85 kg, as triple superphosphate: 11 Dec, 1975 
K applied at 300 kg, as potassium bicarbonate: 11 Dec, 1975 
Mg applied at 55 kg as magnesium sulphate: 11 Dec, 1975
plots dug by hand: 11 Dec, 1975. 
test N1 at 30 kgN as ammonium nitrate: 22 Mar, 1976
test N2 at 60 kgN as ammonium nitrate: 22 Mar, 1976
test N3 at 90 kgN as ammonium nitrate: 22 Mar, 1976, 
RvP ryegrass, sown at 50 kg: 22 Mar, 1976. 
Benazolin with 2,4-DB and MCPA (Ley Cornox at 8.4 1 in 280 1): 25 May. 
Cut: 24 June
test N1 at 30 kgN as ammonium nitrate: 24 June
test N2 at 60 kgN as ammonium nitrate: 24 June
test N3 at 90 kgN as ammonium nitrate:.24 June 
Cut: 5 Nov.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1977</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##ley
test N1 at 30 kgN as ammonium nitrate: 25 Mar, 1977, 1 June, 26 July
test N2 at 60 kgN as ammonium nitrate: 25 Mar, 1977, 1 June, 26 July
test N3 at 90 kgN as ammonium nitrate: 25 Mar, 1977, 1 June, 26 July. 
Cut: 1 June, 20 July, 29 Sept.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1978</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##barley
Hand dug: 14 Dec, 1977. 
Ground chalk at 2.5 tonnes: 7 Mar
P applied at 85 kg, as triple superphosphate: 7 Mar
K applied at 300 kg, as potassium bicarbonate: 7 Mar
Mg applied at 55 kg, as magnesium sulphate: 7 Mar
raked in: 7 Mar
seed sown Porthos, dressed with ethirimol, sown at 160 kg: 7 Mar. 
Ioxynil at 0.52 kg with mecoprop at 1.6 kg and Tridemorph at 0.53 kg in 280 1: 19 May.
Hand harvested: 16 Aug.
note: N at 50, 100 and 150 kgN/ha as ammonium nitrate cumulative to previous dressings. no date given
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1979</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##wheat
Hand dug: 12 Sept, 1978. 
P applied at 85 kg, as triple superphosphate: 3 Oct
K applied at 300 kg, as potassium bicarbonate: 3 Oct 
Mg applied at 55 kg, as magnesium sulphate: 3 Oct
raked in,: 3 Oct
Seed sown Maris Hobbit, sown at 210 kg: 3 Oct. 
Ioxynil 0,32 kg with mecoprop at 0.94 kg and Tridemorph at 0.53 kg in 280 1: 17 Nov. 
test N1 at 50 kgN/ha as ammonium nitrate: 23 Apr, 1979
test N2 at 100 kgN/ha as ammonium nitrate: 23 Apr, 1979
test N3 at 150 kgN/ha as ammonium nitrate: 23 Apr, 1979 
ioxynil at 0.42 kg with mecoprop at 1.3 kg and Tridemorph at 0.53 kg in 280 1: 9 May. 
Carbendazim at 0.25 kg with zineb at 1.6 kg in 280 1: 20 June. 
Hand harvested: 16 Aug.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1980</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##winter barley
P at 85 kg, as triple superphosphate: 12 Sept, 1979 
K at 300 kg, as potassium bicarbonate: 12 Sept, 1979 
Mg at 55 kg, as magnesium sulphate: 12 Sept, 1979. 
Hand dug: 20 Sept.
Seed sown Sonja, sown at 210 kg: 1 Oct. 
loxynil at 0.32 kg with mecoprop at 0.94 kg and Tridemorph at 0.53 kg in 280 1: 28 Nov.
Benomyl at 0.28 kg. plus tridemorph at 0.53 kg in 280 1: 1 Apr, 1980. 
test N1 at 50 kgN/ha as ammonium nitrate: 9 Apr
test N2 at 100 kgN/ha as ammonium nitrate: 9 Apr
test N3 at 150 kgN/ha as ammonium nitrate: 9 Apr.
Carbendazim at 0.25 kg plus tridemorph at 0.53 kg in 280 1: 29 Apr. Hand harvested: 18 July.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1981</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##potatoes
P applied at 85 kg, as triple superphosphate: 10 Feb, 1981
K applied at 300 kg, as potassium bicarbonate: 10 Feb, 1981 
Mg applied at 55 kg, as magnesium sulphate: 10 Feb, 1981
hand dug: 10 Feb, 1981. 
test N1 at 100 kgN/ha as ammonium nitrate: 30 Apr
test N2 at 200 kgN/ha as ammonium nitrate: 30 Apr
test N3 at 300 kgN/ha as ammonium nitrate: 30 Apr.,
potatoes planted Maris Piper: 30 Apr. 
Linuron at 0.92 1 with paraquat at 0.28 kg ion in 280 1: 21 May. 
Mancozeb at 1.3 kg and Pirimicarb at 0.14 kg in 280 1: 25 June, 30 July, 17 Aug. 
Lifted: 15 Sept.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
<report>
<year>1982</year>
<rawcontent>
<![CDATA[
##spring barley 
P applied at 85 kg as triple superphosphate: 6 Jan, 1982
K applied at 300 kg as potassium bicarbonate: 6 Jan, 1982 
Mg applied at 55 kg as magnesium sulphate: 6 Jan, 1982. 
Hand dug: 1 Feb.
Sown Seed: Georgie, dressed with ethirimol, sown at 160 kg: 9 feb 1982, 9 Mar, 24 Mar, 13 Apr.
N appplied at time of sowing at 96 kgN/ha: 9 feb 1982, 9 Mar, 24 Mar, 13 Apr
N applied after sowing for sow date 9FEB and 9MAR: 11 May
N applied after sowing for sow date 24MAR: 17 May
N applied after sowing for sow date 13APR: 28 May
Carbendazim with maneb and tridemorph (as 'Cosmic' at 4.0 kg) with captafol at 1.0 1 and Pirimicarb at 0.14 kg in 280 1: 19 May, 4 June. 
Hand harvested: 16 Aug.
]]></rawcontent>
</report>
</reports>